
PROBLEM

Zeus gave Artemis, the goddess of the wilderness, a rectangular area for growing a forest.
With the left side of the area as a segment of the positive y-axis 
and the bottom side as a segment of the positive x-axis, 
and (0,0) the left bottom corner of the area, 
Zeus told Artemis to plant trees only on integer coordinate points in the area. 
Artemis liked the forest to look natural, and therefore planted trees in such a way 
that a line connecting two trees was never parallel to x-axis or y-axis. 

At times, Zeus wants Artemis to cut trees for him. 
The trees are to be cut as follows:

   1. Zeus wants at least a given number T of trees to be cut for him.
   2. To get a rectangular football pitch for future football success, 
      Artemis is to cut all trees within a rectangular area, and no trees outside of it.
   3. The sides of this rectangular area are to be parallel to x-axis and y-axis.
   4. Two opposite corners of the area must be located on trees 
      and therefore those corner trees are also cut. 
	  
As Artemis likes the trees, she wants to fulfill these conditions 
whilst cutting as few trees as possible. 
You are to write a program that, given information on the forest and the minimum
number T of trees to be cut, selects an area for cutting trees for Artemis. 


INPUT

The input file name is artemis.in. 
The first line contains one integer N: 
   the number of trees in the forest. 
The second line contains one integer T: 
   the minimum number of trees to be cut. 
The following N lines describe the positions of the N trees. 
Each of these lines contains two integers X and Y: 
   the x-coordinate followed by the y-coordinate of a tree

OUTPUT   

The output file name is artemis.out. 
The file is to contain one line with two integers I and J separated by one space: 
Artemis should use the Ith tree (with position given on line I+2 of the input file) 
and Jth tree (with position given on line J+2 of the input file) 
as the corners of the area for cutting trees. 
The order of these two number is irrelevant. 
There may be several ways to choose these trees 
and you need to find and output one of them. For all
test cases at least one solution exists

SOLUTION

Observation: 
Let f(x, y) be the number of trees below and to the left of (x, y). 
Then the number of the trees in the rectangle bounded by t1 and t2 is

   f(t1.x, t1.y) + f(t2.x, t2.y) - f(t1.x, t2.y) + 1 

1. Trivial algorithm. 
   Loop over all rectangles, and loop over all trees 
   to count those inside the rectangle. O(n^3)
   
2. Use dynamic programming to compute f(t1.x, t2.y) for every t1, t2. 
   Then evaluate all rectangles using the formulae. O(n^2), 
   but also O(n^2) memory
   
3. Place an outer loop t over the trees, 
   representing one corner of a potential rectangle. 
   To evaluate rectangles with corners at t, one only needs f(t.x, *) and f(*, t.y). 
   These can be computed with DP as in algorithm (2), and requires only linear memory. 
   O(n^2)
   
4. Sort the trees from left to right, and then process them in that order. 
   As each new tree (say tn) is added, it is inserted into a list of current trees 
   that is sorted vertically. 
   
From this information one can calculate f(t.x, tn.y) and f(tn.x, t.y) for
every t to the left of tn, in linear time. Then one can evaluate all rectangles with
one corner at tn. This ends up being very similar to algorithm (3). O(n

Solution:

Easy algorithm stores the number of trees from (0,0) to (i,j) for all trees (i,j), 
but this is not feasible given the memory limit.

Assume we are processing trees in ascending order of first coordinates. 
Fix a tree (x,y) for which we want to calculate the best rectangle 
with respect to all earlier trees to the left of (x,y).

 For each 1 ≤ j ≤ y, V[j] = 1 if there is a tree at some (z,j)
 For each 1 ≤ i ≤ x, H[i] = 1 if there is a tree at some (i,z)

Prefix sums for H[] and V[] tell us number of trees to the left of some i and below some j.

For each tree (x",y") to the left of (x,y), 
assume we have stored the number of trees between (0,0) and (x",y"). 
Call this Between(0,0,x",y").

We can then get the number of trees between (x',y') and (x,y) as

   PrefixY(y) - [PrefixX(x') + PrefixY(y') - Between(0,0,x',y')]

We check if the number of trees in this rectangle is more than T 
and better than the best we know. 
If so, keep it, else throw it away.

In this way, after sorting the trees (N log N), 
we can process each tree in time N, so overall is N2. 
The space we use is proportional to N 
(for each tree (x,y) store Between(0,0,x,y)).













