
PROBLEM

In a modern city for Greek gods, the streets are geometrically arranged 
as a grid  with integer coordinates with streets parallel to the x and y axes. 

For each integer value Z, there is a horizontal street at y=Z and a vertical street at x=Z. 
This way, integer coordinate pairs represent the street junctions. 
During the hot days, the gods rest in cafeterias at street junctions. 

Messenger Hermes is to send photon messages to gods resting in the cafeterias by only moving along the city streets. 
Each message is for a single god, and it does not matter if the other gods see the message. 

The messages are to be sent in a given order, 
and Hermes is provided the coordinates of the cafeterias in that order. 

Hermes starts from (0,0). 
To send a message to a cafeteria at (Xi,Yi), 
Hermes only needs to visit some point on the same horizontal street (with y-coordinate Yi)
or on the same vertical street (with x-coordinate Xi). 
Having sent all of the messages, Hermes stops.

You are to write a program that, given a sequence of cafeterias, 
finds the minimum total distance Hermes needs to travel to send the messages.

INPUT

The input file name is hermes.in. 
The first line contains one integer N: 
  the number of messages to be sent. 
The following N lines contain the coordinates of the N street junctions
where the messages are to be sent. These N lines are in the order in which the messages are
to be sent. Each of these N lines contains two integers: first the x-coordinate and then the
y-coordinate of the street junction

OUTPUT

The output file name is hermes.out. 
The file is to contain a single line containing one integer: 
the minimum total distance Hermes needs to travel to send the messages.

Solution 

Hermes

An O(n^2) algorithm: 

Let (x0,y0),…,(xn,yn) be the points 
where (x0,y0)=(0,0) is the starting point. 

We will compute A[i,j] and B[i,j] where A[i,j] is the cost to align 
with the i first points and end up at (xi,yj) 

and B[i,j] is the cost to align with the i first points 
and end up at (xj,yi). 

We ha

y 
^                
|-----------------.(j)
|yi      |  .(i+1)|
|--------.(i)     |
|        |        |
|        |        |
|________|________|______> x
         xi 

Suppose, we have aligned with first i points. 
A[i,j] - is min cost to align with first i points and end up in point (xi,yj)
B[i,j] - is min cost to align with first i points and end up in point (xj,yi)

A[i+1,j] - is min cost to align with first i+1 points and up in point (xi+1,yj)
B[i+1,j] - is min cost to align with first i points and end up in point (xj,yi+1)

A[i+1,j] = A[i,j] + xi+1 - xi
A[i+1,j] = B[i,i+1] + yj - yi

B[i+1,j]=min { B[i,j]+d[yi,y{i+1}], A[i,i+1]+d[xi,xj] 

The final answer is minj {A[n,j],B[j,n]}















