
PROBLEM

Famous ancient Greek sculptor Phidias is making preparations to build another marvelous monument. 
For this purpose he needs rectangular marble plates of sizes 
W1 × H1, W2 × H2, ..., WN × HN.

Recently, Phidias has received a large rectangular marble slab. 
He wants to cut the slab to obtain plates of the desired sizes. 
Any piece of marble (the slab or the plates cut from it) 
can be cut either horizontally or vertically into two rectangular plates 
with integral widths and heights, cutting completely through that piece. 
This is the only way to cut pieces and pieces cannot be joined together. 

Since the marble has a pattern on it, the plates cannot be rotated:
if Phidias cuts a plate of size A × B then it cannot be used as a plate 
of size B × A unless A = B. 
He can make zero or more plates of each desired size. 
A marble plate is wasted if it is
not of any of the desired sizes after all cuts are completed. 
Phidias wonders how to cut the initial slab so that as little of it as possible will be wasted. 

As an example, assume that in the figure below 
the width of the original slab is 21 and the height of the original slab is 11, 
and the desired plate sizes are 10 × 4, 6 × 2, 7 × 5, and 15 × 10. 
The minimum possible area wasted is 10, 
and the figure shows one sequence of cuts with total waste area of size 10. 

INPUT

Your task is to write a program that, given the size of the original slab 
and the desired plate sizes, calculates the minimum total area of the original slab 
that must be wasted.

INPUT
The input file name is phidias.in. The first line of input contains two integers: 
first W, the width of the original slab, 
and then H, the height of the original slab. 
The second line contains one integer N: the number of desired plate sizes. 
The following N lines contain the desired plate sizes. 
Each of these lines contains two integers: first the width Wi and then the height Hi of that desired plate size (1 ≤ i ≤ N).

OUTPUT
The output file name is phidias.out. 
The file is to contain one line with a single integer:
the minimum total area of the original slab that must be wasted. 


Solutions

Use Dynamic Programming:

Let a(x, y) be the wasted area for a rectangle (x, y), 1 <= x <= W, 1 <= y <= H.
Initially, put a(x, y) = xy, for all (x, y) 
except for the ones corresponding to needed plates, 
e.g. x = wi and y = hi, 1 <= i <= N, for which we put a(x, y) = 0. 

For a plate (x, y) consider all vertical cuts 
c = 1, 2, . . . , x − 1 and all horizontal cuts c = 1, 2, . . . , y − 1 
and chose the cut producing the minimum wasted area 
a(x, y) = a(c, y)+a(x−c, y) 
       or a(x, c)+a(x, y−c) 
	   
for some c.
y
 ^
 |
 -y.......
 |    .  .
 |    .  .
 |    .  .
 |_ _ .__. _ _ >
      c  x
	  
Another solution: 

If we cut vertically at yi, we get:

   Wastage(x,y) = Wastage(x,yi) + Wastage(x,y-yi).
   
Similarly, if we cut horizontally at xj, we get:

   Wastage(x,y) = Wastage(xj,y) + Wastage(x-xj,y).

The choices available to us are to cut vertically at yi for 1 ≤ yi < y 
or horizontally at xj for 1 ≤ xj < x. 
We check all of these and choose the minimum.

Initially:

Wastage(x,y) = 0,   if (x,y) matches some (ai,bi)
             = x*y, otherwise (this will be updated later)
			 
Update:

 Wastage(x,y) = min {
       Wastage(x,y),                               /* Currently computed quantity */
       min_{0<j<x} Wastage(j,y) + Wastage(x-j,y),  /* Horizontal cut at j */
       min_{0<i<y} Wastage(i,y) + Wastage(x-i,y),  /* Vertical cut at i */
 }
 
Alternatives:

Initialize only

Wastage(x,y) = 0, if (x,y) matches some (ai,bi)
Wastage(1,1) = 1

If (x,y) is completely wasted, all cuts will eventually create a collection of (1,1) rectangles which add up to x*y.

Can optimize a bit by adding

Wastage[x,y] = x*y whenever no tile fits, that is (x < min xi) or (y < min yj)



					  





   
		 