
 
 Packing Biscuits (biscuits)
 
 Aunty Khong is organising a competition with x participants, 
 and wants to give each participant a bag of biscuits. 
 
 There are k different types of biscuits, numbered from 0 to k - 1. 
 Each biscuit of type i (0 <= i <= k - 1 ) has a tastiness value of 2^i. 
 Aunty Khong has  a[i](possibly zero) biscuits of type i in her pantry.
 
 Each of Aunty Khong's bags will contain zero or more biscuits of each type. 
 The total number of biscuits of type i in all the bags must not exceed a[i]. 
 The sum of tastiness values of all biscuits in a bag is called the total tastiness of the bag.
 
 Help Aunty Khong find out how many different values of y exist, 
 such that it is possible to pack x bags of biscuits, 
 each having total tastiness equal to y.
 
 Implementation Details
 
 You should implement the following procedure:
 
  int64 count_tastiness(int64 x, int64[] a)
 
  x: the number of bags of biscuits to pack.
  a: an array of length k. For 0 <= i <= k - 1, 
     denotes the number of biscuits of type a[i] in the pantry.
	 
  The procedure should return the number of different values of y, 
  such that Aunty can pack x bags of biscuits, 
  each one having a total tastiness of y.
  
  The procedure is called a total of q times 
  (see Constraints and Subtasks sections for the allowed values of q). 
  Each of these calls should be treated as a separate scenario.
 

Examples: 

1. Consider the following call:

count_tastiness(3, [5, 2, 1])

This means that Aunty wants to pack bags, and there are types of biscuits in the pantry:
  
  - 5 biscuits of type 0, each having a tastiness value 1,
  - 2 biscuits of type 1, each having a tastiness value 2,
  - 1 biscuit of type 2, having a tastiness value 4.
  
The possible values y of are [1]. For instance, in order to pack bags of total tastiness ,

Solution 1:

We say that a value of y is good if 
it is possible to pack x bags, each of total tastiness.

Subtask 1

We proceed by checking every value of y, noting that y <= 10^5. 
For each value of y, we use the `greedy coin change' algorithm 
to decide if it is good or not.

Greedy coin change algorithm



Implementing this naively gives a runtime of 10^5 x operations. 
There are two ways to speed it up.

One possible way is to remove x coins at a time 
instead of removing them one by one.

The other way is to check for values of y at most 10^5/x, 
so that we have less values of y to check in the even that x is large. 
However, contestants will have to return 1 immediately if x is larger 
than 10^5 to avoid actually packing empty bags!

The sum of the total taste 10^5 
Because it does not exceed, 
all possible yYou can try Brute-force on. 
blast furnace x People y You should see 
if packing is possible to distribute as many biscuits as possible. 
Any value 2^i 
Let's compare the case of filling with one large biscuit 
and filling with several small biscuits. 
Filling with large biscuits can be replaced with small ones, 
but if small biscuits are filling several people, 
it is impossible to replace them with large biscuits. 
Therefore, it is beneficial to fill it with a large biscuit first.


In conclusion, from the big biscuit to the west x 
Give as much as possible to 10 people, 
then all y You can see if you have filled it. 
When you hand out one type of biscuit, 
it doesn't matter who you give it to 
or if you give it as fair as possible, 
so you can give it anyway. 
Greedy's time complexity isO ( k x ) Degree, 
and possible y The number of 105x If you multiply O (105× k )Becomes. 
There is no problem with the time limit even if this is executed 10 times.


The famous coin change problem is a classic example of using greedy algorithms.

Let’s understand what the problem is.

1. max a[i]=0 or 1 for all j > imax

dp[i] is memo array or cur = [  ]
it = dp[i].lower_bound(cur) - smallest element in array bigger or equal to cur
if perfect match return 
else we store 
itt = it
then we check previous itt-1. it means curr lays between itt-1 and itt
if val(itt-1) == val(itt) then it must be same for curr - return it

Then we recur to pos + 1 and calculate

ret = dp[pos][cur] = rec(pos+1,(cur+a[pos])/2) + rec(pos+1,(a[pos]+cur-X)/2)

it=dp[pos].upper_bound(cur) - first element which is greater than cur.
if next element it++ has the same value then remove it. it is inefficient
Then move to previous element, 
if prev element has the same val, we remove bigger one. 



Now for convenience N=60
Express k The reason why I don't write is because the two are a little different. To be exact
log(∑k−1i=02i×A[i]))  

to be.)

x=1 In this case, you don't have to think about giving it out to several people, and just look at the sum of your tastes.
The core idea is as follows. Every biscuit tastes

2^i, y Let's try to match the small bits in order. Fill the 0th bit of y with 0/1, and use biscuit 0 accordingly. After that, when filling more than the 1st bit, type 0 biscuits are always needed in bundles of 2, 4 and 6. This is no different from using 1, 2, and 3 biscuits of the 1st kind, and therefore, biscuit of the 0th kind

If you have a dog, type 1 biscuit
You can think of it as a dog. This logic can be applied to biscuit 1 and biscuit 2 in order.
Let's use this to solve the problem recursively.
I'm filling up the bit 1, and the biscuit i pulled in the previous step
Possible when there is a dog
Let's say the number of cases)
If bit 1 is set to 0, the next state is
If you leave it to 1, the next state is
Becomes (of course at this time
Should be). Therefore, a simple recursion can be derived.

If you simply implement this as a recursive function,
Is consumed. However, it can be shown that there are only two different js in each state. In detail
If there are two j corresponding to i, it always forms k,k+1. In this case, the possible number in the following state is
So, it can be seen that the pattern continues to be maintained. Therefore, if memoization is added, the number of states becomes O(N). Therefore, the problem is solved in O(NlogN).
In fact, it is almost the same solution. Here, if bit i is set to 1, the next state is

Becomes (only j+A[i]≥x).

When you do this, the number of states is about O(Nx). This is because the difference between the minimum and maximum possible j in the current state is maintained at the maximum x. The reason can be seen in the same way as before. If the difference between the minimum and maximum possible j in f(i,∗) is less than or equal to x, subtracting x from the minimum gives the difference 2x, and dividing it by 2 gives the difference x Because it becomes. So, you can do memoization. However, in this case, it should be implemented slightly efficiently, but it would be fine if it was implemented non-recursively in a way that manages the pair of (j,dp(i,j)) in consideration of redundancy, or uses unordered_map.
Perfect score
To get a perfect solution, you need to develop the observations of the above subtasks and then derive completely different solutions. What we do to j when calculating DP is an iteration of adding something and dividing by 2. In this process, j must always be kept above 0. Since we are counting the number of ys that satisfy this condition, let's interpret this condition in a different way.


x. The condition that the above operation does not reach a negative number when subtracting is not considered is 0≤i≤k−1 about

sum (j=0..i  2^j*A[j]) >= 0. 

to be. The reason is, in fact, mathematically,

(j+A[i])/2   You don’t have to go down and ask for it, just (j+A[i])/2 
It is because there is no difference even if you use it as it is
When this happens, on both sides 2^i 
Multiplying by can derive the above equation.


We each A[i] in port x Can be subtracted or not.
A[i] on x If you subtract B[i]=1, if not B[i]=0.
Let's say in this case B is just y Is a binary representation of.

This way:  sum(j=0..i  2^j(A[j] - xB[j])) >= 0

sum(j=0..i  2^j*A[j])/x >= sum(2^j*B[j])

F[i] = Sum(2^j*A[j])/x


Defined as, our condition is

sum(2^j*B[j]) <= F[i] to be

In other words: y = There are conditions that suffix must be less than a certain number when it is expanded in binary.
now y - Let's try to match the big spot first (this is the opposite of the previous approach, where we match the small spot first).

DP[i][j]=i+1

I guessed everything after the first place,

Suppose that the prefix to the i digit must be less than or equal to j, the correct number of y.

DP[N−1][2^N−1] becomes in this case:

B[i]=0 when the next transition is: DP[i−1][min(j,2^i−1,F[i])]
becomes B[i]=1 

DP[i−1][min(j−2^i,2^i−1,F[i]−2^i)]




















  
 

 

