
While lost on the long walk from the college to the UQ Centre, 
you have stumbled across the entrance to a secret cave system running deep under the university. 
The entrance is blocked by a security system consisting of N consecutive doors, 
each door behind the previous; 
and N switches, with each switch connected to a different door.

The doors are numbered 0, 1, …, (N ­ 1) in order, 
with door 0 being closest to you. 
The switches are also numbered 0, 1, …, (N ­ 1), 
though you do not know which switch is connected to which door.

The switches are all located at the entrance to the cave. 
Each switch can either be in an up or down position. 
Only one of these positions is correct for each switch. 
If a switch is in the correct position then the door it is connected to will be open, 
and if the switch is in the incorrect position then the door it is connected to will be closed. 
The correct position may be different for different switches, 
and you do not know which positions are the correct ones.

You would like to understand this security system. 
To do this, you can set the switches to any combination, 
and then walk into the cave to see which is the first closed door. 
Doors are not transparent: once you encounter the first closed door, 
you cannot see any of the doors behind it

You have time to try 70,000 combinations of switches, but no more. 
Your task is to determine the correct position for each switch, 
and also which door each switch is connected to.

Implementation

You should submit a file that implements the procedure exploreCave(). 
This may call the grader function tryCombination() up to 70,000 times, 
and must finish by calling the grader procedure answer(). 
These functions and procedures are described below.

Grader Function: tryCombination()

int tryCombination(intS[]);

Description

The grader will provide this function. 
It allows you to try a combination of switches, 
and then enter the cave to determine the first closed door. 
If all doors are open, the function will return ­1. 
This function runs in O(N) time; 
that is, the running time is at worst proportional to N .
This function may be called at most 70,000 times.

Parameters

S: An array of length N, indicating the position of each switch. 
The element S[i] corresponds to switch i. 
A value of 0 indicates that the switch is up, 
and a value of 1 indicates that the switch is down.
Returns: The number of the first door that is closed, or ­1 if all doors are open.

void answer(intS[],intD[]);

Description

Call this procedure when you have identified the combination 
of switches to open all doors, and the door to which each switch is connected.

Parameters

   S: An array of length N, indicating the correct position of each switch. 
      The format matches that of the function tryCombination() described above.
   D: An array of length N, indicating the door each switch is connected to.
     Specifically, element D[i] should contain the door number that switch i is connected to.
Returns: This procedure does not return, but will cause the program to exit.

void exploreCave(intN);

Description

Your submission must implement this procedure.
This function should use the grader routine tryCombination() 
to determine the correct position for each switch and the door each switch is connected to, 
and must call answer() once it has determined this information.

tryCombination([1,0,1,1]) => 1

This corresponds to the picture. Switches 0, 2 and 3 are down, while switch 1 is up. 
The function returns 1, indicating that door 1 is the first door from the left that is closed.

tryCombination([0,1,1,0]) => 3

Doors 0, 1 and 2 are all opened, while door 3 is closed.

tryCombination([1,1,1,0]) => -1

Moving switch 0 down causes all doors to be opened, 
indicated by the return value of ­1.

Cave

This is a nice problem following a recent IOI trend of having problems 
where the limiting factor is not execution time, 
but some abstract measure of efficiency. 

This is slightly easier than some of the previous problems in each vein.
To achieve 100%, we can use up to 14 queries per door. 
Since 214 is slightly more than the number of doors, 
this strongly suggests some form of binary search on each door. 
It will be easiest if we attack the doors in order. 
Once we know which switch and position opens a door, 
we can lock that switch in place so that we will always be able to see the next door, 
and thereafter pretend the switch does not even exist.

To solve for a door, we can start with all switches down, 
which will immediately tell us which switch position opens the door. 
At this point every switch is a candidate. 

We can then test with half the candidates down and half up, 
which will eliminate half the candidates. 
This process is then repeated until only one candidate remains.

This is done by finding the switches that match sequentially from the 0th door. 
To find a switch that matches statement 0, we do a binary search. 
When there are switch candidates, only half of them are flipped. 
At this time, you can reduce the number of candidates by half 
while checking if the door 0 moves. 
This continues until there is one candidate left. 
The last remaining candidate is a switch that matches statement 0.N

Finding a switch that matches statement 0 
and finding the answer to that switch is only a single attempt. 
After finding the answer to the switch that matches statement 0, 
statement 0 always remains open. 

Then, when looking for the switch for door 1, 
you can find it in exactly the same way as for door 0. 
In this way, you can find the switches and answers that match up to the 1st, 2nd, ..., N-1. 
You can always find the answer in 70000 attempts.

int tryCombination(int S[])

it will accept array of switchers and will return index of first closed door. 
from the start all switchers down. 
     0 1 2 3 
S = [0,0,0,0]   sw = [0,1,2,3]

tryCombination([0,0,0,0]) k = 0  first door is closed 

Now, we need to find a switcher, which opens the first door. 
the simpliest linear algorithm whould be to try open/close fotr first switcher
if we do nto open, then first switcher is not connected to first door. 
Then we will try two combinations for the second switcher and so one until we find a switcher,
which opens the first door. 

We can do it in log time 
From the start switcher lies in range [0,..,N-1] 
s = 0, e = N-1
mid = (s + e) / 2

0000000001111111111
|      /  \        \
s     mid mid+1    


Let's work in different way. Let's find a door which is opened by first lock
i = 0;
l = 0; r = N - 1

from the start: 
dfs(0, n-1, 0, 0)

sw[s] - is door which is opened by switcher s
 0,1,2,3 
------------ 
 0,0,0,0  => 0
 
s = 0, e = 3, mid = (0+3)/2 = 1
 
 1,1,0,0  =>  if first door is opened then, we need to look for in [s,m] 
in this case first door in not opened then look at [2,3]
s = 2, e = 3, m = 2



















