
This story takes place a long time ago, 
when the world was new and the IOI had not yet been dreamt.

Serpent lives in a land which has N billabongs (water holes), numbered 0, …, N ­ 1 .
There are M bidirectional trails, joining pairs of billabongs, 
which Serpent can travel along. 

Each pair of billabongs is connected (directly or indirectly) 
by at most one sequence of trails, 
though some pairs of billabongs may not be connected at all (thus, M ≤ N­1 ). 

Each trail takes a certain number of days for Serpent to travel along it: 
this number may be different for each trail.

Serpent's friend, Kangaroo, wishes to make N ­ M ­ 1 new trails, 
so that it is possible for Serpent to travel between any pair of billabongs. 

Kangaroo can create trails between any pair of billabongs, 
and every trail that Kangaroo creates will take L days for Serpent to travel along it.

Additionally, Kangaroo wants to make Serpent's travels as fast as possible. 
Kangaroo will build the new trails 
so that the longest travel time between any two billabongs is as small as possible. 

Help Kangaroo and Serpent determine the longest travel time between any two billabongs, 
after Kangaroo has built the new trails in this way.

      7
       \                   3 
        \4              6-----10     .4 
  0      2
   \    /          
  4 \  /2                1
     8              1----------3 
	              /  \   5 
	           7 /    \-------9
	      3     /  
	11-------- 5
	
In the picture above there are N = 12 billabongs and M = 8 trails. 
Suppose that L = 2, 
so that any new trail will require Serpent 2 days to travel. 
Then Kangaroo could build three new trails:

   between billabongs 1 and 2;
   between billabongs 1 and 6;
   between billabongs 4 and 10
   
The picture above shows the final set of trails. 
The longest travel time is 18 days, between billabongs 0 and 11. 
This is the smallest result possible—no matter how Kangaroo builds the trails, 
there will be some pair of billabongs 
that requires Serpent to travel for 18 days or more.

Dreaming

This is a combination of a few common tree processing tasks. 
Firstly, the longest path might just be within one of the original trees, i.e., a tree diameter. 
This can be computed recursively on a tree by determining, for each node, 
the two longest paths downwards via different children 
(one or both can be zero if there are fewer than 2 children). 
The diameter path will have a highest node, and so the diameter will be the sum of these two lengths.

When add an edge to a tree, we must decide where to make the connection. 
The longest path from the connection point to anywhere in the tree ought to be as short as possible, 
and so for each point in the tree we need to know the distance to the furthest point. 
This is slightly more complex than before, since we also have to consider paths that start upwards. 
However, a second recursive walk (this time computing top-down instead of bottom-up) 
allows the shortest such paths to be found. 

For a given tree, let the radius be the distance from 
the optimal connection point to the furthest point in the tree.

Finally, we must decide how to connect the trees together. 
Sort the trees by decreasing radius r1 > r2 > .... 
Clearly, there will be a path of at least length r1 + r2 + L. 
If there at least three trees, 
they can't all be connected to each other, 
so there must also be a path of at least length r2 + r3 + 2L. 
Conversely, by connecting the first tree to every other tree (always using the optimal connection points), 
it is not hard to see that there are no other paths that can be longer than the worst of these.

1. dfs to find max distabce in a tree









	
	