 
Marita's little brother has left toys all over the living room floor! 
Fortunately, Marita has developed special robots to clean up the toys. 
She needs your help to determine which robots should pick up which toys.

There are T toys, each with an integer weight W[i] and an integer size S[i]. 
Robots come in two kinds: weak and small.

  - There are A weak robots. Each weak robot has a weight limit X[i], 
    and can carry any toy of weight strictly less than X[i]. 
    The size of the toy does not matter.
	
  - There are B small robots. Each small robot has a size limit Y[i], 
    and can carry any toy of size strictly less than Y[i]. 
	The weight of the toy does not matter.

Each of Marita's robots takes one minute to put each toy away. 
Different robots can put away different toys at the same time.

Your task is to determine whether Marita's robots can put all the toys away, 
and if so, the shortest time in which they can do this.

Examples

As a first example, suppose there are 
A = 3 weak robots with weight limits X = [6, 2, 9] ,
B = 2 small robots with size limits Y = [4, 7], 
and T = 10 toys as follows:

Toy number 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
    Weight 4 8 2 7 1 5 3 8 7 10
    Size   6 5 3 9 8 1 3 7 6 5

The shortest time to put all the toys away is three minutes:
    
                Weak robot 0 | Weak robot 1 | Weak robot 2 | Small robot 0 | Small robot 1 |
First minute       Toy 0     |   Toy 4      |     Toy 1    |     Toy 6     |     Toy 2
Second minute      Toy 5     |              |     Toy 3    |               |     Toy 8    
Third minute                 |              |     Toy 7    |               |     Toy 9

As a second example, suppose there are 
A = 2 weak robots with weight limits X = [2, 5],
B = 1 small robot with size limit Y = [2], 
and T = 3 toys as follows:
   
   Toy number   0  1  2
   Weight       3  5  2
   Size         1  3  2
   
No robot can pick up the toy of weight 5 and size 3, 
and so it is impossible for the robots to put all of the toys away

int putaway(int A, int B, int T, int X[], int Y[], int W[], int S[]);

Description
This function should calculate the smallest number of minutes required for the robots 
to put all of the toys away, or should return ­1 if this is not possible.

A: The number of weak robots.
B: The number of small robots.
T: The number of toys.

X: An array of length A containing integers 
   that specify the weight limit for each weak robot.
   
Y: An array of length B containing integers 
   that specify the size limit for each small robot.
   
W: An array of length T containing integers that give the weight of each toy.
S: An array of length T containing integers that give the size of each toy.

Returns: 
The smallest number of minutes required to put all of the toys away, 
or ­1 if this is not possible.

Solution.

As is commonly the case for problems that ask how long some agents need to achieve a goal, 
the answer can be found by a binary search on the answer. 
So we need to decide whether the robots can clear the floor in S seconds.

We can simplify the problem slightly by noting that for each toy, 
we only need to know how many weak and how many small robots are able to move it, 
which can be found by binary searching the two lists (after sorting them). 
Of course, if a toy cannot be moved by any robot, return ­ -1.

Let's first decide the actions of the weak robots, starting from the weakest. 
There will be some set of toys it can handle. 
Since they effectively differ only in size, the weakest robot should work from the largest downwards, 
so as to make the job of the small robots easier. 

Also, there is never any reason for it to move fewer than S toys, unless it runs out. 
Now consider the 2nd-weakest robot. 
There will be extra toys it can handle, plus any light toys 
that the weakest robot didn't have time for. 

Since the weakest robot is finished, the difference in weights are irrelevant, 
and the 2nd-weakest robot should again work in decreasing order of size amongst the toys it can handle. 
The same process can be continued for the remaining weak robots.

Now consider the small robots, from largest to smallest. 
These can again take up to S toys, starting from the largest remaining one. 
If a robot is unable to handle the largest remaining toy, then S was too small.

Implementation can be done using a priority queue, implemented as a binary heap, 
representing toys that are light enough to be handled by the current robot 
and ordered with the largest at the head. 

The toys are initially sorted by weight. 
Each time a new weak robot is considered, new elements are added from the list of toys to the priority queue, 
and the robot then removes items starting from the head of the queue.

Assuming that T is larger than A, B, the running time will be O(T (log T)2): 
one log T for the binary search, the other for the priority queue operations. 
I think that it may be possible to reduce this to something like O(T·log T·log(max(A, B))) 
using the right sort of data structure for the priority queue 
(to allow S items to be removed in log time): 
something like an interval tree for the number of toys of each size.

Another solution

After answering in advance by using binary search, 
use a method to check if the answer is through greedy. 
This technique is known as Parametric Search.

If there is only one kind of robot, it will be solved very easily. 
However, it can be tricky to think that there 
are two types of robots (soft robots, small robots).

Answer m 
Assuming this, each robot is the maximum m 
It can carry a dog's toy. 

First, the softest robots have the largest 'size' toys that they can take 
m The dog carries. 
If a toy you can takem If less than a dog, carry them all.

Finally, if there are no toys left, that is, 
the robots have transported all the toys m
Can be the answer. 
If not, the answer ismGreater than

If the fragile robots take the toy in this way at first, 
the method is effective because it carries as many toys as possible 
and at the same time the size of the remaining toys is minimal.

Knowledge
A manager is committed to the success of the project and of all team members.
Being Human
Versatility
A stellar manager doesn't just produce outstanding results; s/he has fun in the process! 
Lightness doesn't impede results but rather, helps to move the team forward. 













Good manager 
Superior communication skills
Leading with transparency and honesty.
Supporting your employees with clear direction and removing their roadblocks for them
Creativity














	