
BUSES

Portsaid is a north-eastern Egyptian city that lies near the Suez Canal. 
All streets in Portsaid are perfect straight lines oriented either north-south or east-west. 
Note that an intersection is a place where two streets cross each other. 

The public transport system of Portsaid consists of R bus routes. 
A route is a predefined cycle inside the city that is followed by a bus 
stopping at every intersection on that route.  

Each route has exactly one bus assigned to it that follows its path. 
Every bus has a fee fi, once paid you can take the bus as long as you want, 
but once you get off, you’ll have to pay the bus fee again for another ride.

Since not every intersection in the city lies on the path of a route, 
sometimes you have to walk to be able to move from some intersection to another. 
When walking from one intersection to another, you can only use the streets.  

Today you are in Portsaid for vacation and you want to go from intersection A to intersection B.  
Since you are here for vacation, you decided not to walk more than D blocks 
(A block is a distance that separates two consecutive intersections along a street). 
Also, you want to spend as little money as you can.   

