
GAME

You are playing a computer game. 
Initially you have control of all N cities in the game. 
The cities can be seen as a sequence of adjacent squares that are numbered from 0 to N-1 as shown in figure. 
By the end of each year, you gain some profit (Pi) from each city that is still under your control. 
Note, that the profits associated with each city are not the same since the resources of cities are different. 
Your kingdom withstood many attacks in the past, but now your enemy is preparing an enormous army 
that will crush your whole kingdom. 
As your defeat is certain, your aim is to have the maximum possible accumulated profit before losing everything

Each year you choose to build your bastions between 2 adjacent cities that are still under your control.
Then, the enemy chooses to attack you either from the west taking control of all cities 
before the bastions or from the east taking control of all cities after your bastions. 

By the end of that year, you get the profits associated only with the cities 
that are still under your control after the attack. 

Also, by the end of the year, your enemy will succeed to destroy the bastions 
but he will stop fighting until reinforcements arrive for the next year. 
In each of the next years, the same scenario happens 
again taking into consideration only cities that are still under your control.


TASK

This is an interactive task. Your task is to have the maximum possible profit 
before losing control of all cities. 
You should achieve this task by carefully choosing where to put your bastions 
each year keeping in mind that your enemy is playing optimally concerning 
his choice of whether attacking from the east or from the west of the bastions 
(he is trying to minimize your final profit).


LIBRARY

Your program must use a special library to play the game. 
The library consists of the files: pgamelib.pas (pascal), cgamelib.h and cgamelib.c (C/C++). 
The library provides the following functionalities:

  - procedure initialize()/void initialize() –    
    which must be called only once by your program. 
	This call must be performed before any other calls for any of the following 3 functions.  
	
  - function getN: longint/int getN() – 
    which returns the number of cities N (3 <= N <= 2000).

  - function getValue(city: longint):longint/int getValue (int city) –  
    which is given a city index (0 <= city < N) returns the profit associated with that city. 
	The profit ranges between 1 and 100,000 inclusive. 
	Calling this function with bad city index results in failure for your program for that test case. 
	Note, that city 0 is the leftmost and city N-1 is the rightmost.
	
Termination of your program is an automatic process when only one city is under your control. 
So, your program should keep making moves as long as there are still valid moves.
Your program must not read or write any files, it must not use standard input/output, 
and it must not try to access any memory outside your program. 
Violating any of these rules may result in disqualification.

SAMPLE INTERACTION

initialize() 
getN()        5    5 cities
getValue(0)   8    P0 = 8
getValue(1)   6    P1 = 6
getValue(2)   2    P2 = 2
getValue(3)   4    P3 = 4
getValue(4)   2    P4 = 2

move(1)       1    The 2 intervals are [0,1] and [2,4]. 
                   Your opponent takes control of [0,1] and you still have control of [2,4], 
				   so your score after this turn is P2+P3+P4
				   
move(2)       0    Note that the allowed moves here were only 2 and 3.
                   After you choose 2, the intervals are [2] and [3,4].
                   Your opponent takes control of [3,4] and you now have control of only one city so, 
				   you add P2 to your score and the game ends.

SOLUTION

This is quite obviously a task where dynamic programming shall be used – 
there are exponentially many ways the game can be played, 
but only polynomially many states in which the game can be. 

More precisely, at any moment the current state of the game is a contiguous subsequence 
of the original sequence of cities. 
In other words, each state can be uniquely described by the smallest index A of a city you have, 
and the smallest index B > A of a city you don't have. 
We will denote the state represented by A and B as [A,B).

Your goal at any moment is the same: 
maximize your profit in the game played from the current state. 

Let SA,B be the sum of profits for cities in [A,B) 
and PA,B be the best profit you can get from the game played on [A,B). 

In our solution, we will compute all the values PA,B, and for each of them the optimal first move.
Using this information we can then play the game optimally.  
Note that our opponent can compute the same values and use them for his optimal play as well 
– when presented with a choice, he will always pick the option that will give us a lower profit. 
We can use this observation to write a recurrence relation for the values PA,B:

PA,A = PA,A+1 = 0

PA,B = maxC( min(SA,C+PA,C, SC,B+PC,B) )

The second equality holds for B>A+1, where the maximum is taken over all C such that A<=C<=B.
An explanation in words: 
When we pick the place C where to place the bastion, 
the opponent will examine the two possibilities and leave us with the worse one. 
Knowing this, we can compute the profit for each possible choice of C, and pick the best one

By using the above recurrence, one can easily compute a single value PA,B in O(N), 
and as there are O(N2) pairs A,B, the total time complexity of the precomputation is O(N3). 
We can then make moves in O(1) each.

We can easily precompute the values SA,B in time O(N2). 
However, note that the values SA,B can be precomputed in O(N) time with O(N) memory 
– it is enough to store the values S0,X, as SA,B=S0,B‐S0,A.

To get a better time complexity, we need to find a way to limit the set of places C 
we need to examine when computing PA,B. 
We will use the following observation:

(*) 
Suppose that for the segment A,B the optimal split is C. 
Then for the segment A,B+1 the optimal split is at least C.
We will prove this later.

Once we trust that (*) holds, we can compute the values PA,B and CA,B in the following order:

[0,1) [1,2) ... [N‐2,N‐1) [N‐1,N)
[0,2) [1,3) ... [N‐2,N)
...
[0,N‐1) [1,N)
[0,N)

When computing  PA,B and CA,B, we know from (*) and from symmetry that it is enough to consider CA,B
between CA,B‐1 and CA+1,B, inclusive.

For each row of our table above, the total number of possibilities we have to try when computing it in
this way is at most 2N. If this is not clear to you, consider the following example:
The best split for [0,7) is between the best split for [0,6) and the best split for [1,7).
The best split for [1,8) is between the best split for [1,7) and the best split for [2,8).
The best split for [2,9) is between the best split for [2,8) and ...

Thus we get a solution with both time and memory complexity O(N2).

Lemma 1:
For all A, B we have PA,B+1 >= PA,B.

This is obvious. A formal proof by induction is possible, based on the fact that making the same split for
[A,B+1) as for [A,B) leads at least to the same profit.

Proof of the observation (*):

Let C be an optimal split for [A,B). 
We will show that for [A,B+1) there is some optimal split >= C.
Consider the values X =  SA,C+PA,C and Y = SC,B+PC,B.

We have PA,B = min(X,Y), and from Lemma 1 we have PA,B+1 >= min(X,Y)

Case 1: X <= Y.

In this case PA,B = X. 
Let D < C. Clearly SA,D < SA,C.
From Lemma 1, PA,D <= PA,C. Therefore SA,D+PA,D < SA,C+PA,C.

Case 2: X > Y.

In this case PA,B = Y. Let D < C. 
The split at C was optimal for [A,B), therefore the split at D was equal or worse.
This means that min(SA,D+PA,D, SD,B+PD,B) <= Y.
Clearly, from D<C it follows that SD,B+PD,B > SC,B+PC,B=Y 
for the same reasons as in the previous case
Thus we must have  SA,D+PA,D <= Y
This means that if we split [A,B+1) at D, our opponent can leave us with [A,D), 
which will give us total profit at most Y. 
However, the split at C will give us total profit more than Y,
therefore again D can not be an optimal split.





























  

	




