
Palindrome

PROBLEM

A palindrome is a symmetrical string, that is, 
a string read identically from left to right as well as from right to left. 
You are to write a program which, given a string, determines the minimal number of characters 
to be inserted into the string in order to obtain a palindrome.

As an example, by inserting 2 characters, 
the string "Ab3bd" can be transformed into a palindrome ("dAb3bAd" or "Adb3bdA"). 
However, inserting fewer than 2 characters does not produce a palindrome.

INPUT

The input file name is PALIN.IN. 
The first line contains one integer: the length of the input string N, 3 ≤ N ≤ 5000. 
The second line contains one string with length N. 
The string is formed from uppercase letters from ‘A’ to ‘Z’, 
lowercase letters from ‘a’ to ‘z’ and digits from ‘0’ to ‘9’. 
Uppercase and lowercase letters are to be considered distinct. 

A good method to solve this problem is to determine the length L of a longest common subsequence 
(maximal matching) for the input and its reverse. 
The answer then is N - L. 
An alternative approach is to match a prefix of the string with the reverse of a postfix.

The length of a longest common subsequence can be determined by dynamic programming. 
A triangular table can be constructed, of which only two rows need to be stored. 
The complexity is then O(N) space and O(N^2) time.

Note that constructing a witness 
(indicating where which characters have to be inserted to make a palindrome) 
is computationally more involved and is not asked.
For special inputs, other simpler methods may apply.

If the last two elements are different, 
it doesn't mean that the length of the LCS is 0.

I'm not sure if I understood your code right. 
Why don't you just take the reversed string and use 2D DP or just DP[from][to] 
without computing the LCS:

Let dp[i][j] gives us the answer for the sequence S[i],S[i+1],...,S[j].

Then you have two cases:

If S[i]==S[j], then dp[i][j]=dp[i+1][j-1].
If S[i]!=S[j], then dp[i][j]=1+min(dp[i+1][j],dp[i][j-1]).

Let S[a, b] denote the substring of S from the a-th character to the b-th character
I e.g. If S = abcdefg, then S[2, 5] = bcde
I If a > b, let S[a, b] denote an empty substring
I Define f(a, b) to be the minimum number of characters required 
to be inserted to S[a, b] to make S[a, b] a palindrome

Base Case: (a ≥ b)

   f(a, b) = 0
   
   I Recurrence: (a < b)
    
	f(a, b) = (
        f(a + 1, b − 1) if S[a] = S[b]
        min{f(a, b − 1), f(a + 1, b)} + 1 if S[a] != S[b]
		
  I Answer to the original problem: f(1, N)







