
TASK

Farmer Don watches the fence that surrounds his 
N meter by N meter square, flat field (2 ≤ N ≤ 500,000). 
One fence corner is at the origin (0, 0) and the opposite corner is at (N, N); 

the sides of Farmer Don's fence are parallel to the X and Y axes.
Fence posts appear at all four corners and also at every meter 
along each side of the fence, for a total of 4*N fence posts. 

The fence posts are vertical and are considered to have no radius. 
Farmer Don wants to determine how many of his fence posts 
he can watch when he stands at a given location within his fence.

Farmer Don’s field contains R (1 ≤ R ≤ 30,000) huge rocks 
that obscure his view of some fence posts, 
as he is not tall enough to look over any of these rocks. 
The base of each rock is a convex polygon with nonzero area 
whose vertices are at integer coordinates.

The rocks stand completely vertical. 
Rocks do not overlap, do not touch other rocks, 
and do not touch Farmer Don or the fence. 
Farmer Don does not touch the fence, does not stand within a rock, 
and does not stand on a rock.

Given the size of Farmer Don's fence, 
the locations and shapes of the rocks within it, 
and the location where Farmer Don stands, 
compute the number of fence posts that Farmer Don can see. 

If a vertex of a rock lines up perfectly with a fence post 
from Farmer Don's location, he is not able to see that fence post.

Input: boundary.in
  • The first line of input contains two space-separated integers: N and R.
  • The next line of input contains two space-separated integers 
    that specify the X and Y coordinates of Farmer Don's 
	location inside the fence.
  • The rest of the input file describes the R rocks:
    o Rock i’s description starts with a line containing a single integer 
	  pi (3 ≤ pi ≤ 20), 
	  the number of vertices in the rock's base.
    o Each of the next pi lines contains a space-separated pair of integers 
	  that are the X and Y coordinates of a vertex. 
	  The vertices of a rock’s base are distinct and given in counterclockwise order.

100 1    (N,R) N-length of the square side, R-number of rocks.
60 50    (X,Y) coordinates of farmer.  
5         pi - number of rocks.
70 40     
75 40
80 40
80 50
70 60

Output: boundary.out
The output file should contain a single line with a single integer, 
the number of fence posts visible to Farmer Don.

SCORING

You will receive full points on each test case for 
which your program produces a correct output file. 
No partial credit will be given on any test case.


Algorithms:

Note that there are many ways to get the computational geometry wrong. 
In addition, one must be very careful to avoid rounding mistakes in floating point numbers. 
Our low scoring solutions make errors of various sorts, and are not covered below.

Let d be the maximum number of vertices in any rock.

Algorithm 1: 
 Consider the fence as a circular list. 
 Each rock obscures a range of fence posts. 
 Determine the range for each fence post by sorting the angles of the rocks 
 from Farmer Don’s location 
 and find the right-most and left-most rock obscured 
 (being careful to deal with wrap-around). 
 Collect these ranges. 
 After processing all rocks, 
 sort the ranges and determine loop through the ranges, 
 counting any fence post not covered by a range.
 This algorithm takes O(R log R + N log d) time. 
 It is expected to receive full marks

Algorithm 2: 
 Keep a binary array of fence posts. 
 For each rock, determine the range obscured by the rock and reset those data points.
 This algorithm takes O(N R) time. 
 It is expected to receive about 80% of the points.

Algorithm 3: 
 For each rock and fence post, run a ray to determine 
 if the rock obscures the fence posts.
 This algorithm takes O(N R) time. 
 It is expected to receive about 72% of the points.

Solution:
 
Fix an interior grid point (X,Y). 
For each rock, 
we need to compute the segment of the fence that is blocked by the rock. 
For this, 
we have to compute the tangent points on the polygon. 

It is not difficult to see that the tangent must pass through a vertex of the polygon. 
There are K vertices. 
If we draw a line through each of these K vertices from (X,Y) and sort the slopes, 
the lines at the two extremes will be the tangents.

We number the trees 1..4N clockwise starting from the top left corner. 
For each rock r, we extend the tangents from (X,Y) to r 
to the boundary to identify a segment [Lr,Rr] 
of fence posts hidden by rock r. 
This takes time R (20 log 20) to process all the rocks. 

One minor point: if [Lr,Rr] include the top left corner 
— that is, it starts before 4N and wraps around beyond 1 
— it is better to split it as two intervals [Lr,4N] and [1,Rr] 
to make all later calculations easier.

Now, for each fence post, we have to determine if it is hidden by some segment. 
If we do this naively, 
we will have to examine all R segments for each fence post, 
making the complexity NR.

We can do much better. 
We sort the R segments by the starting point. 
We then start walking from fence post 1. 
We maintain a count that keeps track of how many rocks are hiding the current fence post. 
Each time we enter a hidden segment, we increment the count. 
Each time we exit a hidden segment, we decrement the count. 

The current fence post is visible from (X,Y) precisely 
if the count is 0 when we reach that post.

It takes R log R time to sort the segments 
and then time N to traverse the boundary 
and compute the number of visible fence posts.



 
 




	  
	  

