
Trail Maintenance (interactive task)

TASK

Farmer John's cows wish to travel freely among the N (1 ≤ N ≤ 200) fields 
(numbered 1…N) on the farm, even though the fields are separated by forest. 
The cows wish to maintain trails between pairs of fields 
so that they can travel from any field to any other field using the maintained trails. 
Cows may travel along a maintained trail in either direction.

The cows do not build trails. Instead, they maintain wild animal trails 
that they have discovered. 
On any week, they can choose to maintain any or all of the wild animal trails they know about.

Always curious, the cows discover one new wild animal trail at the beginning of each week. 
They must then decide the set of trails to maintain for that week 
so that they can travel from any field to any other field. 

Cows can only use trails which they are currently maintaining.
The cows always want to minimize the total length of trail they must maintain. 
The cows can choose to maintain any subset of the wild animal trails they know about, 
regardless of which trails were maintained the previous week.

Wild animal trails (even when maintained) are never straight. 
Two trails that connect the same two fields might have different lengths. 
While two trails might cross, cows are so focused, 
they refuse to switch trails except when they are in a field.

At the beginning of each week, the cows will describe the wild animal trail they discovered. 
Your program must then output the minimum total length of trail the cows must maintain 
that week so that they can travel from any field to any other field, 
if there exists such a set of trails.

Input: standard input

  • The first line of input contains two space-separated integers, N and W. 
    W is the number of weeks the program will cover (1 ≤ W ≤ 6000).
	
  • For each week, read a single line containing the wild animal trail that was discovered. 
    This line contains three space-separated integers: 
	the endpoints (field numbers) and the integer length of that trail (1…10000). 
	No wild animal trail has the same field as both of its endpoints.
	
Output: standard output

Immediately after your program learns about the newly discovered wild animal trail, 
it should output a single line with the minimum total length of trail the cows must maintain
so that they can travel from any field to any other field. 

If no set of trails allows the cows to travel from any field to any other field, output “-1”.
Your program must exit after outputting the answer for the last week.

4 6  (N, W)  N is number of fields  
        
    10  - > .2 
      /	 _ / ^ 
   1./</ 2    \ 3  
   / \         \
  /   \6______ >.3
 / 3
V 
.4

	   
1 2 10   -1 No trail connects 4 to the rest of the fields.
1 3 8    -1 No trail connects 4 to the rest of the fields.
3 2 3    -1 No trail connects 4 to the rest of the fields.
1 4 3    14 Maintain 1 4 3, 1 3 8, and 3 2 3.
1 3 6    12 Maintain 1 4 3, 1 3 6, and 3 2 3.
2 1 2    8 Maintain 1 4 3, 2 1 2, and 3 2 3.

SCORING
You will receive full points on each test case 
for which your program produces the correct output. 
No partial credit will be given on any test case.

Algorithms:

Algorithm 1: 
After each year, compute the minimum spanning tree (MST). 
When computing the next year’s MST, 
only consider the trails within the previous year’s MST and the trail added.

This algorithm takes O(N Y log N). 
It is expected to receive full points.

Algorithm 2: 
Use a true incremental minimum spanning tree. 
Each year, determine the path between the endpoints of the new trail 
and find the maximum length trail in that path. 
If the length of this maximum trail is greater than the new trail, 
delete that trail and add the new one. 
Otherwise, ignore the new trail.

This algorithm takes O(N Y). It is expected to receive full points.

Algorithm 3: 
Recompute the MST after each year, considering all trails ever seen. 
Only consider the best trail between any pair of nodes. 
Use Prim’s or Kruskal’s algorithm to compute the MST.
This algorithm takes O(Y2 log N) time. 
It is expected to receive around 60% of the points.

Algorithm 4: 
Recompute the MST after each year, considering all trails ever seen. 
Use Prim’s or Kruskal’s algorithm to compute the MST.
This algorithm takes O(Y2 log Y) time. 
It is expected to receive around 50% of the points.

Computing Minimum Spanning Tree algorithm:

What is Minimum Spanning Tree?

Given a connected and undirected graph, 
a spanning tree of that graph is a subgraph that is a tree and connects all the vertices together. 
A single graph can have many different spanning trees. 
A minimum spanning tree (MST) or minimum weight spanning tree for a weighted, 
connected and undirected graph is a spanning tree with weight less 
than or equal to the weight of every other spanning tree. 
The weight of a spanning tree is the sum of weights given to each edge of the spanning tree.

How many edges does a minimum spanning tree has?
A minimum spanning tree has (V – 1) edges where V is the number of vertices in the given graph.

What are the applications of Minimum Spanning Tree?
See this for applications of MST.

Minimum Spanning Tree (MST) problem: Given connected graph G with positive edge weights, find a min weight set of edges that connects all of the vertices.
MST is fundamental problem with diverse applications.

Network design.

– telephone, electrical, hydraulic, TV cable, computer, road

The standard application is to a problem like phone network design. 
You have a business with several offices; 
you want to lease phone lines to connect them up with each other; 
and the phone company charges different amounts of money to connect different pairs of cities. 
You want a set of lines that connects all your offices with a minimum total cost. 
It should be a spanning tree, since if a network isn’t a tree 
you can always remove some edges and save money.

Approximation algorithms for NP-hard problems.

– traveling salesperson problem, Steiner tree
A less obvious application is that the minimum spanning tree can be used 
to approximately solve the traveling salesman problem. 
A convenient formal way of defining this problem 
is to find the shortest path that visits each point at least once.

Note that if you have a path visiting all points exactly once, it’s a special kind of tree. 
For instance in the example above, 
twelve of sixteen spanning trees are actually paths. 
If you have a path visiting some vertices more than once, 
you can always drop some edges to get a tree. 
So in general the MST weight is less than the TSP weight, 
because it’s a minimization over a strictly larger set.

On the other hand, 
if you draw a path tracing around the minimum spanning tree, 
you trace each edge twice and visit all points, 
so the TSP weight is less than twice the MST weight. 
Therefore this tour is within a factor of two of optimal.

Indirect applications.
– max bottleneck paths
– LDPC codes for error correction
– image registration with Renyi entropy
– learning salient features for real-time face verification
– reducing data storage in sequencing amino acids in a protein
– model locality of particle interactions in turbulent fluid flows
– autoconfig protocol for Ethernet bridging to avoid cycles in a network

Cluster analysis
k clustering problem can be viewed as finding an MST and deleting the k-1 most
expensive edges.

Below are the steps for finding MST using Kruskal’s algorithm

1. Sort all the edges in non-decreasing order of their weight.
2. Pick the smallest edge. 
   Check if it forms a cycle with the spanning tree formed so far. 
   If cycle is not formed, include this edge. 
   Else, discard it.
3. Repeat step#2 until there are (V-1) edges in the spanning tree.









	


