
A parking garage has N parking spaces, numbered from 1 to N inclusive. 
The garage opens empty each morning and operates in the following way 
throughout the day. 

Whenever a car arrives at the garage, 
the attendants check whether there are any parking spaces available. 

If there are none, then the car waits at the entrance until a parking space is released. 

If a parking space is available, or as soon as one becomes available, 
the car is parked in the available parking space. 

If there is more than one available parking space, 
the car will be parked at the space with the smallest number. 

If more cars arrive while some car is waiting, 
they all line up in a queue at the entrance, 
in the order in which they arrived. 

Then, when a parking space becomes available, the first car in the queue 
(i.e., the one that arrived the earliest) is parked there.

The cost of parking in dollars is the weight of the car in kilograms 
multiplied by the specific rate of its parking space. 

The cost does not depend on how long a car stays in the garage.
The garage operator knows that today there will be M cars coming 
and he knows the order of their arrivals and departures. 
Help him calculate how many dollars his revenue is going to be today.

TASK

Write a program that, given the specific rates of the parking spaces, 
the weights of the cars and the order in which the cars arrive and depart, 
determines the total revenue of the garage in dollars.

CONSTRAINTS

1 ≤ N ≤ 100     – The number of parking spaces
1 ≤ M ≤ 2 000   – The number of cars
1 ≤ Rs ≤ 100    – The rate of parking space s in dollars per kilogram
1 ≤ Wk ≤ 10 000 – The weight of car k in kilograms

INPUT

Your program must read from standard input the following data:

• The first line contains the integers N and M, separated by a space.

• The next N lines describe the rates of the parking spaces. 
  The s-th of these lines contains a single integer Rs, 
  the rate of parking space number s in dollars per kilogram.
  
• The next M lines describe the weights of the cars. 
  The cars are numbered from 1 to M inclusive in no particular order. 
  The k-th of these M lines contains a single integer Wk, 
  the weight of car k in kilograms.

• The next 2*M lines describe the arrivals 
  and departures of all cars in chronological order. 
  A positive integer i indicates that car number i arrives at the garage. 
  A negative integer −i indicates that car number i departs from the garage. 
  No car will depart from the garage before it has arrived, 
  and all cars from 1 to M inclusive will appear exactly twice in this sequence, 
  once arriving and once departing. 
  Moreover, no car will depart from the garage before it has parked 
  (i.e., no car will leave while waiting on the queue).  
  
OUTPUT

Your program must write to standard output a single line containing a single integer: 
the total number of dollars that will be earned by the garage operator today.

GRADING
For a number of tests worth 40 points there will always 
be at least one available parking space for every arriving car. 
In these cases no car will ever have to wait for a space.

Sample     
Input Sample Output
3    4    ( N   M ) number of parking spaces and number of cars    

2
3      rates of parking spaces 
5


200
100
300   weights of cars in kilogrames 
800


3    car 3 arrives
2    car 2 arrives 
−3   car 3 departs
1    car 1 arrives
4    car 4 arrives
−4
−2
−1


5300 


Car number 3 goes to space number 1 and pays 300 * 2 = 600 dollars.
Car number 2 goes to space number 2 and pays 100 * 3 = 300 dollars.
Car number 1 goes to space number 1 (which was released by car number 3) and pays 200 * 2 = 400 dollars.
Car number 4 goes to space number 3 (the last remaining) and pays 800 * 5 = 4 000 dollars.


2    4    ( N   M ) number of parking spaces and number of cars    

5
2      rates of parking spaces 

100
500    weights of cars in kilogrames 
1000
2000

3
1
2
4
−1
−3
−2
−4

Car number 3 goes to space number 1 and pays 1 000 * 5 = 5 000 dollars.
Car number 1 goes to space number 2 and pays 100 * 2 = 200 dollars. 
Car number 2 arrives and has to wait at the entrance.
Car number 4 arrives and has to wait at the entrance behind car number 2.
When car number 1 releases its parking space, car number 2 parks there and pays 500 * 2 = 1 000 dollars.
When car number 3 releases its parking space, car number 4 parks there and pays 2 000 * 5 = 10 000 dollars.


Solution. 


The problem is essentially a straight-forward simulation,
but the data structures required are not completely trivial. 
A simple implementation that does not require any kind of data structure 
beyond a fixed-size array will keep track of:

  • for each car, its state (absent, in the queue, or parked), 
	its parking space (if parked), 
	and its arrival time (if in the queue);
	
  • for each parking space, whether there is a car parked there.

Now one can process the input events one at a time. 
When a car arrives, loop over all parking spaces to find the first empty one. 
If one is found, park the car there. 
Otherwise, the car will have to go into the queue — so record its arrival time.

When a car leaves the garage, it will be replaced by the car at the front of the queue (if any). 
Loop over all cars to find the car that arrived earliest and is still in the queue. 

If one is found, park it in the parking space that has just been freed up, 
and mark it as no longer in the queue.
This solution runs in O(M2 + MN) time. 

This can be improved: keeping the queue in a separate array reduces this to O(MN), 
and also keeping the available parking spaces in a binary heap reduces it to O(M log N). 
However, these optimisations are not necessary to receive a full score.








 
  





