
 An extraterrestrial team of contestants, known as the aliens, 
 is coming to Plovdiv for the IOI. 
 They would like to land their ﬂying saucer on one of Plovdivs hills, 
 but they have no map of the city, 
 so they need to use their laser scanner to ﬁnd a hill. 
 
 The aliens have divided the city into a grid of N by M cells, 
 and each time they use the scanner they can determine the altitude of a single cell. 
 Their scanner is so precise that no two cells would ever have the same altitude. 
 
 The aliens deﬁne a hill as a cell that has higher altitude 
 than all of its adjacent cells. 
 Two cells are considered adjacent if they share a side. 
 Thus typically each cell has four adjacent ones, 
 with the cells on the border of the grid being the exception 
 (they have less than four adjacent cells). 
 
 The aliens have time for only 3 050 scans before their saucer hits the ground. 
 Help the aliens ﬁnd a hill before they run out of time.
 
 TASK 
 
 Write a program that, given the dimensions of the grid, 
 interactively uses the scanner to determine the location of a hill, 
 while doing no more than 3 050 scans in total.
 
 
 CONSTRAINTS 
 
 1≤ N,M ≤1 000 – The dimensions of the grid 
 1≤ Ax,y ≤2 000 000 000 – The altitude of cell < x,y > 
 
 INPUT
 Your program should read from the standard input a single line with two integers N and M, separated by a single space.
 
 INTERACTION
 After reading the input data, your program should start using the laser scanner.
 Each time you want to use the scanner for a cell with coordinates x and y (1 ≤ x ≤ N, 1 ≤ y ≤ M), 
 you should print a single line on the standard output, 
 containing three integers separated by single spaces: 0 (a literal zero), x and y, in this order.
 
 After submitting your request to the scanner, you should read a single line on the standard input. 
 It will contain a single integer: the altitude of the cell with coordinates x and y in some alien units.
 
 OUTPUT
 When your program has determined the location of a hill <a, b> (1 ≤ a ≤ N, 1 ≤ b ≤ M), 
 you should report your answer by printing a single line on the standard output, 
 containing three integers separated by single spaces: 1 (a literal one), a and b, in this order.
 
 First we make an observation: 
  starting at any point in the grid, we can “walk uphill” 
  until reaching a cell with no adjacent higher cells, which is a hill. 
  
  Furthermore, if we start from a cell with height h inside a region 
  bounded entirely by cells with height less than h 
  (or by the boundaries of the entire grid), 
  then this walk cannot leave this region, and hence 
  we know that a hill must exist inside this region
  
  We start the algorithm knowing that somewhere in the entire grid we have a hill. 
  The algorithm then repeatedly finds smaller and smaller rectangles known to contain hills. 
  At each step of the algorithm, we will have a rectangle with the following properties:
  
    1. The highest cell seen so far falls inside this rectangle1
    2. The rectangle is bounded by cells strictly lower than this highest cell, 
	   or by the boundaries of the original grid.
	   
  Although we do not actually perform an uphill walk, 
  the property noted above guarantees that this rectangle will contain a hill. 
  If the rectangle is 1×1, then it consists of just a cell which is a hill, and the problem is ﬁnished. 
  Otherwise, we can produce a smaller rectangle as follows. 
     
  First, use the laser scanner on every cell in a line that cuts the rectangle in half 
  (either horizontally or vertically, whichever will use the fewest scans)   
  
  Let H be the highest cell that has been seen so far 
  (including the cells that have just been scanned).
  Now if H does not lie on the cut, then it falls into one half of the rectangle. 
  This half then satisﬁes the properties above, 
  and we have successfully reduced the size of the rectangle.
  
  If H lies on the cut, then some additional work is required. 
  Scan the cells immediately adjacent to H that have not yet been scanned, 
  and let H0 be the new highest cell seen. 
  If H0 = H then H is a hill 
  (since we have scanned all its neighbours), and we can immediately terminate. 
  
  Otherwise, H0 does not lie on the cut, and we can proceed to select one half of the rectangle as before. 
  
  By repeatedly ﬁnding smaller rectangles known to contain a hill, 
  we must eventually ﬁnd a 1×1 rectangle and the problem is solved. 
  An upper bound on the number of scans required is 1002+502+502+252+252+···+5+5+3 = 3023 
  Slightly tighter or looser bounds can be obtained depending on exact details of the implementation, 
  but this is not important as full points are awarded as long as the number of scans is at most 3050
  
  We employ a divide and conquer algorithm, by scanning all cells on a
  line that cuts the area in half. For the highest cell in that line (call it X), 
  we scan the cells on either side of the line adjacent to that cell. 
  We now have a few cases:
    1) All the cells surrounding X are of lower height. X is then a hill
    2) At least one of the cells adjacent to X and not on the line is higher than X. 
	   If both cells are higher, then use the highest one; call the higher cell Y. 
	   Either Y is a hill, or there is another cell in the same half of the area as Y which is higher 
	   than it and is a hill. 
  
  In the event of option 2, the area being scanned can be shrunk to the
  half in which Y lies, and the process repeated. 
  The only minor thing that must be catered for, 
  is the case where we scan a line and the highest adjacent cell lies in the half 
  different to the globally best height in the whole area. 
  
  In such cases, the other half should be recursed into, otherwise a true hill might not be found. 
  Consider the following map:
  
     18  7  9 10  5  3
     12  6  8 11  4  2
     17 13 12 14 15 16
 
  And suppose that we started by scanning the whole of the middle row.
  We would find that 12 is the highest cell, and scan the cells adjacent to it, with heights 17 and 18. 
  Since 18 is the highest, we would recurse into the top portion of the map, 
  meaning we are required to solve the sub-problem: 
  
     18 7 9 10 5 3
	 
  We attack this problem by scanning the middle column, say the 9. 
  Since it is the only cell in the column it is also the highest, 
  and we scan the cells on either side, finding that 10 is higher. 
  If we now recursed  into the right half of this row, we would fail to find a hill 
  -- since the 10 is actually bordered by an 11 below it. 
  
  Instead, we must realise that although the 10 seems like it might be a hill, 
  we have seen a higher value of 18 and must thus recurse to the left.
  
  Similarly, if we scanned the 10 as the middle column, we might be
  tempted to declare it a hill, as the 9 and 5 adjacent to it are both lower. 
  Again, this is erroneous, and remedied by the fact that 
  we have seen a higher cell which lies to the left of the 10.
  	 
   
  

   
   
   
   
   
   
 
   
 
