
Mecho the bear has found a little treasure the bees secret honeypot, which is full of honey! 
He was happily eating his newfound treasure until suddenly one bee saw him and sounded the bee alarm. 
He knows that at this very moment hordes of bees will emerge from their hives 
and start spreading around trying to catch him. 

He knows he has to leave the honeypot and go home quickly, 
but the honey is so sweet that Mecho doesnt want to leave too soon. 
Help Mecho determine the latest possible moment when he can leave.

Mechos forest is represented by a square grid of N by N unit cells, 
whose sides are parallel to the north-south and east-west directions. 
Each cell is occupied by a tree, by a patch of grass, by a hive or by Mechos home. 

Two cells are considered adjacent if one of them is immediately 
to the north, south, east or west of the other (but not on a diagonal). 
Mecho is a clumsy bear, so every time he makes a step, it has to be to an adjacent cell. 
Mecho can only walk on grass and cannot go through trees or hives, 
and he can make at most S steps per minute.

At the moment when the bee alarm is sounded, 
Mecho is in the grassy cell containing the honeypot, 
and the bees are in every cell containing a hive (there may be more than one hive in the forest). 
During each minute from this time onwards, 
the following events happen in the following order:

  • If Mecho is still eating honey, he decides whether to keep eating or to leave.
    If he continues eating, he does not move for the whole minute.
	
  • Otherwise, he leaves immediately and takes up to S steps through the forest as described above. 
    Mecho cannot take any of the honey with him, so once he has moved he cannot eat honey again.
	
After Mecho is done eating or moving for the whole minute, 
the bees spread one unit further across the grid, moving only into the grassy cells. 
Specifically, the swarm of bees spreads into every grassy cell that is adjacent to any cell 
already containing bees. 
Furthermore, once a cell contains bees it will always contain bees
(that is, the swarm does not move, but it grows).

In other words, the bees spread as follows: 
When the bee alarm is sounded, the bees only occupy the cells where the hives are located. 
At the end of the first minute, 
they occupy all grassy cells adjacent to hives (and still the hives themselves). 
At the end of the second minute, 
they additionally occupy all grassy cells adjacent to grassy cells adjacent to hives, and so on. 
Given enough time, the bees will end up simultaneously occupying all grassy cells 
in the forest that are within their reach.

Neither Mecho nor the bees can go outside the forest. 
Also, note that according to the rules above, 
Mecho will always eat honey for an integer number of minutes.
The bees catch Mecho if at any point in time Mecho finds himself in a cell occupied by bees.

TASK
Write a program that, given a map of the forest, determines the largest number
of minutes that Mecho can continue eating honey at his initial location, while still
being able to get to his home before any of the bees catch him.

CONSTRAINTS
1 ≤ N ≤ 800 – The size (side length) of the map
1 ≤ S ≤ 1 000 – The maximum number of steps Mecho can take in each minute

INPUT
Your program must read from standard input the following data:
  • The first line contains the integers N and S, separated by a space.
  • The next N lines represent the map of the forest. 
    Each of these lines contains N characters with each character representing one unit cell of the grid. 
	The possible characters and their associated meanings are as follows:
	
    T denotes a tree
    G denotes a grassy cell
    M denotes the initial location of Mecho and the honeypot, which is also a grassy cell
    D denotes the location of Mechos home, which Mecho can enter, but the bees cannot.
    H denotes the location of a hive

NOTE: 
It is guaranteed that the map will contain 
exactly one letter M, 
exactly one letter D 
and at least one letter H. 

It is also guaranteed that there is a sequence of adjacent letters G 
that connects Mecho to his home, 
as well as a sequence of adjacent letters G 
that connects at least one hive to the honeypot 
(i.e., to Mechos initial location). 

These sequences might be as short as length zero, 
in case Mechos home or a hive is adjacent to Mechos initial location. 
Also, note that the bees cannot pass through or fly over Mechos home. 
To them, it is just like a tree.

OUTPUT

Your program must write to standard output 
a single line containing a single integer: 
the maximum possible number of minutes 
that Mecho can continue eating honey at his initial location,
while still being able to get home safely.
If Mecho cannot possibly reach his home before the bees catch him, 
the number your program writes to standard output must be −1 instead.

GRADING
For a number of tests, worth a total of 40 points, N will not exceed 60.

Example 1:

7 3

TTTTTTT
TGGGGGT
TGGGGGT
MGGGGGD
TGGGGGT
TGGGGGT
THHHHHT

After eating honey for one minute, 
Mecho can take the shortest path directly
to the right and he will be home in another two minutes, safe from the bees.

7 3
TTTTTTT
TGGGGGT
TGGGGGT
MGGGGGD
TGGGGGT
TGGGGGT
TGHHGGT

After eating honey for two minutes, Mecho can take steps →↑→ during the
third minute, then steps →→→ during the fourth minute and steps ↓→ during
the fifth minute.


Solution 1

Firstly, working with fractional amounts of time is tricky, 
so we will measure time in units of 1S seconds — let’s call them ticks. 
Bees take S ticks to move from one cell to the next, while Mecho takes one tick.

Let us try to solve an easier problem first. 
Suppose we know when Mecho leaves the honey: can he get home safely? 

If we can solve this problem, then we can use it inside a binary search 
to find the last moment at which he can leave.

Mecho’s moves will depend on the bees, but the bees’ moves are fixed, 
so let us deal with the bees first. 
A standard breadth-first search will tell us when the bees reach each grassy cell 
(this just means simulating the spread of the bees over time).

Next, we can perform a similar breadth-first search for Mecho 
to answer the question “How soon (if at all) can Mecho reach each cell?” 

This can be implemented almost exactly as for the bees, 
except that one must exclude any steps that would have Mecho move to a cell 
where he would immediately be caught.

These breadth-first searches can each be implemented in O(N2) time. 
The problem statement guarantees that Mecho will eventually be caught 
if he stays with the honey, it takes O(N2) seconds for the bees to cover all the cells 
they can reach, and we are only interested in integer numbers of seconds in the binary search. 

Thus, the range of values explored by the binary search is O(N2) 
and hence the time complexity of this solution is O(N2 log N).

Solution 2

Instead of using a binary search, we can use a more complicated method to
directly determine the optimal time to leave any cell.
The bees are processed as in the first solution. 
However, instead of working from the honey towards Mecho’s home, we start from his home. 
Since he is safe in his home, there is no limit on how late he can arrive there.
Now suppose we know that for some cell Y, 
Mecho must leave no later than t ticks (from the time the alarm went off) 
and still make it home safely. 
If X is a neighbouring cell of Y, 
what is the latest time Mecho can leave cell X to safely make it home via Y? 
Clearly t − 1 is an upper bound, otherwise he will reach Y too late. 
However, he must also leave Y before the bees get there. 
The latest he can stay will be just the minimum of the two constraints.

One can now do a priority-first search: 
simulate backwards in time, keeping track of the latest time to leave each cell 
(keeping in mind that X has other neighbours, and it might be better to leave via those than via Y ).
The time complexity of this solution depends on the priority queue used to order cells by leaving time. 
A binary heap gives an O(N2 log N) implementation,
and this is sufficient for a full score. 
However, it can be shown that the number of different priorities 
that are in the priority queue at any one time is O(1), which makes an O(N2) solution possible.

Binary search for results: 
low = -1, high = 2*n*n = 2*8 = 16


 t t t t t t t t t t t t  t   t  f  f  f  f 
-1,0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,16

Suppose that last test() == true was at delay 11, delay 12 is false. Need to return delay.
Binary search should stop when low == 12 and high == 13. 
high - low == 1. if high - low > 1 we need to do binary search: 
mid = (-1 + 16) / 2 = 7 = t => low = 7, high = 16
mid = (7 + 16) / 2 = 23 / 2 = 11 => low = 11, high = 16
mid = (11 + 16) / 2 = 27 / 2 = 13 => low = 11, high = 13

















