 
 The Plovdiv Museum of Modern Art has an exhibition of ancient Thracian vases. 
 There are N vases total. 
 The first one is a miniature of height 1 centimeter.
 The second one is of height 2 centimeters; 
 the third one is 3 centimeters tall and so on 
 until the Nth vase, which is N centimeters tall.
 
 Since this a modern art museum and the vases are ancient, 
 the organizers of the exhibition would like to add a modern, 
 chaotic twist to the presentation of the vases. 
 
 They have decided to arrange the vases in a line 
 that satisfies the following condition: 
 For any three vases A, B and C, such that Bs height 
 is exactly the average of the heights of A and C, either B 
 must be positioned to the left of both A and C, 
 or B must be positioned to the right of both A and C 
 (in other words, B may not be positioned between A and C on the line).
 
 TASK 
 
 Write a program that, given the number of vases, determines 
 a linear arrangement of the vases 
 that satisﬁes the condition of the exhibition organizers.
 
 CONSTRAINTS 
 1≤ N ≤2 000 The number of vases 
 
 INPUT 
 You are given ﬁve problem instances in the ﬁles museum.1.in to museum.5.in. 
 Each ﬁle contains a single line, which in turn contains a single integer: 
 the number of vases N.
 
 OUTPUT 
 You are to submit ﬁve output ﬁles, named museum.1.out to museum.5.out, 
 each corresponding to one of the input ﬁles. 
 The ﬁles should be in the following format: 
 There should be N lines, each representing the N positions in the arrangement, in order from left to right. 
 Line k should contain a single integer Hk, 
 the height of the vase you decided to place on position k. 
 All N heights should be distinct integers between 1 and N inclusive.
 
 SOLUTION
 To solve this problem, we start by observing 
 that if we have three vases with heights A, B and C, 
 such that either A is odd and C even, or A even and C odd, 
 then no matter what B is these three vases 
 will not violate the condition of the exhibition organisers. 
 This is because A+C must therefore be odd, and so is not divisible by two, 
 meaning that it is impossible for B to be the average of A and C. 
 
 We therefore start by arranging the vases such that we place all the even vases ﬁrst, 
 and all the odd vases second. 
 This gives an arrangement that looks like this:
  
   E1 E2 ... Ep O1 O2 ... Oq 

 where E1,E2,...,Ep are the even heights in some order, 
 and O1,O2,...,Oq are the odd heights in some order. 
 
 Now consider any heights A,B,C which violate the organisers’ requirements. 
 By the observations above, either A and C are both even 
 (in which case B is even, since it appears between A and C and all the even values are grouped together), 
 or A and C are both odd (in which case B is also odd)
 
 In other words, we can consider the problems of ordering the even numbers and the odd numbers separately. 
 
 Now suppose that a1,a2,...,ap is a permutation of the heights 1,2,...,p 
 which satisﬁes the organisers’ requirements 
 (this is a smaller instance of the problem, so it can be solved by divide-and-conquer). 
 Then simply assigning Ei = 2ai will satisfy the requirements on the even values. 
 Similarly, given a permutation b1,b2,...,bq of the heights 1,2,...,q 
 which satisﬁes the requirements, we can assign Oi = 2bi−1. 
 
 Examining the properties of the resulting sequence gives another approach to generating the same solution. 
 We can write all the heights in binary form, 
 and then sort them according to the reverse of their binary form. 
 This sorts ﬁrst on the least signiﬁcant bit (i.e., on whether they are odd or even), 
 then the next least signiﬁcant bit and so on. 
 To prove that this solution is valid, 
 note that if B is the average of A and C, 
 then at the least signiﬁcant bit that A and B ﬁrst diﬀer, 
 A and C must have the same value for that bit, 
 placing A and C in a separate group from B when sorting on that bit.

 To solve this problem, we start by observing that 
 if we have three vases with heights A, B and C, 
 such that either A is odd and C even or A even and C odd, 
 then no matter what B is these three vases will not violate the condition of the exhibition organisers. 
 This is because A + C must therefore be odd, and so is not divisble by 2, 
 meaning that it is impossible for B to be the average of A and C.
 
 We therefore start by arranging the vases such that 
 we place all the even vases first, and all the odd vases second. 
 This gives an arrangement that looks like this:

   E1 E2 E3 ... Ex O1 O2 O3 ... Oy
   
 Since we know from the above observation 
 that it is impossible to choose A = Ei and B = Oj for any i and j 
 such that there is a vase C between these which violates the organisers' condition, 
 it follows that if there is a violation 
 we must have either A = Ei and B = Ej or A = Oi and B = Oj.  
 
 Consider the even vases -- each has height 2X for some X. 
 Suppose we pick three vases with heights A = 2X, B = 2Y and C = 2Z 
 such that they violate the condition. 
 We must then have 2 * 2Y = 2X + 2Z, which implies that 2Y = X + Z. 
 Similarly to above, it follows that X and Z 
 must either both be even or both be odd. 
 If X and Z are even, then A and C are divisible by 4, 
 and if X and Z are odd then A and C are not divisible by 4. 
 To eliminate these condition violations, 
 we thus arrange the even group of vases 
 such that they start with those divisible by 4 and are followed by those not divisible by 4.
 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
   

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 

 
   