
Plovdiv’s famous master chocolatier Bonny needs to cut a slab of chocolate with raisins. 
The chocolate is a rectangular block of identical square pieces. 
The pieces are aligned with the edges of the chocolate, 
and they are arranged in N rows and M columns, 
for a total of N * M pieces. 

Each piece has one or more raisins on it, and no raisins lie between or across pieces.

Initially, the chocolate is one single, monolithic block. 
Bonny needs to cut it into smaller and smaller blocks until finally 
she has cut the chocolate down to its N*M individual pieces. 

As Bonny is very busy, she needs the help of her assistant, Sly Peter, to do the cutting. 
Peter only makes straight line, end-to-end cuts and he wants to be paid for every single cut he makes. 
Bonny has no money at hand, but she has plenty of raisins left over, so she offers to pay Peter in raisins. 

Sly Peter agrees to this arrangement, but under the following condition: 
every time he cuts a given block of chocolate into two smaller blocks, 
he has to be paid as many raisins as there are on the block he was given.

Bonny wants to pay Peter as little as possible. 
She knows how many raisins there are on each of the N * M pieces. 
She can choose the order in which she gives Peter any remaining blocks, 
and she can also tell Peter what cuts to make (horizontal or vertical) 
and where exactly to make them. 

Help Bonny decide how to cut the chocolate into individual pieces, 
so that she pays Sly Peter as few raisins as possible.

TASK

Write a program that, given the number of raisins on each of the individual pieces, 
determines the minimum number of raisins that Bonny will have to pay Sly Peter.

CONSTRAINTS

1 ≤ N, M ≤ 50 – The number of pieces on each side of the chocolate
1 ≤ Rk,p ≤ 1000 – The number of raisins on the piece in the k-th row and the p-th column

INPUT

Your program must read from standard input the following data:
  • The first line contains the integers N and M, separated by a single space.
  • The next N lines describe how many raisins there are on each piece of the chocolate. 
    The k-th of these N lines describes the k-th row of the chocolate. 
	Each such line contains M integers separated by single spaces. 
	The integers describe the pieces on the corresponding row in order from left to right. 
	The p-th integer on the k-th line (among these N lines) tells you 
	how many raisins are on the piece in the k-th row and the p-th column.
	
OUTPUT

Your program must write to standard output a single line containing a single integer: 
the minimum possible number of raisins that Bonny would have to pay Sly Peter.

GRADING
For a number of tests, worth a total of 25 points, N and M will not exceed 7.

EXAMPLE
Input

2 3 
2 7 5
1 9 5

output = 77

The first cut that Bonny asks Peter to make separates 
the third column from the rest of the chocolate. 
Bonny needs to pay Peter 29 raisins for this.

2 7 5  ->  2 7  | 5     pay 29 points 
1 9 5      1 9  | 5   

Then Bonny gives Peter the smaller of the two blocks: 
the one that has two pieces with 5 raisins each, 
and asks Peter to cut the block in two in exchange for 10 raisins.

5     5
  ->  -       pay 10 points 
5     5

After this, Bonny gives Peter the largest remaining block: 
the one having pieces with 2, 7, 1 and 9 raisins respectively. 
Bonny asks Peter to cut it horizontally, separating the first 
and the second row and pays him 19 raisins.

2 7     2 7 
     ->       pay 19 points.
1 9     1 9

Following this, Bonny gives Peter the top-left block, paying 9 raisins. 
Finally, Bonny asks Peter to split the bottom-left block, paying 10 raisins.

2 7   -> 2 | 7    pay 9 points

1 9   -> 1 | 9    pay 10 points.  total 77 points.


Solution

At any moment during the cutting, 
we have a set of independent sub-problems — blocks of chocolate. 
If we find the optimal solution for each of the blocks,
together we get the optimal solution for the whole chocolate. This clearly hints at
a dynamic programming solution.

Each sub-problem we may encounter corresponds to a rectangular part of the chocolate, 
and it can be described by four coordinates: 
specifically, two x and two y coordinates — 
the coordinates of its upper left and lower right corner. Hence we have O(N4) sub-problems to solve.

Now to solve a given sub-problem, we have to try all possible cuts. 
There are O(N) possible cuts to try — at most N − 1 horizontal and N − 1 vertical ones.
Each possible cut gives us two new, smaller sub-problems we solve recursively.
Obviously, the recursion stops as soon as we reach a 1 × 1 block

Assume that someone has given us a function S(x1, y1, x2, y2) 
that returns the number of raisins in the rectangle given by coordinates (x1, y1) and (x2, y2) in constant time.
Using this function we can solve the entire problem in O(N5). 

We will use recursion with memoization. 
Given any of the O(N4) sub-problems, 
first check the memoization table to see whether we have computed it already. 

If yes, simply return the previously computed value. 
Otherwise, proceed as follows: 

The cost of the first cut is S(x1, y1, x2, y2), 
which we have supposed can be computed in O(1) time. 

For each possible placement of the first cut, 
recursively determine the cost of the remaining cuts in each sub-problem, 
and pick the optimal choice, storing the answer in the memoization table.

We are only missing one piece of the puzzle: the function S. 
All possible values can easily be precomputed in O(N4) and stored in an array.

Alternatively, we can use two-dimensional prefix sums: 
let A be the input array, and 

let Bx,y = Sum(i<x)Sum(j<y) Ai,j 

The values B are called two-dimensional prefix sums. 
They can be computed using the formula

∀x, y > 0 : Bx,y = Bx−1,y + Bx,y−1 − Bx−1,y−1 + Ax−1,y−1.

Having the two-dimensional prefix sums, we can compute the sum in any rectangle, using a similar formula. 
The sum in the rectangle with corners (x1, y1) and (x2, y2) is:

S(x1, y1, x2, y2) = B(x2,y2) − B(x1,y2) − B(x2,y1) + B(x1,y1).


















	











