
  Plovdiv’s famous master chocolatier Bonny needs to cut a slab of chocolate with raisins. 
  The chocolate is a rectangular block of identical square pieces. 
  The pieces are aligned with the edges of the chocolate, 
  and they are arranged in N rows and M columns, for a total of N*M pieces. 
  Each piece has one or more raisins on it, 
  and no raisins lie between or across pieces
  
  Initially, the chocolate is one single, monolithic block. 
  Bonny needs to cut it into smaller and smaller blocks until finally 
  she has cut the chocolate down to its N*M individual pieces. 
  As Bonny is very busy, she needs the help of her assistant, Sly Peter, to do the cutting. 
  Peter only makes straight line, end-to-end cuts and he wants to be paid for every single cut he makes. 
  Bonny has no money at hand, but she has plenty of raisins left over, 
  so she offers to pay Peter in raisins. 
  Sly Peter agrees to this arrangement, but under the following condition: 
  every time he cuts a given block of chocolate into two smaller blocks, 
  he has to be paid as many raisins as there are on the block he was given
  
  Bonny wants to pay Peter as little as possible. 
  She knows how many raisins there are on each of the N*M pieces. 
  She can choose the order in which she gives Peter any remaining blocks, 
  and she can also tell Peter what cuts to make (horizontal or vertical) 
  and where exactly to make them. 
  Help Bonny decide how to cut the chocolate into individual pieces, 
  so that she pays Sly Peter as few raisins as possible. 
  
  TASK
  
  Write a program that, given the number of raisins on each of the individual pieces, 
  determines the minimum number of raisins that Bonny will have to pay Sly Peter. 
  
  CONSTRAINTS
  
  1 ≤ N, M ≤ 50 The number of pieces on each side of the chocolate
  1 ≤ Rk,p ≤ 1000 The number of raisins on the piece in the k-th row and the p-th column  
  
  INPUT
  
  Your program must read from standard input the following data:
    - The first line contains the integers N and M, separated by a single space.
    - The next N lines describe how many raisins there are on each piece of the chocolate. 
	  The k-th of these N lines describes the k-th row of the chocolate. 
	  Each such line contains M integers separated by single spaces. 
	  The integers describe the pieces on the corresponding row in order from left to right. 
	  The p-th integer on the k-th line (among these N lines) 
	  tells you how many raisins are on the piece in the k-th row and the p-th column.

  



   

