
The traveling salesman has decided that optimally scheduling his trips on land 
is an intractable computational problem, 
so he is moving his business to the linear world of the Danube River. 

He has a very fast boat that can get him from anywhere to anywhere along the river in no time, 
but unfortunately the boat has terrible fuel consumption. 
It costs the salesman U dollars for every meter traveled upstream 
(towards the source of the river) 
and D dollars for every meter traveled downstream 
(away from the source of the river).

There are N trade fairs that the salesman would like to visit along the river. 
Each trade fair is held for one day only. 
For each trade fair X, the traveling salesman knows its date TX, 
measured in the number of days since he purchased his boat. 

He also knows the fair’s location LX,
measured as the distance in meters from the source of the river downstream to the fair, 
as well as the number of dollars MX that the salesman is going to gain if he attends this trade fair. 

He has to start and end his journey at his waterfront home on the river, 
which is at location S, measured also in meters downstream from the source of the river

Help the traveling salesman choose which trade fairs to attend (if any) and in what order, 
so that he may maximize his profit at the end of his travels. 
The traveling salesman’s total profit is defined as the sum of the dollars he gained at the fairs he attended, 
minus the total sum of dollars he spent traveling up and down the river.

Keep in mind that if trade fair A is held earlier than trade fair B, 
the salesman can visit them only in this order (i.e., he cannot visit B and then visit A). 
However, if two fairs are held on the same date, the salesman can visit them both in any order. 
There is no limit to how many fairs the salesman can visit in a day, 
but naturally he can't visit the same fair twice and reap the gains twice. 
He can pass through fairs he has already visited without gaining anything. 

TASK
Write a program that, given the date, location and profitability of all fairs, 
as well as the location of the traveling salesman’s home and his costs of traveling, 
determines the maximum possible profit he can make by the end of his journey.

CONSTRAINTS
1 ≤ N ≤ 500,000    The number of fairs
1 ≤ D ≤ U ≤ 10     The cost of traveling one meter upstream (U) or downstream (D)
1 ≤ S ≤ 500,001    The location of the salesman’s home
1 ≤ Tk ≤ 500,000   The day on which fair k is held
1 ≤ Lk ≤ 500,001   The location of fair k
1 ≤ Mk ≤ 4,000     The number of dollars the salesman would earn if he attends fair k

INPUT
Your program must read from standard input the following data:
• The first line contains the integers N, U, D and S, in this order, separated by single spaces.
• The next N lines describe the N fairs in no particular order. 
  The k-th of these N lines describes the k-th fair and contains three integers separated by single spaces: 
     the day of the fair Tk,       t - day of the fair
	 its location Lk,              x - location of the fair
	 and its profitability for the salesman Mk.   a - profitability
	 
NOTE: 
All locations given in the input will be different. 
That is to say, no two fairs will happen at the same location and no fair will happen at the salesman’s home.

OUTPUT
Your program must write to standard output a single line containing a single integer: 
the maximum profit the salesman can possibly make by the end of his journey.

GRADING
For a number of tests, worth a total of 60 points, no two fairs will be held on the same day.
For a number of tests, worth a total of 40 points, none of the numbers in the input will exceed 5,000.
The tests where both of the above conditions hold are worth 15 points.
The tests where at least one of the two conditions holds are worth 85 points.

4 5 3 100    (N, U, D, S) -> (Number of fairs, cost of travelling, salesman location)

1.  2 80 100       (T1,L1,M1) - the day of fair, location and profit. 
2.  20 125 130
3.  10 75 150
4.  5 120 110 

     0  75   80       100          120  125
     |---|---|---------|------------|----|------------------>
                       S
days     10  2                      5    20

An optimal schedule would visit fairs 1 and 3 (the ones at locations 80 and 75). 
The sequence of events and their associated profits and costs would be as follows:

   The salesman travels 20 meters upstream at a cost of 100 dollars. Profit so far: -100
   He attends fair number 1 and earns 100. Profit so far: 0
   He travels 5 meters upstream at a cost of 25. Profit so far: -25
   He attends fair number 3 where he earns 150. Profit so far: 125
   He travels 25 meters downstream to return home at a cost of 75. Profit at the end: 50 

   
Solution   

We’ll start by considering only the case where no two fairs occur on the same day. 
Later we’ll show how to modify our algorithm to incorporate fairs that occur on the same day.

The first polynomial solution
First we’ll describe a fairly standard dynamic programming algorithm. 
We order the fairs according to the day when they take place. 
For each fair i we will compute the best profit Pi we can achieve immediately after visiting this fair.

To avoid special cases, we’ll add dummy fairs 0 and N + 1 which both take place at the salesman’s home, 
fair 0 being the first and fair N + 1 the last of all fairs. 

We can immediately tell that P0 = 0 and that PN+1 is the answer we are supposed to compute.

The values P1 to PN+1 can all be computed in order, using the same observation: 

we have to arrive from some fair, and we may pick which one it is.
Let cost(x, y) be the cost of travelling from point x to point y on the river. 

If x ≤ y, we have cost(x, y) = (y − x)D, otherwise we have cost(x, y) = (x − y)U.

We can then write: ∀i ∈ {1, . . . , N + 1} : 

       Pi = max0≤j<i(Pj − cost(Lj , Li)) + Mi

Explanation: 
To compute Pi we pick the number j of the fair we visited immediately before fair i. 
Immediately after fair j the best profit we could have was Pj. 

We then have to travel to the location of the current fair, which costs us cost(Lj , Li), 
and finally we visit fair i for a profit Mi. 

To obtain the largest possible Pi we take the maximum over all possible choices of j.
The time complexity of this algorithm is O(N2), 
which is sufficient to solve the cases where all the input values are at most 5,000.


An improved solution

We will now improve the previous algorithm. 
Note that the profit Mi from visiting fair i is the same for all choices of j. 
Thus, the optimal choice of j depends 
     on the profits P0, . . . , Pi−1, 
	  the locations L0, . . . , Li−1, 
	  and the location Li of the current fair.
	  
We can divide the fairs 0 to i − 1 into two groups: 
   those upstream of Li, 
   and those downstream. 
   
We can now divide our problem “find the optimal j” into two subparts: 
      “find the optimal choice for the previous fair upstream” 
  and “find the optimal choice for the previous fair downstream”.
  
Consider locating the optimal previous fair upstream of Li. 
If we were to change the value Li 
(in such a way that it does not change which other fairs are upstream of fair i), 
can it influence our choice? 

No, it can not. 

If we, for example, increase Li by ∆, this means that for each of the upstream fairs 
the cost of travelling to fair i increases by the same amount: D * ∆. 
Hence the optimal choice would remain the same.

We will now show a relatively simple data structure 
that will allow us to locate the optimal previous fair upstream of fair i in O(log N) time.

The data structure is commonly known as an interval tree. 
We can assign the fairs new labels according to their unique positions on the river. 
More precisely, 
  let lf be the number of fairs that are upstream of fair f (including those that occur after fair f).
  
Our interval tree is a complete binary tree with k levels, 
where k is the smallest integer such that 2^(k−1) ≥ N + 2. 
Note that k = O(log N).

Leaves in this binary tree correspond to the fairs, 
and the order in which fairs are assigned to leaves is given by the values li. 

That is, the leftmost leaf is the fair closest to the river source, 
the second leaf is the second-closest fair, and so on.

Now note that each node in our tree corresponds to an interval of fairs 
— hence the name “interval tree”. 

In each node of the interval tree we will store the answer to the following question: 

  “Let S be the set of fairs that correspond to leaves in this subtree and were already processed. 
   Supposing that I’m downstream from each of them, which one is the optimal choice?”
   
Given this information, we can easily determine the optimal choice for the next fair i in O(log N). 
And it is also easy to update the information in the tree after fair i was processed; 
this too can be done in O(log N).

In our solution we will, of course, have two interval trees: 
one for the direction upstream and one for the direction downstream. 
For each fair i, we first make two queries to determine the best predecessor upstream and downstream, 
then we pick the better of those two choices, compute Pi, and finally we update both interval trees.


Another equally good solution

In this section we will show another solution with the same complexity, 
which uses an “ordered set” data structure only, 
and can easily be implemented in C++ using the set class

As before, we will process the fairs one by one, 
ordered by the day on which they occur. 
Imagine a situation after we have processed some fairs. 
Let a and b be two fairs that we have already processed. 
We say that a is covered by b if 
  
    Pa ≤ Pb − cost(Lb, La).

In human words, a is covered by b if the strategy 
“visit fair b last and then move to the location of fair a” 
is at least as good as the strategy 
“visit fair a last”.

Once a fair a is covered by some other fair b, 
this fair will never be an optimal predecessor for any later fair. 
Fair b will always (regardless of the location of the later fair) be at least as good a choice as a.

On the other hand, if a fair is currently not covered by any other fair, 
there are some locations on the river for which b would be the optimal predecessor —
at least the location Lb and its immediate surroundings.
We will call such fairs active.

In our solution we will maintain the set of currently active fairs, 
ordered by their position on the river. 
We will use an “ordered set” data structure, 
most commonly implemented as a balanced binary tree

It can easily be shown that for each active fair f 
there is an interval of the river where f is the optimal choice. 
These intervals are obviously disjoint 
(except possibly for their endpoints), 
and together they cover the entire river. 
And as the interval for f contains f, 
the intervals are in the same order as their corresponding active fairs.

Hence whenever we are going to process a new fair i, 
we only have to locate the closest active fairs upstream and downstream of i
— one of these two must be the optimal choice.

After we process the fair i and compute Pi, we have to update the set of active fairs. 
Clearly, i is now active, as we computed Pi by taking the best way of getting to Li, 
and then added a positive profit Mi. 
We add it into the set of active fairs.
But we are not done yet — i might now cover some of the previously active fairs.

But these are easy to find: 
if neither of the immediate neigbours of i (in the set of active fairs) is covered by i, 
we are obviously done. 
If some of them are covered by i, erase them from the set and repeat the check again.

In this solution, each fair is inserted into the set of active fairs once, and is
erased from the set at most once. In addition, when processing each fair we make
one query to find the closest two active fairs. Each of these operations takes
O(log N), hence the total time complexity is O(N log N).


Multiple fairs on the same day

First of all, note that we cannot process fairs that are on the same day one by one 
— because we must allow the salesman to visit them in a different order than the one we picked.

There may be many ways in which to visit the fairs on a given day. 
However, we don’t need to consider all of them, 
just some subset that surely contains the optimal solution.

Suppose that we already picked some order 
in which to visit the fairs on a given day. 

Let u and d be the fairs furthest upstream and downstream we visit. 
We can then, obviously, visit all fairs between u and v as well, 
as we’ll surely be travelling through their locations. 

And clearly to visit all of these fairs, 
it’s enough to travel first to u and then from u to v, or vice versa. 

We will only consider such paths.
We will process each day in two phases. 

In the first phase, we process each fair i separately, 
as if it were the only fair that day, and we determine a preliminary value Pi 
— the best profit we can have after coming to fair i from some fair on a previous day.

In the second phase we will take travelling upstream or downstream into account. 
We will consider each direction separately. 
When processing a direction, we’ll process the fairs in order, 
and for each of them we’ll determine whether it is more profitable to start at this fair 
(i.e., use the value computed in the previous step) 
or to start sooner 
(i.e., use the optimal value computed for the previous fair in this step, 
 subtract the cost of travel from that fair to this one, 
 and add the profit from this fair).
 
For each fair i, the actual value Pi is then equal to the larger of the two values we get for travelling upstream and downstream.

US.upt(s, -u*s);
DS.upt(s, d*s);


0                 s
------------------|--------



https://oj.uz/submission/53636

	
	
	


   
   





