
Parachute rings

An early and quite sophisticated version of what we now call a parachute 
is described in Leonardo's Codex Atlanticus (ca. 1485). 
Leonardo's parachute consisted of a sealed linen cloth held open by a pyramid-shaped wooden structure.

Linked rings

Skydiver Adrian Nicholas tested Leonardo's design more than 500 years later. 
For this, a modern lightweight structure tied Leonardo's parachute to the human body. 
We want to use linked rings, which also provide hooks for the sealed linen cloth. 
Each ring is made of flexible and strong material. 
Rings can be easily linked together as every ring can be opened and re-closed. 
A special configuration of linked rings is the chain. 
A chain is a sequence of rings in which each ring is only connected to its (at most two) neighbours, as illustrated below. 
This sequence must have a start and an end (rings that are connected to at most one other ring each). 
Specifically, a single ring is also a chain.

Other configurations are clearly possible, since a ring can be linked to three or more other rings. 
We say that a ring is critical if after opening and removing it, 
all remaining rings form a set of chains (or there are no other rings left). 
In other words, there can be nothing but chains left.

Example

Consider the 7 rings in the next figure, numbered from 0 to 6. There are two critical rings. 
One critical ring is 2: 
   after its removal, the remaining rings form chains [1], [0, 5, 3, 4] and [6]. 

The other critical ring is 3: 
   after its removal, the remaining rings form chains [1, 2, 0, 5], [4] and [6]. 
   
If we remove any other ring, we do not obtain a set of disjoint chains. 
For example, after removing ring 5: 
although we have that [6] is a chain, 
the linked rings 0, 1, 2, 3 and 4 do not form a chain.

Statement

Your task is to count the number of critical rings in a given configuration 
that will be communicated to your program.

At the beginning, there are a certain number of disjoint rings. 
After that, rings are linked together.
At any given time, you can be asked to return the number of critical rings in the current configuration. 
Specifically, you have to implement three routines.

Init(N) — it is called exactly once at the beginning to communicate 
          that there are N disjoint rings numbered from 0 to N - 1 (inclusive) in the initial configuration.
		  
Link(A, B) — the two rings numbered A and B get linked together. 
             It is guaranteed that A and B are different and not already linked directly; 
			 apart from this, there are no additional conditions on A and B, 
			 in particular no conditions arising from physical constraints. 
			 Clearly, Link(A, B) and Link(B, A) are equivalent.
			 
CountCritical() — return the number of critical rings for the current configuration of linked rings.

Solution

A suboptimal solution covering all but the last subtask considers the following conditions:

• if there is a vertex V of degree >= 4, 
  no other vertex can be critical 
  (because removing V still leaves one or more vertices of degree >= 3); 
  so if there is more than one vertex of degree >= 4, there are no critical vertices;
   
• if there is a vertex V of degree 3, each critical vertex is either V or one of its neighbors;

• if there is a cycle, all critical vertices lie on the cycle;

• if the graph is linear (a set of disjoint paths), all of its vertices are critical.
These checks can be easily extended to the dynamic case of the last subtask: 
the only nontrivial check is keeping track of cycle formation, 
which can be dealt with using suitable data structures (union-find d.s., etc.).

For this problem, the trick was keeping track of all the cases. 
Firstly, it is quite easy to keep a histogram of the degree of each ring. 
We can also keep track of the components, 
and the number of vertices and edges in each component 
(this can be kept in the root of a standard union-find structure). 
Now, let's consider cases:

1.If there is a ring with at least 4 connections, 
  it is the only possible critical ring, 
  because removing any other ring will leave it with at least three connections. 
  
    0 0
     0
	0 0
	
  If there is more than one such ring, there can be no more critical rings.
  
2. If there is a ring with exactly 3 connections, 
   only it and its neighbours can be critical rings. 
   There are thus at most four candidates to consider.
   
3. If all rings have at most 2 connections, there could be many critical rings. 
   Every component will be either a chain or a cycle, 
   and these can be distinguished by comparing the number of edges and vertices in the component. 
   If there are no cycles, all rings are critical. 
   If there is one cycle, all rings in that cycle are critical. 
   Otherwise there are no critical rings.
   
   0    one cycle means all rings are critical 
  0 0
   0
   
   0  0   
  0 00 0 more than one cycle - no critical rings 
   0  0
   
4. The last case can be checked as we go, 
   but the others are a little more tricky because they identify only candidates, 
   not definitely critical rings. 
   However, at most four rings can become candidates during the lifetime of the program: 
   the first to have at least three connections, plus those three neighbours. 
   As soon as a ring becomes a candidate, 
   we can replay all the previous connections on another union-find data structure with that ring removed, 
   and thereafter maintain that structure so that it can be examined after future connections.

I've omitted one minor detail: 
we also need to maintain in each union-find structure whether there are 0, 1, or more cycles, 
and if 1, the size of the component with 1 cycle. 
This can quite easily be maintained as the connections are made. 
Thus, total memory is O(N) and total time is O(N α(N)).

   1.     .2
   
other_endpoint  _1_|_2_
                 1 | 2

 .3----.1    .2-----.4				 
   
   







