
How does update work in Simple Segment Tree?
In the previous post, update function was called to update only a single value in array. 
Please note that a single value update in array may cause multiple updates in Segment Tree 
as there may be many segment tree nodes that have a single array element in their ranges.

Below is simple logic used in previous post.
1) Start with root of segment tree.
2) If array index to be updated is not in current node’s range, then return
3) Else update current node and recur for children.

Below is code taken from previous post.

/* A recursive function to update the nodes which have the given 
   index in their range. The following are parameters 
    tree[] --> segment tree 
    si     -->  index of current node in segment tree. 
                Initial value is passed as 0. 
    ss and se --> Starting and ending indexes of array elements  
                  covered under this node of segment tree. 
                  Initial values passed as 0 and n-1. 
    i    --> index of the element to be updated. This index  
            is in input array. 
   diff --> Value to be added to all nodes which have array 
            index i in range */
void updateValueUtil(int tree[], int ss, int se, int i,  
                     int diff, int si) 
{ 
    // Base Case: If the input index lies outside the range 
    // of this segment 
    if (i < ss || i > se) 
        return; 
  
    // If the input index is in range of this node, then 
    // update the value of the node and its children 
    st[si] = st[si] + diff; 
    if (se != ss) 
    { 
        int mid = getMid(ss, se); 
        updateValueUtil(st, ss, mid, i, diff, 2*si + 1); 
        updateValueUtil(st, mid+1, se, i, diff, 2*si + 2); 
    } 
}

What if there are updates on a range of array indexes?
For example add 10 to all values at indexes from 2 to 7 in array. 
The above update has to be called for every index from 2 to 7. 
We can avoid multiple calls by writing a function updateRange() 
that updates nodes accordingly.

/* Function to update segment tree for range update in input  
   array. 
    si -> index of current node in segment tree 
    ss and se -> Starting and ending indexes of elements for 
                 which current nodes stores sum. 
    us and ue -> starting and ending indexes of update query 
    diff -> which we need to add in the range us to ue */
void updateRangeUtil(int si, int ss, int se, int us, 
                     int ue, int diff) 
{ 
    // out of range 
    if (ss>se || ss>ue || se<us) 
        return ; 
  
    // Current node is a leaf node 
    if (ss==se) 
    { 
        // Add the difference to current node 
        tree[si] += diff; 
        return; 
    } 
  
    // If not a leaf node, recur for children. 
    int mid = (ss+se)/2; 
    updateRangeUtil(si*2+1, ss, mid, us, ue, diff); 
    updateRangeUtil(si*2+2, mid+1, se, us, ue, diff); 
  
    // Use the result of children calls to update this 
    // node 
    tree[si] = tree[si*2+1] + tree[si*2+2]; 
}

Lazy Propagation – An optimization to make range updates faster

When there are many updates and updates are done on a range, 
we can postpone some updates (avoid recursive calls in update) 
and do those updates only when required.

Please remember that a node in segment tree stores 
or represents result of a query for a range of indexes. 
And if this node’s range lies within the update operation range, 
then all descendants of the node must also be updated. 

For example consider the node with value 27 in above diagram, 
this node stores sum of values at indexes from 3 to 5. 
If our update query is for range 2 to 5, 
then we need to update this node and all descendants of this node. 

With Lazy propagation, we update only node with value 27 
and postpone updates to its children by storing this update information in separate nodes 
called lazy nodes or values. 
We create an array lazy[] which represents lazy node. 
Size of lazy[] is same as array that represents segment tree, 
which is tree[] in below code.

The idea is to initialize all elements of lazy[] as 0. 
A value 0 in lazy[i] indicates that there are no pending updates on node i in segment tree. 
A non-zero value of lazy[i] means that this amount needs to be added to node i in segment tree 
before making any query to the node.

// To update segment tree for change in array
// values at array indexes from us to ue.

updateRange(us, ue)

  1) If current segment tree node has any pending
     update, then first add that pending update to
     current node.
	 
  2) If current node's range lies completely in update query range.
     ....a) Update current node
     ....b) Postpone updates to children by setting lazy value for children nodes.
	 
  3) If current node's range overlaps with update range, 
     follow the same approach as above simple update.
	 
     ...a) Recur for left and right children.
     ...b) Update current node using results of left and right calls.
	 
Is there any change in Query Function also?

Since we have changed update to postpone its operations, 
there may be problems if a query is made to a node that is yet to be updated. 
So we need to update our query method also which is getSumUtil in previous post. 
The getSumUtil() now first checks if there is a pending update and if there is, then updates the node. 
Once it makes sure that pending update is done, 
it works same as the previous getSumUtil().




	  
	  
	  












