
 Archaeologist Benjamas is running for her life 
 after investigating the mysterious Crocodile's Underground City. 
 The city has N chambers. 
 
 There are M bidirectional corridors, each connecting a different pair of distinct chambers. 
 Running through different corridors may require different amounts of time. 
 Only K of the N chambers are exit chambers that allow her to escape. 
 Benjamas starts in chamber 0. 
 She wants to reach an exit chamber as quickly as possible.
 
 The Crocodile gatekeeper wants to prevent Benjamas from escaping. 
 From his den, he controls secret doors that can block any single corridor. 
 That is, whenever he blocks a new corridor, 
 the previously blocked one has to be reopened.
 
 Benjamas's situation can be described as follows: 
 Each time she tries to leave a chamber, 
 the Crocodile gatekeeper may choose to block one of the corridors adjacent to it. 
 
 Benjamas then chooses and follows one of the unblocked corridors to the next chamber. 
 Once Benjamas enters a corridor, the Crocodile gatekeeper may not block it 
 until Benjamas reaches the other end. 
 
 Once she enters the next chamber, 
 the gatekeeper may again choose to block one of the outgoing corridors 
 (possibly the corridor that Benjamas just followed), and so on.
 
 She would like to have a simple escape plan in advance. 
 More precisely, she would like to have a set of instructions 
 that tell her what to do when she gets to a chamber. 
 Let A be one of the chambers. 
 If it is an exit chamber, no instructions are needed–obviously, 
 she can escape the city. 
 
 Otherwise, the instruction for chamber A should have one of the following forms:
 
   • If you ever reach chamber A, take the corridor leading to chamber B. 
     However, if that corridor is blocked, 
	 then take the corridor leading to chamber C.
	 
   • Don't bother about chamber A; 
     according to this escape plan you cannot possibly reach it.
	 
Note that in some cases 
(for example, if your plan directs Benjamas to run in a cycle)
the gatekeeper may be able to prevent Benjamas from reaching an exit.
An escape plan is good if Benjamas is guaranteed to reach an exit chamber 
after a finite amount of time, 
regardless of what the gatekeeper does. 

For a good escape plan, 
let T be the smallest time such that after time T, 
Benjamas is guaranteed to reach an exit. 
In that case, we say that the good escape plan takes time T.

Your task

Write a procedure travel_plan(N,M,R,L,K,P) 
that takes the following parameters:

  • N – the number of chambers. The chambers are numbered 0 through N-1.
  • M – the number of corridors. The corridors are numbered 0 through M-1.
  • R – a two-dimensional array of integers representing the corridors. 
        For 0 ≤ i < M, corridor i connects two distinct chambers R[i][0] and R[i][1]. 
		No two corridors join the same pair of chambers.
  • L – a one-dimensional array of integers containing the times needed to traverse the corridors. 
        For 0 ≤ i < M, 
		the value 1 ≤ L[i] ≤ 1 000 000 000 is the time 
		Benjamas needs to runthrough the i-th corridor.
  • K – the number of exit chambers. You may assume that 1 ≤ K < N.
  • P – a one-dimensional array of integers with K distinct entries describing the exit chambers. 
        For 0 ≤ i < K, the value P[i] is the number of the i-th exit chamber. 
		Chamber 0 will never be one of the exit chambers.
		
Your procedure must return the smallest time T 
for which there exists a good escape plan that takes time T
You may assume that each non-exit chamber will have at least two corridors leaving it. 
You may also assume that in each test case there is a good escape plan for which T ≤ 1 000 000 000.

1 Subtask 1: Trees

In this subtask, we can infer that the underlying graph is a tree 
and the exit chambers are precisely the leaves. 
This is simpler than the general case but will be instructive for the next subtasks. 

To begin, let L(u,v) denote the time to travel 
along the corridor connecting node u to node v. 

For simplicity, we will root the tree at the starting node (chamber 0).

The crucial observation then is that in any successful escape plan, 
the instruction at each node, if reachable from the root, 
will always tell Somying to move further away from the root
(otherwise, she can be forced to cycle around the underground city forever). 

This leads to a simple dynamic programming (DP) solution: 
Let T[u] denote the best time to reach an exit chamber. 

First, T[u] = 0 if u is a leaf. 
Otherwise, if u has children v1; : : : ; vk,
ordered such that 
  T[v1]+L(u, v1) <= T[v2]+L(u, v2) <= : : : <= T[vk]+L(u, vk), 
then T[u] = T[v2]+L(u, v2). 

The problem statement guarantees that k >= 2.

It is easy to show inductively that T[u] is indeed the best time starting at u. 
Specifically, we prove that first, 
Benjamas can reach an exit chamber from u in T[u] time regardless 
of what the gatekeeper does, and second, 
the gatekeeper can force Benjamas to spend T[u] time in the underground city. 

Clearly, if u is a leaf node and hence an exit chamber, T[u] is 0. 
Assuming inductively that T[vi] is as claimed for each child vi of u, 
we have that in time T[vi] + L(u, vi), Benjamas can reach an exit from u, through (u, vi), 
if the corridor is not blocked. 

Since the evil crocodile can only block one corridor at a time, 
he can force Benjamas to spend T[v2]+L(u, v2),
by blocking (u, v1) | blocking any other corridor only helps Benjamas reach an exit faster, 
in T[v1] + L(u, v1) time.

To compute this DP, we traverse the tree in postorder 
(i.e., the leaves are visited first and each parent is visited after all its children); 
the final answer is stored in T[0]. 

The computation at each node involves finding the second smallest value, 
which can be done in O(du) time. 
Here, du denotes the (out-)degree of u. 
Therefore, the total running time is C * sum(u, du) = O(N), 
for some positive constant C, because the degrees of the tree nodes sum to 2(N - 1).

2 Subtasks 2 and 3: General Graphs

The challenge in generalizing our current algorithm to the general setting 
is the lack of a clear sense of direction; 
in our current algorithm, we know Benjamas must always move further 
from the root as necessitated by the tree structure.
A moment's thought reveals striking similarity between Dijkstra's single-source 
shortest path algorithm and our algorithm for trees. 
Indeed, the algorithm iteratively grows the frontier set,
where at any point in time, a node u is in the set if T[u] has been determined. 
From this view, our algorithm for trees can be seen as running Dijkstra's algorithm 
starting from the exit chambers. 
The algorithm is standard except for how the cost at a node is deffined.

Consider the following algorithm: 
For all nodes u, set T[u] to 1 except when u is an exit chamber, set T[u] = 0. 
Initially, the frontier set S contains exactly the exit chambers. 
During the execution of the algorithm, 
we maintain that for w not from S, 
the cost of w can be conceptually
computed by producing the list {v from N(w) : T[v]+L(w, v)}, sorting this list, 
and returning the second value (i.e., the second smallest value in this list). 
When a node u enters the frontier (it has the lowest cost among non-frontier nodes), 
T[u] is set to the cost of u at that moment.

Claim 1. 
For each node u, Benjamas can reach an exit from u in T[u] time regardless 
of what the gatekeeper does. 
Furthermore, the crocodile gatekeeper can force Benjamas to spend T[u] time in the underground city.

This claim can be shown by a similar inductive argument as in the tree case 
and by observing that as in Dijkstra's algorithm, 
once a node enters the frontier its cost cannot decrease because the edges have positive cost.

Implementation Details. 

For each node, we can maintain its cost by keeping two numbers
| the smallest value and the second smallest value|
which can be updated in O(1) 
when the neighboring values change. 
Using this, Dijkstra's algorithm takes O((M + N) logN) 
using a heap or O(N2) without using one.

dist[1][curr] it is the second shortest distance from exit nodes to curr node. 

We can't use dist[0][curr], because it can be blocked by a guardian.














 