
Dancing Elephants is a spectacular show in Pattaya 
that features N elephants dancing on a line, known as the stage.

After years of training, elephants in this show are capable of many amazing dances. 
The show consists of a series of acts. 
In each act, exactly one elephant performs a cute dance 
while possibly moving to a different position.

The show producers want to produce a photo book 
that contains pictures of the entire show. 
After each act, they want to take pictures of all elephants as seen by the spectators.

At any time during the show, multiple elephants may share the same position. 
In that case, they simply stand behind one another at the same position.

A single camera can take a picture of a group of elephants 
if and only if all their positions lie on some segment of length L (including both its endpoints). 

As the elephants can spread out across the stage, 
multiple cameras may be needed in order to take simultaneous snapshots of all the elephants

As an example, suppose that L=10 and that the elephants are at positions 10, 15, 17, and 20 on the stage. 
At this moment, a single camera can take their picture, as shown below. 
(Elephants are shown as triangles; cameras are shown as trapezoids.)

In the following act, the elephant at position 15 dances to position 32. 
After this act, we need at least two cameras to take the snapshot.

In the next act, the elephant at position 10 moves to position 7. 
For the new arrangement of elephants, we need three cameras to photograph all of them.

Your task
Write the following procedures:
    • Procedure init(N,L,X) that takes the following parameters:
    • N – the number of elephants. The elephants are numbered 0 through N-1.
    • L – the length of the segment captured by a single camera. 
	      You may assume that L is an integer such that 0 ≤ L ≤ 1 000 000 000.
    • X – a one-dimensional array of integers representing the initial positions of the elephants. 
	      For 0 ≤ i < N, elephant i starts at the position X[i]. 
		  The initial positions are in sorted order. 
		  More precisely, you may assume that 0 ≤ X[0] ≤ ... ≤ X[N-1] ≤ 1 000 000 000. 
		  Note that during the dance the elephants may reorder themselves.
		  
This procedure will be called only once, prior to all calls to update. 
It does not return any value.

  • Procedure update(i,y) that takes the following parameters:
     • i – the number of the elephant that moves in the current act.
     • y – the position where the elephant i will stand after the current act. 
	You may assume that y is an integer such that 0 ≤ y ≤ 1 000 000 000.
	
This procedure will be called multiple times. 
Each call corresponds to a single act (which follows on from all of the previous acts). 
Each call must return the minimum number of cameras needed to photograph all elephants 
after the corresponding act.

Example

Consider the case where N=4, L=10, and the initial positions of the elephants are
X = 10  - 0
    15  - 1
    17  - 2
    20  - 3 

First, your procedure init will be called with these parameters. 
Afterwards, your procedure update will be called once for each act. 
Here is an example sequence of calls and their correct return values

----|---------|----|------|---
    10	     16   20     25 
	

init(10,15,17,20)   need one camer of length 10
update(2,16)        need one camear of length 10
update(1,25)        need two cameras

Subtask 1

In subtask 1, there are only two elephants. 
Thus we can easily determine the number of required cameras in constant time. 
Namely, we only need one camera if the elephants are at most distance L apart; 
otherwise, we need two cameras.

2 Subtasks 2 and 3

If elephants are at positions x0, x1, ....., xN-1, 
such that xi <= xi+1 for all 0 <= i < N - 1, 
we can compute the minimum number of cameras required using a greedy algorithm.

We start with an empty set of cameras. 
While the current set of cameras do not cover all elephants, 
we choose an elephant which is not already covered with the minimum position xj, 
and place a camera to cover elephants at positions in [xj, xj + L]. 

We can implement this procedure to run in time
O(N) by iterating through the list of sorted positions once.
Each time an elephant moves in the show, we can update the sorted list of positions in O(N) time. 
Hence, we have an O(NM) solution to this problem, which is sufficient to fully solve subtask 2, 
and an adequate optimization is required to fully solve subtask 3. 
However, a faster algorithm is required for subtasks 4 and 5.

3 Subtasks 4 and 5
3.1 Bucketing elephants

To find the number of cameras, instead of iterating through all elephants, 
we shall build a data structure that allows us to "jump" over lots of elephants.
We maintain k buckets B0,B1, .... ,Bk-1 of elephants such 
that buckets with lower indices store elephants with lower positions, i.e., 
for any 0 <= b < k - 1, for all xi from Bb and xj from Bb+1, xi <= xj. 
Also, elephants in each bucket are sorted according to their positions.

The goal is to make sure that to find the number of required cameras, 
one needs to visit each bucket once. 
For simplicity, we will always place cameras so that 
the left-most position covered by a camera is the position of some elephant.

Consider bucket b with p elephants. 
Denote the list of indices of elephants in Bb as e0,e1,....,ep-1 (that is, xei <= xei+1). 
Given an elephant ei, we would like to answer the following two questions quickly:

    Q1: If we would like to cover all elephants starting from ei 
	   (i.e., elephants in the set {ei, ei+1, ...., ep-1}, how many cameras are needed?
	Q2: What is the highest position that these set of cameras cover?
	
For elephant e, denote the answer for Q1 for as J(e) and the answer to Q2 as T(e).
If we have these answers for every elephant in every bucket, 
we can find the number of cameras in time O(k logN) as follows.

We start by placing the camera at the first elephant in bucket B0, 
so that the position of this elephant is the left-most position covered by this camera. 
Now consider placing a camera at elephant e in bucket Bi in the same fashion. 

We know that to cover all elephants in Bi, we have to use J(e) cameras and these cameras cover positions up to T(e). 
We find the first elephant e0 not covered by these cameras in the next bucket Bi+1 
by binary searching for the elephant in Bi+1 whose position is minimum but greater than T(e). 
Then, we start placing the camera at elephant e0 in bucket Bi+1.

We repeat this step until we reach the last bucket. 
Since each step runs in O(logN) time (from binary search), we spend O(klogN) time as required.

We can precompute the answers for Q1 and Q2 for elephants in Bi in O(|Bi|) time 
by iterating over each elephant ej from ep-1 to e0 and keeping a pointer to the first elephant outside the range xej + L. 
For implementation details, please see the appendix.
It is crucial to note that we can process each bucket independent of all other buckets.

3.2 Updating the data structure

When an elephant e moves, we will have to update two buckets: 
  the current bucket Bi and the new bucket Bj. 
This can be done in time proportional to the current size of the bucket. 
To find the current bucket of e we can store a pointer from e, but it takes O(k) to find the new bucket anyway. 

Therefore, the running time for the update is O(k + |Bi| + |Bj|).
Note that the time depends heavily on the size of each bucket. 
Initially, we would have about N/k elephants in each bucket, but the number may grow as elephants can move. 
To keep the size of each bucket bounded above by O(N/k), 
we will rebuild the whole data structure for every [N/k] updates. 
The rebuilding takes time O(N).

3.3 Choosing the right parameter

We need to handle M updates and answer one question after each of these updates. 
The total running time is
  O(M * k logN) + O(M * (k + N/k)) + O(M * (N/(N/k))),

where the first term denotes the total query time, 
the second term denotes the total updating time, 
and the last term denotes the total rebuilding time.

Choosing k = sqrt(N) gives the running time of O(M * sqrt(N) * logN), 
which is sufficient to obtain full marks for this problem. 
However, an inefficient implementation may not be able to solve subtask 5. 
For example, using the set data structure in the C++ Standard Template Library
can introduce an extra factor of log n to the running time of rebuilding the data structure. 
This can be avoided by using simple arrays.

A Processing each bucket

To simplify the presentation, we add a dummy elephant ep at position xep-1 + L + 1. 
Also, we let yj = xej be the position of the j-th left-most elephant in bucket Bi.

We consider each elephant j from the right-most elephant ep-1 to the left-most one. 
We also maintain an index t that points to the left-most elephant et whose position yt > yj +L. 
Initially, j = p - 1 and t = p.

For each elephant ej, we will compute J(ej) and 
last(ej), the left-most elephant in the right-most camera in the set of cameras covering {ej, ej+1, ... , ep }

For the dummy node, we let J(ep) = 0 and last(ep) = ep. 
For elephant ej, we check if we need to move t, i.e., if the position of et-1 is greater than yj + L; 
if that's the case we find the smallest t such that yt > yj + L. 
We let J(ej) = J(et) + 1 and last(ej) = last(et).

Finally, for each elephant ej such that last(ej) points to the dummy elephant ep, we change last(ej) to ej.

We can complete the process using only one pass over all elephants in the bucket Bi 
and note that the pointer t moves over each elephant only once. 
Thus, the running time is O(|Bi|) as claimed.
To answer question Q2 for each elephant ej, we report ylast(ej ) + L.

group operation: 

for i = 0 to n
  gp[ci[i]] = i/sz;  
  
gp 0|1|2..|sz-1|  |sz| ......
   0 0 0    0       1  1  1 

i/sz - is group index 
gs[i/sz] - is group size; 
pos[gp[ci[i]]][gs[i/sz]] = ci[i]; position of element inside a group. 
gn - is number of groups 

Consider bucket b with p elephants. 
Denote the list of indices of elephants in Bb as e0, e1, ... , ep-1 (that is, xei <= xei+1). 
Given an elephant ei, we would like to answer the following two questions quickly:

  Q1: If we would like to cover all elephants starting from ei 
      (i.e., elephants in the set {ei, ei+1, ... ,ep-1}, 
	  how many cameras are needed?
	  
  Q2: What is the highest position that these set of cameras cover?
  
        int ptr = n[grp];
		for (int i = ptr - 1; i >= 0; --i)
		{
			int len = pos[grp][i] + L;

            while (pos[grp][ptr-1] > len)
			{
			    --ptr;
		    }
		}
		
Let's take the last elephant in the bucket and calculate how many cameras needed to cover elements {ep-1}
and highest position tese cameras can cover
		

|---|----------| .............|
0   1  ..... pos[p-1]       pos[p-1]+L

id we put camera at position p-1 it will cover region [pos[p-1],...,pos[p-1] + L]

check pos[p-1] > len - false

cam[p-1] = 1
end[p-1] = len

then we continue until we find first pi where pos[pi-1] + L is less than pos[p-1] - is does not cover the last point in bucket 


|---|---------|------------------|----------|
0   1  ..... pos[pi-1]  len=pos[pi-1]+L    pos[p-1]
                      
1. Currently p is the latest then we do while(pos[p-1] > len) p--; 
so p is always the farthest elephat that is covered by a camera put at elephant pi
   
if p == n[p] is size of the group then cam[pi] = 1 one camera is sufficient to cover all elephants from pi to last
if p < n[p] then camera that we put into pi will cover range [pi,...,p] and we need cam[p] to cover all further elephants

if p == n[p] the farter position that this camera covers is pos[pi-1] + L  if we have multiple pi, it will recude
if p < n[p] then   end[pi] = end[p] 


Query:
Take the first bucket i = 0;   |----|---| .... |----|...| 
                              start                end
							  
prev= -1; k = pos[0] - is start of the array. k = 0;
tot = cam[0][0] - number of cameras needed to cover the whole bucker starting at 0
prev = 


							  
							  







