
In conjunction with the IOI, Pattaya City will host a race: 
the International Olympiad in Racing (IOR) 2011. 
As the host, we have to find the best possible course for the race.
In the Pattaya-Chonburi metropolitan area, 
there are N cities connected by a network of N-1 highways. 

Each highway is bidirectional, connects two different cities, 
and has an integer length in kilometers. 

Furthermore, there is exactly one possible path connecting any pair of cities. 
That is, there is exactly one way to travel from one city to another city 
by a sequence of highways without visiting any city twice.

The IOR has specific regulations that require the course to be a path 
whose total length is exactly K kilometers, 
starting and ending in different cities. 

Obviously, no highway (and therefore also no city) may be used twice on the course to prevent collisions. 
To minimize traffic disruption, the course must contain as few highways as possible.

Your task
Write a procedure best_path(N,K,H,L) that takes the following parameters:
  • N – the number of cities. The cities are numbered 0 through N-1.
  • K – the required distance for the race course.
  • H – a two-dimensional array representing highways. 
        For 0 ≤ i < N-1, highway i connects the cities H[i][0] and H[i][1].
  • L – a one-dimensional array representing the lengths of the highways. 
        For 0 ≤ i < N-1, the length of highway i is L[i].
		
You may assume that all values in the array H are between 0 and N-1, inclusive, 
and that the highways described by this array connect all cities as described above. 
You may also assume that all values in the array L are integers between 0 and 1 000 000, inclusive.
Your procedure must return the minimum number of highways on a valid race course of length exactly K. 
If there is no such course, your procedure must return -1.

Example 1
Consider the case shown in Figure 1, where 
  N=4   - number of cities.
  K=3   - required distance for the race course.
  H= 0 1
     1 2
     1 3
  L= 1
     2
     4
	       2
	       |
	       | 2   
  0 ------ 1 -------- 3 	 
  	  1          4

The course can start in city 0, go to city 1, and terminate in city 2. 
Its length will be exactly 1 km + 2 km = 3 km, 
and it consists of two highways. 
This is the best possible course; 
therefore best_path(N,K,H,L) must return 2.

Example 2
Example 2
Consider the case shown in Figure 2, where 
N=3, 
K=3,
H=
  0 1
  1 2
L=
  1
  1
  
There is no valid course. 
In this case, best_path(N,K,H,L) must return -1.

Given a tree T with N nodes, this task asks for a path P* of length K 
with the minimum number of edges. 
It looks like a usual dynamic programming task. 
However, when K is large, another approach is required.

The model solution for this task follows a divide-and-conquer approach.
Consider a node u in the graph. 
There are two possible cases: 
   when node u belongs to the solution path P*; 
   or when node u does not.
   
In the second case, we can delete node u from the tree and break it into smaller trees. 
We can then recurse on each of the resulted trees to find the solution.

With this general approach in mind, we have to answer the following questions.
 - How to find the best path that contains node u?
 - How to choose u to achieve a better running time?
 
Note that the second question is very important because if we can guarantee 
that the sizes of all resulting trees are small, 
we can bound the number of recursion levels.

1 Finding the solution containing u

Consider the case that P* contains node u. 
Let's consider a simpler case where we only want to
find if there exists a path of length exactly K that contains u.

If u is one of the endpoints in P*, we can find the path 
using one application of depth first search (DFS).

However, if u is "inside" P*, then two of u's adjacent nodes x and y must also be in P*.
Thus, we shall find x and y.

Consider some node w adjacent to u. 
With one application of DFS, we can find the set Lw
of all path lengths for all paths starting at u and containing edge (u,w).

Hence, to find x and y, we need to find two nodes x and y such that 
there exists a pair lx from Lx and ly from Ly for which lx + ly = K. 
This can be done by DFS from u through every edge (u,w) for all adjacent nodes w 
with careful book keeping using an array A[0,.....,K] of size K + 1.
The running time for this step is O(N).

2 Finding the right node

Our goal is to find node u such that after deleting u, 
each resulting trees are all sufficiently small. 
In this case, we shall find node u such that each remaining tree has at most N=2 nodes.

We shall refer to node u as the central node. It is not clear if such a node exists. 
So let's argue about that first.
Pick an arbitrary node v as a candidate. 
Denote by T* = T\{v} the forest obtained by deleting v from T. 

For each node w adjacent to v, denote by Tw the tree containing w in T*. 
If every tree Tw from T* has at most N=2 nodes, 
we are done and v is the required central node.

Otherwise there exists one tree Tw that contains more than N=2 nodes. 
(Note that there can be only one tree violating our criteria.) 
In this case, we pick w as our new candidate and repeat the process.

This process will eventually stop at some candidate node and that's the required central node. 
To see this, note that after leaving v, we shall never go back to pick v again; 

since there are N nodes, the process can repeat at most N times.
After knowing that the central node exists, there are many ways to find it. 
We can follow the process directly as in the argument. 
But this is too slow to be useful.

The following are two procedures that find the central node in O(N logN) time and O(N) time.

2.1 Bottom-up approach

We can find node u in a bottom-up fashion. 
We shall keep a priority queue Q of all \processed" subtrees using their sizes as weights.
We maintain, for each node, its state which can either be new or processed; 
initially all nodes are new. 
Every node also has a weight. 
Initially every node has weight of 1.
We start with all leaf nodes in Q. 
Note that each node in Q is every node which has all but one of its adjacent nodes processed. 

For each node v from Q, we denote by p(v) the unique neighbors of v which is new.
While there are nodes in Q, we extract node v with the smallest weight. 
We update v state to processed and increase the weight of p(v) by v's weight. 
If all but one neighbor of p(v) are processed, we insert v into Q.
Using this procedure, the last node inserted to Q is the desired central node.

2.2 DFS with bookkeeping

With DFS and a good bookkeeping, we can find the central node in O(N).
We pick an arbitrary node r to start a DFS. 
With this procedure, we can consider T as rooted at r and the parent-child relationship 
between adjacent pairs of nodes are clearly defined.
While performing DFS, we compute, for each node v, the number of its descendants D(v).

With this information, we can figure out if a candidate u is the central node. 
For each node w adjacent to u, if w is one of u's children, 
the size of the resulting tree containing w after deleting u is 
    
	    D(w) + 1. 

If w is u's parent, the size of the resulting tree containing w after deleting u is
     
	   n - 1 - sum(v from Ch(u), D(v) + 1)

where Ch(u) are a set of children of u. 
If the size of each resulting tree is at most N/2, u is the desired central node. 
The time needed to check u is proportional to u's degree. 
Therefore, we can check all nodes in time O(N)

SUBTASKS 1 AND 2

In the first two subtasks N is less than 100 and 1000, respectively. 
So a brute force approach is sufficient here.
The idea is to perform a single depth first search starting on each node 
and find which of the found paths that sums to K has the fewest edges.

That said, this is a simple algorithm that can be easily implemented in O(N^2) 
(since the number of paths in a tree is of this order). 
The first subtask was made to accommodate solutions 
that were poorly implemented and ended up being O(N^3), 
for example, if one was to recompute the distances 
between each pair of nodes instead of calculating them incrementally.

SUBTASK 3

The third subtask was still a relatively standard one. 
For this subtask N can be as large as 200 000, but K is limited by 100. 
This means we can play around with K as long as we keep our solution linear on N. 
The idea is to apply a rather well known algorithm, dynamic programming on trees.

We start by rooting the tree in some node u, for example, on node 0. 
If you are unfamiliar with this concept, rooting here means setting u as the “start” of the tree 
(from where the rest of the nodes will branch out) 
and thus we calculate the children of each node and the parent of each node (where the root has no parent). 

Now we create a dynamic programming array of N by K dimensions. 
The idea is that for each node v, we have: 

   DP[v][l] = min(DP[c][l – cost(v, c)] + 1) for all c, 
   
where c is a child of v and cost(v, c) is the cost of the edge from v to c. 
In other words, the path with the minimum number of edges that sum l and ends at node v 
is the minimum of the paths that sum to l – cost(v, c) over all children c of v plus one (the own edge {v, c}). 

We can easily fill this matrix in O(N * K) 
if we iterate the tree in a depth first search fashion starting from the root 
and for each node filling in all values from K to 0. 
Also, don’t forget the base case, that for all nodes v, 
DP[v][0] = 0 (and DP[v][x] = ∞ for all x different from 0, we will fill these with the above recurrence).

After we fill the dynamic programming matrix, 
our answer is the minimum of DP[v][K] for all nodes v. 
Thus our approach here is O(N * K) and is enough for subtask 3 
(notice, however, that this approach doesn’t necessarily work for subtask 2, 
 since K isn’t bounded by 100, 
 so to get full marks on the first three subtasks you’d have to implement both approaches).
 
SUBTASK 4

The final subtask requires some more creativity. 
Now K is no longer bounded by 100, so our solution will have to be linear on both N and K. 
We could try to approach this in a bunch of different ways, 
but one way that works well is called centroid decomposition. 
Instead of simply describing the technique and then trying to apply it, 
we’ll progressively get there more organically throughout the rest of this analysis.

An initial important observation is that our first solution tries a lot of paths multiple times. 
I say so because when starting a depth first search on a certain node 
we are basically “shifting” our previous search one node further. 
To use this in our favor, we’re going to first select a node from the tree 
and consider all of the paths pass through that node. 
To calculate these it is not enough to do a simple depth first search like 
we did for subtasks 1 and 2, but rather something slightly more ingenious.

Let’s fix a node v and calculate all paths that cross v. 
If we do a depth first search starting on each neighbor of v (careful to not go back through v), 
we can store what’s the minimum number of edges necessary to make a path of length l, for all l between 1 and K. 

Now, if we keep an array A[] of K elements (initially all at infinity, but the element 0, that will be at 0), 
which we’ll fill with the minimum number of edges to get a path of sum l as A[l]. 
When we do a new depth first search starting on a new neighbor of v, 
if the current length of the search is l and we got here using p edges, 
then there is a path that sums K with p + A[K – l] edges. 

We have to be careful to not consider overlapping paths, 
so in practice we do two depth first searches from each neighbor of v, 
one to calculate the minimums and one to fill the array A[].

If we do the above calculation, we can divide the graph into separate components 
by removing the node v from the graph (along with all adjacent edges) 
and recursively calling our method to calculate the answer on each component. 

We can do so because all paths between components have been considered in the calculation of the above paragraph 
(since they have to use node v). 
So essentially we have found a way of dividing our original problem into smaller problems, 
in a sort of divide and conquer way. 

But now the question arises: 
which node should we select as v in order to have the best efficiency possible? 
Note that the method of the above paragraph is of complexity O(T), 
where T is the number of nodes in the component we are applying the method (initially this is N), 
so the better we divide the graph into smaller graphs, the better the complexity. 

Here is where the idea of centroid decomposition enters. 
The centroid of a tree is the node whose maximum subtree is minimum, or in other words, 
that when removed partitions the graph in components whose maximum size is the minimum possible 

(note that the centroid is not the same as the center, 
where the eccentricity is minimized instead of the maximum sized subtree). 

It is sort of the center of mass of the tree 
and can be generalized to weighted graphs, 
but here we are interested in the unweighted decomposition, 
to be able to take advantage of the following result. 

The following image shows an example of such 
(notice that 6 would be the center of the tree, but 4 is the centroid).

Why the centroid? Because there is a known result that says that if the original tree has N nodes, 
the centroid partitions the tree into subtrees each of size at most N/2. 
It is not very difficult to prove, if a certain node v partitions the tree into a subtree of size larger than N/2, 
then choose the node from that subtree that neighbors v as the new possible centroid. 
If we repeat this, eventually there is no subtree is larger than N/2.
This helps us because if always select the centroid as the vertex from the previous paragraph, 
we always divide the tree into at most two trees of size N/2
(or a lot of trees of sizes smaller than N/2 that sum to N). 
Thus we can apply the divide and conquer idea and get a complexity similar to the merge sort O(NlogN) complexity, 
for the same reasons.

To find the centroid there are a number of different algorithms. 
The one I feel is the simplest, 
is to first root the tree in any node. 
Afterwards, pre-compute the size the subtree of each node 
(the subtree that contains all its descendants) 
using a standard depth first search. 
Finally, iterate through all the nodes and select the one where: 

max(T – size[v], size[c1], size[c2], …) is the least possible, 

where T is the number of nodes of the tree 
and c1, c2, … are the children of v. 
This corresponds to the size of all the subtrees starting on v.

So to summarize everything, the algorithm first computes the centroid of the tree in O(N), 
then calculates all paths that cross the centroid in O(N) 
and finally divides the tree intro subtrees by the centroid 
and recursively computes the same (unless the tree has size 1, which is the base case). 
The overall complexity of this algorithm is O(NlogN), which is enough for the full 100 points.

I implemented a solution in C++ using the method described for subtask 4. 
I didn’t implement the methods of the previous subtasks since they are less interesting, but they are simpler. 
You can find the code here. The code isn’t very complicated, 
it is actually pretty much divided into the tasks described in the explanation of the algorithm. 
However, there are a few details I think I should highlight.

First of all, in order to simplify and shorten my implementation, 
I didn’t actually root explicitly any tree 
(meaning I didn’t calculate children or parents, like in my previous code for Ideal City 2012). 
What I actually did was keep an adjacency list and also a processed nodes list. 
Now, whenever I did a depth first search, 
I kept the previous node and used it as the parent of the next node in order to prevent infinite recursion. 
The processed nodes list was used in order to “close” the recursed subtree, 
that is, whenever I did any recursion after calculating a centroid, 
I marked the centroid as processed and made sure I never got 
there again in any of the next calculations, since this node is no longer required. 
That way, I didn’t have to do expensive operations or pass the graph as an argument to the function.

Another thing that I did and didn’t mention on the explanation above, 
was the way I dealt with the array with K elements 
that stored the minimum number of edges needed to make a path of size l for all l from 1 to K. 
After each recursion step, we need to clean up this array, 
but we can’t simply memset it or iterate through it, 
since that would be O(K) and would ruin our lovely complexity. 

What I did was use a standard (though clever) technique 
that considers an auxiliary array initially filled with 0. 
Then, we use an extra variable, initially at 0. 
Whenever we need to reset the array, 
we increment the extra variable 
and only if A_auxiliary[value] == extra variable 
do we consider the actual value on A[value], 
if not, we ignore the current value on A[]. 
Also, whenever we update the value of A[value], 
we place the value of A_auxiliary[value] = extra variable.

Let's understand what select_split_node does: 



0 
  \
   
7 - 5 ---- 4 --- 6 --- 3 --- 2 --- 8 

   /
1

                    0(8)
					
			        |

                    5(7)
              /	    |   \			
           7(0)    1(0) 4(4)    
		                   \
                            6(3) - 3(2) - 2(1) - 8(0)

    select_split_node(0):						
       current = 0
       split_node = -1
       current_max = 8 + 3 = 11
       total = 8 + 1 = 10
       node_max = 0
         |
		 V
    split_node(5):
     node_max = 10 - (7 + 1) = 2
     /
   V                         
split_node(7)                     
node_max = 10-(1) = 9
split_node = 7
current_max = 9
  
void dfs_calculate_path(int current, int parent, int current_cost, int current_length)

the goal of this method is to calculate munimum number of edges necessary to make a path of length l from 1 to K.
minimum_paths[current_cost] - minmum number of edges necessary to make a path of length current_cost

In the scope of this procedure we need to be able to clean up previously filled array.
So without this optimization, dfs would look like this: 

void dfs_calculate_path(int current, int parent, int current_cost, int current_length)
{
   if (current_cost > K) return;

   if (current_length < minimum_paths[current_cost])
   {
       minimum_paths[current_cost] = current_length;
   }

   for (int i = 0; i < neighbours[split_node].size(); i++)
   {
     ...
   }
|

book-keeping is indicator of the first dfs run. book-keeping = 1
before running dfs first time we have achievable[u] = 0 - all vertexes' run is set to 0.

we run dfs the first time. When we enter a vertex u the first time, 
if (achievable[current_cost] < book_keeping) - we entered current_cost the frst time 
minimum_paths[current_cost] may contain previous value - we override it. 

suppose achievable[current_cost] == book_keeping - we are entering current_cost the second time.

Then we run dfs to calculate minimum path to get cost of K.
We start at every child of a centroid c 

     c  --
   /  \	   \
  v1  v2 ...vn

current_lenth = 1. 
current_cost = length(c,v1)

if we bump into curren_cost == K, we need to update answer with current_length

  




	  



