
In the countryside, you can find a long straight road known as the Rice Way. 
Along this road there are R rice fields. 
Each field is located at an integer coordinate between 1 and L, inclusive.

The rice fields will be presented in non-decreasing order of their coordinates. 
Formally, for 0 ≤ i < R, rice field i is at coordinate X[i]. 
You may assume that 1 ≤ X[0] ≤ ... ≤ X[R-1] ≤ L.

Please note that multiple rice fields may share the same coordinate.
We plan to construct a single rice hub as a common place to store as much of the harvest as possible. 
As with the rice fields, the hub has to be at an integer coordinate between 1 and L, inclusive.

The rice hub can be at any location, 
including one that already contains one or more rice fields.

Each rice field produces exactly 1 truckload of rice every harvest season. 
To transport the rice to the hub, the city has to hire a truck driver. 
The driver charges 1 Baht to transport a truckload of rice per unit of distance towards the hub. 

In other words, the cost of transporting rice from a given field 
to the rice hub is numerically 
equal to the difference between their coordinates.

Unfortunately, our budget for this season is tight: 
we may only spend at most B Baht on transportation. 
Your task is to help us strategically place the hub 
to gather as much rice as possible.

Your task

Write a procedure besthub(R,L,X,B) that takes the following parameters:
  • R – the number of rice fields. The fields are numbered 0 through R-1.
  • L – the maximum coordinate.
  • X – a one-dimensional array of integers sorted from smallest to largest.
    For each 0 ≤ i < R, field i is located at X[i].
  • B – the budget.
  
Your procedure must find an optimal location of the hub 
and return the maximum number of truckloads of rice 
that can be transported to the hub within the budget.

Note that the total cost of transporting the rice can be very large. 
The budget is given as a 64-bit integer, 
and we recommend that you use 64-bit integers in your computation. 
In C/C++, use the type long long; 
in Pascal, use the type Int64.

The key insight to solving this problem is the observation that for any K rice fields 
located at r0 <= r1 <= r2 <= .... <= rK-1, 
the transportation cost from all these K fields is minimized 
by placing the rice hub at a median. 

For example, when K = 1, the hub should be at r0, 
and when K = 2, placing it between r0 and r1 is optimal. 
In this problem, we will place the rice hub at r[K/2] for simplicity. 
Following this observation, we denote a solution by a sequence 
     S from (r0,....,rR-1)
and let |S| denote the length of S, which is the solution's value 
(the number of rice fields whose rice will be transported to the hub). 
The cost of S is 

     cost(S) = sum(ri from S, |rj - h(S)|) 

     where h(S) is the [|S|/2]-th element of S.
	 
1 An O(R3) solution

Armed with this, we can solve the task by a guess-and-verify algorithm. 
We try all possible lengths of S (ranging between 1 and R). 
Next observe that in any optimal solution S*, 
the rice fields involved must be contiguous; 
that is, S* is necessarily (rs; rs+1; : : : ; rt) for some 0 <= s <= t <= R - 1. 

Therefore, there are R - K + 1 solutions of length K. 
For each choice of S, 
we compute h(S) and the transportation cost in O(|S|) time 
and check if it is within the budget B.
This leads to an O(R3) algorithm, which suffices to solve subtask 2.

2 An O(R2) solution

To improve it to O(R2), we will speed up the computation of cost(S). 
Notice that we are only dealing with consecutive rice fields. 
Thus, for each S, the cost cost(S) can be computed in O(1) after pre-computing certain prefix sums. 
Specifically, let T[i] be the sum of all coordinates to the left of rice field i, i.e., 

     T[0] = 0 and T[i] = sum(j=0,i-1 X[j]). 
	 
Then, if S = (rs; : : : ; rt), 

cost(S) is given by 
   (p - s)*rp - (T[p] - T[s]) + (T[t+1] - T[p+1]) - (t - p)*rp, where p = [(s + t)/2] 
   
This O(R2) algorithm suffices to solve subtask 3.

3 An O(RlogR) solution

Applying a binary search to find the right length in place of a linear search 
improves the running time to O(RlogR) and suffices to solve all subtasks.

An O(R) solution

We replace binary search with a variant of linear search carefully designed 
to take advantage of the feedback obtained each time we examine a combination of rice fields. 
In particular, imagine adding in the rice fields one by one. 

In iteration i, we add ri and find 

(1) Si*, the best solution that uses only (a subsequence of) the first i rice fields 
    (i.e., Si* is (r0,...., ri-1), and 
	
(2) Si, the best solution that uses only (a subsequence of) the first i rice fields 
    and contains ri - 1. 
	
This can be computed inductively as follows. 
As a base case, when i = 0, both Si and Si* 
are just (r0) and cost 0, 
which is within the budget B >= 0. 

For the inductive case, assume that Si and Si* are known. 
Now consider that Si+1 is Si appended with ri, 
    Si+1 = Si + ri, 

denoted by Si*ri, if the cost cost(Si*ri) is at most B, 
or otherwise it is the longest preffix of Si*ri that costs at most B. 

Futhermore, Si+1* is the better of Si* and Si+1. 

To implement this, we represent each Si by its starting point s and ending point t; 
thus, each iteration involves incrementing t and possibly s, 
but s is always at most t. 
Since cost((rs, ...., rt) takes O(1) to compute, 
the running time of this algorithm is O(R) and suffices to solve all subtasks.











 