
Day 1 Task 2: Hotter Colder

Jack and Jill play a game called Hotter, Colder. 
Jill has a number between 1 and N, and Jack makes repeated attempts to guess it.

Each of Jack's guesses is a number between 1 and N. 
In response to each guess, Jill answers hotter, colder or same. 
For Jack's first guess, Jill answers same. 
For the remaining guesses Jill answers:
  • hotter if this guess is closer to Jill's number than his previous guess
  • colder if this guess is farther from Jill's number than his previous guess
  • same if this guess is neither closer to 
    nor further from Jill's number than his previous guess.
	
You are to implement a procedure HC(N) that plays Jack's role. 
This implementation may repeatedly call Guess(G), 
with G a number between 1 and N. 
Guess(G) will return 1 to indicate hotter, 
-1 to indicate colder 
or 0 to indicate same. 
HC(N) must return Jill's number.

Example

As example, assume N=5, and Jill has chosen the number 2. 
When procedure HC makes the following sequence of calls to Guess, 
the results in the second column will be returned.
Call Returned value Explanation

  Guess(5) 0 Same (first call)
  Guess(3) 1 Hotter
  Guess(4) -1 Colder
  Guess(1) 1 Hotter
  Guess(3) 0 Same
  
At this point Jack knows the answer, and HC should return 2. 
It has taken Jack 5 guesses to determine Jill's number. 
You can do better.
 
Subtask 1 [25 points]
HC(N) must call Guess(G) at most 500 times. 
There will be at most 125 250 calls to HC(N), 
with N between 1 and 500.

Subtask 2 [25 points]
HC(N) must call Guess(G) at most 18 times. 
There will be at most 125 250 calls to HC(N) with N between 1 and 500.

Subtask 3 [25 points]
HC(N) must call Guess(G) at most 16 times. 
There will be at most 125 250 calls to HC(N) with N between 1 and 500.

Subtask 4 [up to 25 points]
Let W be the largest integer, such that 2W ≤ 3N. 
For this subtask your solution will score:
  • 0 points, if HC(N) calls Guess(G) 2W times or more,
  • 25α points, where α is the largest real number, such that 0<α<1 and HC(N) calls Guess(G) 
    at most 2W-αW times,
  • 25 points, if HC(N) calls Guess(G) at most W times.
   There will be at most 1 000 000 calls to HC(N) with N between 1 and 500 000 000.
   Be sure to initialize any variables used by HC every time it is called.
   Implementation Details
   
• Implementation folder: /home/ioi2010-contestant/hottercolder/
• To be implemented by
contestant: hottercolder.c or hottercolder.cpp or hottercolder.pas
• Contestant interface: hottercolder.h or hottercolder.pas
• Grader interface: grader.h or graderlib.pas
• Sample grader: grader.c or grader.cpp or grader.pas and graderlib.pas
• Sample grader input: grader.in.1 grader.in.2.
Note: The input file contains several lines, each containing N and Jill's number.
• Expected output for sample grader input: the grader will create
files grader.out.1 grader.out.2 etc.
o If the implementation correctly implements Subtask 1, one line of output
will contain OK 1
o If the implementation correctly implements Subtask 2, one line of output
will contain OK 2
o If the implementation correctly implements Subtask 3, one line of output
will contain OK 3
o If the implementation correctly implements Subtask 4, one line of output
will contain OK 4 alpha α
• Compile and run (command line): runc grader.c or runc grader.cpp or runc
grader.pas
• Compile and run (gedit plugin): Control-R, while editing any implementation
file.
• Submit (command line): submit grader.c or submit grader.cpp or submit
grader.pas
• Submit (gedit plugin): Control-J, while editing any implementation or grader
file.

Solution

This problem is an interesting variant of the well-known guessing game Higher-Lower, 
also featured in the demonstration task Guess.
Higher-Lower is efficiently solved by the, also well-known, Binary Search algorithm. 
Binary Search maintains an interval of still possible numbers (candidates). 
Initially, this interval includes all numbers in the range. 
By comparing to the middle candidate, 
the interval can be halved by a single guess. 
Thus, the secret number can be determined in a logarithmic (to base 2) number of guesses. 
Or, to put it differently, 
if the range of allowed numbers is doubled, 
than the secret number can be determined with one additional guess.

Subtask 1
Doing a Linear Search, that is, successively calling Guess(i) for i from 1 to N, 
yields a solution requiring N calls to Guess, in the worst case. 
This solves Subtask 1. See below for a Pascal program.

Analysis
To get a better understanding of the Hotter-Colder problem, 
it helps to formalize the rules of this game.
Let J be Jill's number, and let P be the most recent guess, that is, Guess(P) was called last. 
In that situation, 

J - is Jill's number.
P - is the most recent guess. 

Guess(G) will return

     HOTTER if abs(G - J) < abs(P - J)
     COLDER if abs(G - J) > abs(P - J)
     SAME   if abs(G - J) = abs(P - J)
	 
Or in a single formula: 
     sign(abs(P - J) - abs(G - J)). 

Letting M = (P + G)/2, 
this can be rephrased as
   
   if P <= G then
       HOTTER if J > M
       COLDER if J < M
       SAME if J = M
   else
       HOTTER if J < M
       COLDER if J > M
       SAME if J = M
	   
Or in a single formula: 

   sign(G - P) * sign(J - M).
   
Thus, we see that each Guess(G) effectively provides a high-low comparison to the midpoint M. 
In fact, sign(G - P) * Guess(G) = sign(J - M) offers a genuine high-low comparison.
Unfortunately, due to the range restriction on G, 
we cannot make the midpoint M go wherever we want.
So, a straightforward Binary Search is not going to work.

const Colder = -1;
      Same = 0;
      Hotter = +1;
type
      TResult = Colder .. Hotter;
	  
function HC(N: Longint): Longint;
{ returns secret number of Jill }
var
   r: TResult; { result of Guess }
   G: Longint; { argument for Guess }
begin
   if N = 1 then begin
      HC := N; 
	  Exit
   end { if }
{ N >= 2 }
; G := 1
; r := Guess(G) { ignored }
; repeat
{ numbers >= G are remaining candidates; G < N }
G := G + 1
; r := Guess(G) { compares to G - 0.5; r <> Same }
until (r = Colder) or (G = N)
; case r of
Colder: HC := G - 1;
Hotter: HC := G;
end { case r }
end;


Subtask 2

Ignoring the results of all odd calls to Guess, 
we can extract one bit of information out 
of every successive pair of odd-numbered 
and next even-numbered call to Guess. 
This yields a solution that calls Guess at most W times, 
where W is the largest integer such that 2W/2≤N. 
That is, it makes at most log2 N2 (rounded up) calls to Guess. 
For N=500 (almost 29), 
this boils down to making at most 18 calls.


Subtask 3
By exploiting the fact that we actually 
do a high/low/equal comparison instead of a pure high/low (binary) comparison,
we can gain almost one extra bit of information (taken over all guesses). 
Explanation: 
  a complete binary tree with 2k leaves has 2k-1 internal nodes.
  So, the same number of high/low/equal guesses can reach 
  twice the number of nodes minus one 
  (compared to using just binary high/low guesses).
A Pascal program is given below.

Subtask 4
The preceding approaches obviously throw away (ignore) valuable information. 
However, using this information requires careful tuning of the guesses. 
It helps to do some small cases by hand.

   • N=3 can obviously be done in 2 guesses, 
         by straddling the middle, for example, 
		 Guess(1) followed by Guess(3) 
		 does a high/low/equal comparison to 2.
     1 2 3
     Guess(1) = same
     Guess(2) = hotter  need one more guess

     Guess(3) = same 
     Guess(2) = hotter

     Suppose number is 2, then 
     Guess(1) = same
     Guess(3) = same

     Suppose number is 3, then 
     Guess(1) = same
     Guess(3) = hotter  => 3  	 
		 
   • N=5 can be done in 3, but this already needs some care, 
        because it does not work to set this up 
		so that the first two guesses compare to the middle number 3. 
		
 	 When, after Guess(1) Guess(5), or Guess(2) Guess(4), 
	 the result of the second guess is colder, 
	 you won't be able to solve the remaining problem in a single guess.
	
	 1 2 3 4 5 
	
	 Suppose number is 3 

     Guess(1) = same
     Guess(5) = same it can be 2,3 or 4
       Guess(3) = hotter
       Guess(2) = colder	   
	
     You need to start with Guess(1) Guess(3) (or symmetrically Guess(5) Guess(3)). 
	 
	 If the result of the second guess is same, Jill's number is 2; 
	 if the result is colder, only candidate 1 remains and this must be Jill's number. 
	 If the result is hotter, candidates 3, 4, and 5 remain. 
	     Since 3 was the most recent guess, doing Guess(5) will compare to 4, and we are done.
		 
     In general, it turns out to be possible to determine Jill's number in no more than log2 3*N = log2 3 + log2 N calls of Guess.
	 
     We explain one such algorithm. 
	 Because of the nature of the guess (being a comparison), 
	 at any moment you have an interval of remaining candidate numbers. 
	 You can distinghuish two cases for the location of this interval with respect to the initial interval:
       1. either this interval of candidates contains 1 or N (is "against a wall");
       2. or it contains neither 1 nor N (is "in the middle").

     Furthermore, you know what the previous guess was, say P.
     If the interval of candidates is "in the middle", 
	 then you are home free (provided you are a bit careful), 
	 because now each guess can be made to reduce the interval sufficiently. 
	 In K more guesses, you can find Jill's number among 2K+1-1 candidates. [Details suppressed (for the time being)]
If the interval of candidates is "against a wall", then you can always arrange it so that the interval is 1 through P (or symmetrically on the other side). With two extra steps you can grow a solution that solves for P in K more guesses to one that solves for P+2K+2 in K+2 more guesses.




9ee009a0c1578bb240b7548e0bad3e1237d460f7













