
The Xedef Courier Company provides air package delivery among several cities. 
Some of these cities are Xedef hubs 
where special processing facilities are established. 

Each of Xedef's aircraft shuttles back and forth between one pair of cities, 
carrying packages in either direction as required.

To be shipped from one city to another, a package must be transported by a sequence of hops, 
where each hop carries the package between a pair of cities served by one of the aircraft. 

Furthermore, the sequence must include at least one of Xedef's hubs.
To facilitate routing, Xedef wishes to encode the length 
of the shortest sequence of hops from every city to every hub on the shipping label of every package. 
(The length of the shortest sequence leading from a hub to itself is zero.) 
Obviously, a compact representation of this information is required.

You are to implement two procedures, encode(N,H,P,A,B) and decode(N,H). 
  N is the number of cities and 
  H is the number of hubs. 
  
Assume that the cities are numbered from 0 to N-1, 
and that the hubs are the cities with numbers between 0 and H-1.

Further assume that N ≤ 1000 and H ≤ 36. 

P is the number of pairs of cities connected by aircraft. 

All (unordered) pairs of cities will be distinct. 
A and B are arrays of size P, such that the first pair of connected cities is (A[0],B[0]), 
the second pair is (A[1],B[1]), and so on.

encode must compute a sequence of bits from which decode 
can determine the number of hops from every city to every hub. 
encode will transmit the sequence of bits to the grading server by a sequence of calls to encode_bit(b) 
where b is either 0 or 1. 

decode will receive the sequence of bits from the grading server by making calls to decode_bit. 
The i-th call to decode_bit will return the value of b from the i-th call to encode_bit(b). 
Note that you must ensure that the number of times decode calls decode_bit 
will always be at most equal to the number of times encodepreviously called encode_bit(b).

After decoding the numbers of hops, decode must call hops(h,c,d) 
for every hub h and every city c (including every hub, that is, also for c=h), 
giving the minimum number d of hops necessary to ship a package between h and c. 
That is, there must be N*H calls to hops(h,c,d). 
The order does not matter.

You are guaranteed that it is always possible 
to ship a package between every hub and every city.

Note: 
encode and decode must communicate only through the specified interface.
Shared variables, file access and network access are prohibited. 
In C or C++, you may declare persistent variables to be static 
to retain information for encode or decode, 
while preventing them from being shared. 
In Pascal, you may declare persistent variables in the implementation part of your solution files.

Example
As an example, consider the diagram on the right. 
It shows five cities (N=5) connected by seven aircraft (P=7). 
Cities 0, 1 and 2 are hubs (H=3). 

One hop is needed to ship a package between hub 0 and city 3, 
whereas 2 hops are needed to ship a package between hub 2 and city 3. 
The data for this example are in grader.in.1.

Solution:

This task also is innovative for the IOI. 
In general, for most IOI tasks efficiency matters. 
However, in this case it is not execution time or memory usage 
but rather communication efficiency: 
how to represent some complex data in as few bits as possible, without losing information.

This difference in focus makes the tasks possibly somewhat harder to understand. 
Furthermore, it is technically more complicated, 
because the contestant has to program two independent procedures that are inverses to each other. 
The communication format is not prescribed; 
all that matters is that the decoder programmed by the contestant 
can decode the data from the encoder that is also programmed by the contestant. 
The grading server then connects these two procedures to verify 
that the decoder can indeed "understand" what the encouder produced. Two things are important. 
First, find a way to encode adjacency information about Xedef's package transportation network. 
Second, to transmit that information with communication efficiency.

Subtask 1: 
  You can send the entire adjacency matrix "as is"; 
  this information is naturally expressed in terms of bits, 
  other encodings are imaginable as well. 
  All that the encoder and decoder need to agree upon is the order of the bits. 
  Since there are 1000 cities, this requires no more than 1000*1000=1 000 000 bits. 
  Other approaches using more bits also work in this subtask.
  
Subtask 2: 
  You can send the entire table with all hop counts directly. 
  Since there are no more than 1000 cities, 
  the maximum hop count is less than 1000, 
  and thus can be encoded in 10 bits. 
  The size of the table is at most 1000*36=36 . 
  Hence, not more than 360 000 bits are needed.
  
Subtask 3: 
  One needs a new idea to improve the communication efficiency further. 
  The crux is to come up with the idea of considering a spanning tree; 
  any spanning tree will do. 
  The distance from v1 to v2 is one of
     distance from parent(v1) to v2
     1 + distance of parent(v1) to v2
     -1 + distance of parent(v1) to v2
	 
  Then all one has to do is encode these possibilities with 2 bits each.

Subtask 4: 
  Using two bits to record a one-of-three choice is excessive. 
  It is possible to map 3 ternary decisions (27 choices) to 5 bits (32 possibilities). 
  This improves the communication further.  
  
Suppose we have called bfs starting on vertex 0 and have built a spanning tree. 
par[0][0],par[0][1],par[0][2],...,par[0][i],....,par[0][n-1]

     0
	/ \  \ 
  1   2   3 
 /   /  \ 
4    5  6

For this graph we will have a par array like this:
par[0]  0 | 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | 6
-----------------------------------
        0   0   0   0   1   2   2 
   
pr[0][i] is number in range [0, N] N <= 1000  2^10 = 1024. 10 bits is enough
to encode any number. So we encode bits from larger to smaller, from 10 to 0

for (int i = 1; i < H; ++i) {
        for (int j = 1; j < N; ++j) {
            int x = dist[i][j] - dist[i][pr[0][j]] + 1;
        }
    }

Let's understand what this code means. 
i != 0. i = 0 is source. 
let's take i to a part of hops. 

   0
   |  \
   |   - - p(V)- \
   V              V
   i -----------> j 

dist[i][j] - is distance from i to j
pr[0][j] - is parent of V 
dist[i][pr[0][j]] - is distance from i to parent of V.  

x = distance(i,j) - distance(i, parent(j)) + 1

Possible values for distance(i,j) - distance(i, parent(j)) are: -1,0,1
Possible values for x are: 0,1,2

x = 3u * x + (unsigned int)i, 

Suppose values are: 2,1,0,1,2
x = 2 3*2+1 = 3*10

Suppose we use unsinged int 64 bits. we can use 60 bits to store 20 values.

3*(3*2+2)+2

After we have flushed everything, 










