
Definitions:
  A (2 ≤ A ≤ 30) - the length of the side of the chip. 
  N (1 ≤ N ≤ 50), the number of power junctions
  N lines contains two integers X and Y (1 ≤ X, Y ≤ A-1) 
  - the coordinates of a power junction. 
  No two power junctions will occupy the same position.
  
Find a way to connect the junctions to the sides, 
so that the total length of wire used is the smallest possible.  

Solution.

1. Sort by x coordinate.
2. Suppose we have connected K junctions and used minimum length and try to add K + 1 th wire.
Possible options: 
 1. Connect to the right. We can always do this. All previous junctions have x coordinate less than current.
 2. Connecting to the left.
    It may intesect with previous junctions connected up or down.
    To check if it does not intersect with junctions connected down we need to consider only junctions 
    with higher y coordinate. The same for junctions connected up.
 3. Connecting up or down. 
    To connect up it may intersect with previous junctions connected right with higher y coordinate.
    The same for connecting down.
    
So patameters of the system:
K - number of junctions connected.
lowest y coordinate of previous K junctions connected up.
highest y coordinate of previous K junctions connected down.
lowest y coordinate of previous K junctions connected right.
higest y coordinate of previous K junctions connected right.

We can calculate all possible states and transitions among them.
It will be a graph. 

move left
if we move left, we do not influence future choices. All y restrictions remain the same.

|---------
|   |
|   |     .
|   .
|         .
|   .
|   |
|   |
------------ 

move up down

|
|         
|    .--------- loy
|
|    .--------- hiy
|        . y
|
------------

move left with multiple points on y 
if multiple point lie on the same line the same y
only left most can be moved left.

|
|
|  .        
|     .    .  .  .  .  
|   .       
|
|_ _ _ _ _ _ _ 


The first line of input contains a single integer A (2 ≤ A ≤ 30), the length of the side of the chip
The second line contains an integer N (1 ≤ N ≤ 50), the number of power junctions.
Each of the following N lines contains two integers X and Y (1 ≤ X, Y ≤ A-1), 
the coordinates of a power junction. 
No two power junctions will occupy the same position.
You may assume that there exists a solution for each input file.

1. Brute force solution. 
First we sort points by x coordinates. 
Consider first point. There are 4 possibilities up=0,down=1,left=2,right=3. 
if line crosses with next point or any point, we can't use it. 
draw line lets say to the right and keep this information.
Take next point and also draw all possible lines whick do not cross previous points. 
What information we need to keep in order to make decision if line is allowed. 
First option is to pass array of previous lines and check. O(i) time to check which is big. 

Is it possible to pass less information. 
Consider first point and draw line to left
when we draw left line, we do not affect next point.
If we draw right line. then next points which lie above this line 
can't draw line towards bottom. 

ly - is coordinate for this line. so if y >= ly - no down, 
     but they can write up. Those points for which y <= ly
	 they can't move up. 
	 So, we need to keep min(ly) and max(ly)
	 
Suppose, at first point we draw line in north direction, y2.
then point that y >= y2, can't move left. points y < y2 we can
we need to keep min(y2) 

y3 - is y coordinate of a point from which we draw line down. 
we need to keep max(y3)

Solution

Because the task is output-only, a well-implemented backtracking solution will be fast enough 
to run locally and solve all test cases. 
The task was originally batch, with a time limit of 1 second. 
The remainder of this text shows how to efficiently solve the problem. 

First, sort the power junctions in increasing order by the x-coordinate. 
We will connect junctions to sides in that order. 
Now, suppose we've already connected the first K junctions 
and consider our options for connecting the junction K+1: 

 - Connecting to the right: 
   Since all K junctions already connected have x-coordinate less 
   than or equal to this junction, we can always do this. 
   
 - Connecting to the left: 
   Some of the previous junctions that are connected up or down might get in our way. 
   Of all junctions connected up we only have to check the one with the lowest y-coordinate, 
   and of all junctions connected down we only have to check the one with the highest y-coordinate. 
   No other junction is relevant in determining if we can connect junction K+1 to the left. 
   
 - Connecting up or down: 
   Some previous junctions that are connected right might get in our way. 
   Of all such junctions we have to check only the one with the highest y-coordinate 
   if we want to connect junction K+1 up, and the one with the lowest y-coordinate 
   if we are connecting junction K+1 down.
   
No other junction is relevant in determining if we can connect this junction up or down.

These five parameters 
(K, 
lowest y-coordinate of all junctions connected up, 
highest y-coordinate of all junctions connected down, 
lowest y-coordinate containing of all junctions connected to the right, 
highest y-coordinate of all junctions connected to the right) 

define all possible states we can encounter in the process of connecting junctions.   

These states, along with valid transitions between them, form a directed acyclic graph. 
We can calculate the optimal configuration using dynamic programming. 
The time complexity of this algorithm is O(N·A4).

Solution

Another thing that we need to think about - is how to understand how to check if there is previous points 
with the same x or y coordinate. The simpliest way is to loop over all previous points. 
     minx[i] - is minimal point x for previous points with p[i].y  
|
|
|     .
|   .   .  
| .       .
|_ _ _ _ _ _ 







	 



    


   
   
   
   


