
There are two coal mines, each employing a group of miners. 
Mining coal is hard work, so miners need food to keep at it. 
Every time a shipment of food arrives at their mine, the miners produce some amount of coal. 
There are three types of food shipments: meat shipments, fish shipments and bread shipments.

Miners like variety in their diet and they will be more productive if their food supply is kept varied. 
More precisely, every time a new shipment arrives to their mine, 
they will consider the new shipment and the previous two shipments (or fewer if there haven't been that many) 
and then:
  • If all shipments were of the same type, they will produce one unit of coal.
  • If there were two different types of food among the shipments, they will produce two units of coal.
  • If there were three different types of food, they will produce three units of coal.
  
We know in advance the types of food shipments and the order in which they will be sent. 
It is possible to influence the amount of coal that is produced by determining which shipment should go to which mine.
Shipments cannot be divided; 
each shipment must be sent to one mine or the other in its entirety.
The two mines don't necessarily have to receive the same number of shipments 
(in fact, it is permitted to send all shipments to one mine). 

TASK
Your program will be given the types of food shipments, in the order in which they are to be sent. 
Write a program that finds the largest total amount of coal that can be produced (in both mines) 
by deciding which shipments should be sent to mine 1 and which shipments should be sent to mine 2.

INPUT
The first line of input contains an integer N (1 ≤ N ≤ 100 000), the number of food shipments.
The second line contains a string consisting of N characters, 
the types of shipments in the order in which they are to be distributed. 
Each character will be one of the uppercase letters 'M' (for meat), 'F' (for fish) or 'B' (forbread).

OUTPUT
Output a single integer, the largest total amount of coal that can be produced. 

Example 1:
n = 6 input = MBMFFB  output = 12

i  Mine 1    Mine 2
0   M (1)
1   B (2)
2           M (1)
3           F (2)
4   F (3)	   
5           B (3)
		   
In the left sample, by distributing the shipments in this order: mine 1, mine 1, mine 2, mine 2, mine 1, mine 2,
the shipments will result in 1, 2, 1, 2, 3 and 3 units of coal produced in that order, for a total of 12 units. 
There are other ways to achieve this largest amount.


Solution:

The problem is solved using dynamic programming. 
Let M(n, state1, state2) be the largest amount of coal 
that can be produced after n−1 food shipments have already been distributed; 

state1 describes which shipments have gone to mine 1 so far, 
and state2 describes which shipments have gone to mine 1 so far

Furthermore, let value(a, b) denote the amount of coal produced when food of type b arrives to a mine in state a. 
The following recursive formula holds:

n - current type of food processed. We have processed 1,2,..n types of food.
state1 - list of shipments that went to Mine1
state2 - list of shipments that went to Mine2

n = 0, state1 = [M], state2 = [O]
n = 1, state1 = [M,B], state2 = [O]
n = 2, state1 = [M,B], state2 = [O,M]
n = 3, state1 = []

M(n, state1, state2) = max 
{
   M(n+1, newstate1, state2) + value(state1, type of shipment n),
   M(n+1, state1, newstate2) + value(state2, type of shipment n)
) 

Start:  M(0, [], []) = max  M(1, [M], []) + 1,
                            M(1, [], [M]) + 1
                 M(2, [MB], []) + 2
M(1, [M], []) -  M(2, [M], [B]) + 1

Try example:

n=6 S = M B M F F B. 
    s = 2 3 2 1 1 3

now=0, prev=1, k = 5
(a,b,c) = (0,0,0) ... (3,3,3). = (1,2,3) = (F,M,B)

left  = dp[1][F][b][c] + value(B, F, a) 
right = dp[1][b][F][a] + 

       mine left      mine right 
n - 4     c
n - 3 	  b 
n - 2     F  
n - 1      
 
M(state1, state2)  
   a  b  c 

Another solution:   
  
dp[now][a][b][c][d] = 
  max
  (
     dp[1 - now][arr[k]][a][c][d] + cnt(arr[k], a, b), 
     dp[1 - now][a][b][arr[k]][c] + cnt(arr[k], c, d)
  );

  
  
  left        right
   b           d
   a           c
   arr[k]    arr[k]

n=6 S = M B M F F B
   
k = n - 1 = 5, arr[k] = 'B'

cnt('B', a, b) = cnt('B','M','F') or cnt('B','F','M') = 3      
      
dp[0][a][b][c][d] = 

[0](0,0,0,0) = 0
[0](M,F,M,F) = 3
[0](B,F,B,F) = 2
....

Another solution.
Start with solve(0, 0, 0)  solve (m1, m2, done)

 M B M F F B

int solve(int m1,int m2,int i)
   if(i == n) return 0;
   
   if(dp[m1][m2][i] != -1)      //if we have already met this state, we return. 
       return dp[m1][m2][i];

   int leftScore = solve( ( (m1<<2) | arr[i]) & 15, m2, done + 1)  // solve(0011, m2, 1)
                   + getScore(m1,arr[done])
   
// {{'M',1},{'B',2},{'F',3}};   1 = 00001,  2 = 0000010, 3 = 0000011, 15 = 100000000 - 1 = 111111111
 
m1 = 0.  arr[0] = M = 1 => m1 = 0000011      

getScore(m1,arr[done])
m1 = 00000 11 11
            a  b
			
a,b,c from [1,2,3]

14 = 001110			


map<char,int> m = {{'M',1},{'B',2},{'F',3}};


int getScore(int i,int c){
	int a = (i >> 2);
	int b = (i&3);
	return __builtin_popcount(((1 << a)|(1 << b)|(1 << c))&14);
}

c is the next type of food. It can be 1,2,3
i maintains previous 2 supplies of food:    000000aabb
r = 14 = 1110        
(111 >> 2) & 1 + 


//m1 - previous 2 food supplies for the first group of miners
//m2 - previous 2 food supplies for the second group of miners
int solve(int m1,int m2,int i)
{
      m1 -> (m1 << 2 | i) & 15 + getScore(m1, i)
	  or 
	  m2 -> (m2 << 2 | i) & 15 + getScope(m2, i)
	  
Use memoization and dp. Need to decide how big can be m1,m2
max m1 = 1110 = 8 + 4 + 2 = 14

