
Determine the area of the room into which the robot was teleported.
The area of the room is the number of empty squares reachable from 
the robot's initial position, including the starting square.

The area is 1000 and not more than 5000 move commands are allowed.

Solution. It can be done with some king of dfs with visited bag. 
Robot can move if if there is  not wall and the cell is not visited.

There is one trick that when we enter a dead end, 
we need to return back to to the previous node where we have other options. 




 