Mirko and Slavko are training hard for the annual tandem cycling marathon taking place in Croatia. 
They need to choose a route to train on.
There are N cities and M roads in their country. 
Every road connects two cities and can be traversed in both directions.
Exactly N−1 of those roads are paved, while the rest of the roads are unpaved trails
The network of roads was designed so that each pair of cities is connected by a path consisting of paved roads.
In other words, the N cities and the N−1 paved roads form a tree structure. 
Additionally, each city is an endpoint for at most 10 roads total. 
A training route starts in some city, follows some roads and ends in the same city it started in.
Mirko and Slavko like to see new places, so they made a rule never to go through the same city nor travel the same road twice. 
The training route may start in any city and does not need to visit every city. 
Riding in the back seat is easier, since the rider is shielded from the wind by the rider in the front. 
Because of this, Mirko and Slavko change seats in every city. 
To ensure that they get the same amount of training, they must choose a route with an even number of roads. 

Mirko and Slavko's competitors decided to block some of the unpaved roads, 
making it impossible for them to find a training route satisfying the above requirements. 

For each unpaved road there is a cost (a positive integer) associated with blocking the road. 
It is impossible to block paved roads. 


TASK

Write a program that, given the description of the network of cities and roads, 
finds the smallest total cost needed to block the roads so that no training route exists satisfying the above requirements. 


INPUT

The first line of input contains two integers N and M (2 ≤ N ≤ 1 000, N−1 ≤ M ≤ 5 000), 
the number of cities and the total number of roads.

Each of the following M lines contains three integers A, B and C (1 ≤ A ≤ N, 1 ≤ B ≤ N, 0 ≤ C ≤ 10 000), describing one road. 
The numbers A and B are different and they represent the cities directly connected by the road. 

If C=0, the road is paved; otherwise, the road is unpaved and C represents the cost of blocking it.
Each city is an endpoint for at most 10 roads. 
There will never be more than one road directly connecting a single pair of cities.

Solution.

Detecting an odd cycle in a graph is a well-known problem. 
We claim that a digraph G has an odd-length directed cycle if and only if 
one (or more) of its strong components is nonbipartite (when treated as an undirected graph).

- If the digraph G has an odd-length directed cycle, 
  then this cycle will be entirely contained in one of the strong components. 
  
  A directed graph is strongly connected if there is a path between all pairs of vertices. 
  A strongly connected component (SCC) of a directed graph is a maximal strongly connected subgraph.
  
  When the strong component is treated as an undirected graph, 
  the odd-length directed cycle becomes an odd-length cycle. 
  Recall that an undirected graph is bipartite if and only if it has no odd-length cycle.
  
  Theorem (Konig). A graph is bipartite if and only if it has no odd cycle.
   => If G is bipartite with bipartition X, Y of the vertices, 
      then any cycle C has vertices that must alternately be in X and Y. 
	  Thus, since a cycle is closed, C must have an even number of vertices and hence is an even cycle.

   A graph does not contain an odd cycle if and only if it is bipartite. 
   On the other hand, the problem of detecting an even cycle in a graph is not widely known. 	  
  
  We are given a graph consisting of N vertices and M edges. 
  Exactly N−1 edges are marked as tree edges and they form a tree. 
  An edge that is not a tree edge will be called a non-tree edge. 
  Every non-tree edge e has a weight w(e) associated with it.  
  
  The task asks us to find a minimum-weighted set of non-tree edges whose removal results in a graph 
  that does not contain a cycle of even length. 
  We will call such a cycle an even cycle. 
  
  Reasoning backwards, starting from a graph containing tree edges only, 
  we have to find a maximum-weighted set of non-tree edges 
  that can be added to the graph without forming any even cycles. 
  
  In order to describe the model solution, 
  we first need to make a few observations about the structure of the graph we are working with. 
  
  Even and odd edges.
  
  Consider a non-tree edge e={A, B}. 
  We define the tree path of the edge e to be the unique path from A to B consisting of tree edges only.
  If the length of the tree path is even, we say that e is an even edge; 
  otherwise we say that e is an odd edge. 
  We will use TP(e) to denote the tree path of an edge e. 
  
  Obviously, any odd edge present in the graph together with its tree path forms an even cycle. 
  Therefore, we can never include an odd edge in our graph and we can completely ignore them. 
  
  Relation between two even edges.
  
  Individual even edges may exist in the graph. 
  However, if we include several even edges, an even cycle might be formed. 
  More precisely, if e1 and e2 are even edges such that TP(e1) and TP(e2) share a common tree edge, 
  then adding both e1 and e2 to the graph necessarily creates an even cycle.
             
    / * \ / * \
  *      *     *
  |      |     |
  |      |     |
  * --   * --  *
  
  In order to sketch the proof of this claim, 
  consider the two odd cycles created by e1 and e2 together with their respective tree paths. 
  If we remove all common tree edges from those cycles we get two paths P1 and P2. 
  The parity of P1 is equal to the parity of the P2 since we removed the same number of edges 
  from the two initial odd cycles. 
  As P1 and P2 also have the same endpoints, we can merge them into one big even cycle.
  
  Tree edges contained in odd cycles.
  
  As a direct consequence of the previous claim, 
  we can conclude that every tree edge may be contained in at most one odd cycle.

  Conversely, if we add only even edges to the tree 
  in such a way that every tree edge is contained in at most one odd cycle, 
  then we couldn’t have formed any even cycles. 
  
  We briefly sketch the proof of this claim here. 
  
  If an even cycle existed, it would have to contain one or more non-tree edges. 
  Informally, if it contains exactly one non-tree edge 
  we have a contradiction with the assumption that only even edges are added; 
  
  if it contains two or more non-tree edges then we will arrive at a contradiction
  with the second assumption. 
  
  
  Model solution
  
  Now, we can use our observations to develop a dynamic programming solution for the problem. 
  A state is a subtree of the given tree.
  
  For each state we calculate the weight of the maximum-weighted set of even edges 
  that can be added to the subtree while maintaining the property 
  that each tree edge is contained in at most one odd cycle. 
  The solution for the task is the weight associated with the state representing the initial tree. 
  
  To obtain a recursive relation, we consider all even edges with tree paths passing through the root of the tree.
  We can choose to do one of the following: 
  
    (1) We do not add any even edge whose tree path passes through the root of the tree. 
	    In this case, we can delete the root and proceed to calculate the optimal solution 
		for each of the subtrees obtained after deleting the root node. 
		
	(2) We choose an even edge e whose tree path passes through the root of the tree and add it to the tree.
        Next, we delete all tree edges along TP(e) (since, now, they are contained in one odd cycle), 
		and, finally, we proceed to calculate the optimal solution for each of the subtrees 
		obtained after deleting the tree path. 
		Add w(e) to the total sum. 
		
Because of the way the trees are decomposed, all subtrees that appear as subproblems can be represented 
with an integer and a bit mask. 
The integer represents the index of the subtree's root node, 
while the bit mask represents which of the root node's children are removed from the subtree. 		

   parent a
 /  |   |  \   
v1  v2  v3  v4

parent[v1] = (a, 00010)
parent[v2] = (a, 00100)
parent[v3] = (a, 01000)
parent[v4] = (a, 10000)

degree(parent) = 4


Lowest common ancestor for edge (u,v)
1. E(u,v) belongs to tree:
 while( depth[u] > depth[v] ) u = parent[u].first;
              root
      ......
     v depth = 4
    /
   /
  /
 u depth = 5
 
 u = v
 
 while( depth[v] > depth[u] ) v = parent[v].first;
 
 u == v => E[i].LCA = u;
 
 Lowest common ancestor on (u,v) which is an edge on the tree we return v
 
 
      u1 (4) 
    /   \
   u1(5) v2 (5)
  /       \
 u(6)      v3  (6)
            \
             v4 (7)
 
 while( depth[u] > depth[v] ) u = parent[u].first;
 while( depth[v] > depth[u] ) v = parent[v].first;
 
		
    
     *6 0
    / \ 
   /   \
 4*2 1  \
 /  \    * 1 
*3   *  / \
0     05*   *
	   
	   


