Problem

You have a special set of N six-sided dice, each of which has six different positive integers on its faces. Different dice may have different numberings.

You want to arrange some or all of the dice in a row such that the faces on top form a straight (that is, they show consecutive integers). For each die, you can choose which face is on top.

How long is the longest straight that can be formed in this way?

Input

The first line of the input gives the number of test cases, T. T test cases follow. Each test case begins with one line with N, the number of dice. Then, N more lines follow; each of them has six positive integers Dij. The j-th number on the i-th of these lines gives the number on the j-th face of the i-th die.

Output

For each test case, output one line containing Case #x: y, where x is the test case number (starting from 1) and y is the length of the longest straight that can be formed.

Limits

1 ≤ T ≤ 100.
1 ≤ Dij ≤ 106 for all i, j.
Small dataset

1 ≤ N ≤ 100.
Large dataset

1 ≤ N ≤ 50000.
The sum of N across all test cases ≤ 200000.

Sample


Input 
 	
Output 
 
3
4
4 8 15 16 23 42
8 6 7 5 30 9
1 2 3 4 55 6
2 10 18 36 54 86
2
1 2 3 4 5 6
60 50 40 30 20 10
3
1 2 3 4 5 6
1 2 3 4 5 6
1 4 2 6 5 3

Case #1: 4
Case #2: 1
Case #3: 3

In sample case #1, a straight of length 4 can be formed by taking the 2 from the fourth die, the 3 from the third die, the 4 from the first die, and the 5 from the second die.

In sample case #2, there is no way to form a straight larger than the trivial straight of length 1.

In sample case #3, you can take a 1 from one die, a 2 from another, and a 3 from the remaining unused die. Notice that this case demonstrates that there can be multiple dice with the same set of values on their faces.


Dice Straight: Analysis

Small dataset

One brute force approach to the problem is to examine all possible subsets of dice in all possible orders, and look for the longest straights. Since there may be as many as 100 dice in the Small dataset, we need a better strategy.

First, let's create the set of all integers that are present on at least one die, and sort that set in increasing order. Then we will create an interval that initially contains only the first number in that sorted list. We will expand and contract that interval according to the following strategy. As an invariant, the entire interval will always be a straight (a sequence of one or more consecutive numbers).

Check whether it is possible to build the straight using the available dice (we'll get to how to do that in a moment).

If it is possible: Expand the interval to include the next value to the right.
If that value is not one greater than the previous rightmost value, then we no longer have a straight; contract the interval to remove all but that new rightmost value. Then we have a straight again.
If it is not possible: Contract the interval by removing its leftmost value.
To check whether a possible straight can be built, we can find a bipartite matching from the required integers to the dice by using a flow algorithm such as Ford-Fulkerson. Since each die has exactly 6 faces, the number of edges in the graph is 6N, and the running time of one iteration of Ford-Fulkerson is O(N2). We run it up to O(N) times as we adjust our interval, so this solution is O(N3). Other polynomial solutions are possible.

Large dataset

To make the flow algorithm fast enough to solve the Large dataset, we need the additional insight that we do not need to start the algorithm from scratch every time. When expanding by adding a new number, we need to add all O(N) edges into that number (either by adding them outright or changing their flow capacity from 0 to 1), and then find and add a single augmenting path to the existing flow, which also takes O(N) time (since the total number of edges in the graph is at most 6N). So an expansion takes O(N) time overall. When contracting, we need to remove edges and flow from the path associated with that number; this takes O(N) time. Since we have O(N) expansions and contractions, they take O(N2) time in total. Adding this to the O(N2) from completely solving the flow problem the first time, the overall complexity is still O(N2). This is fast enough for the Large dataset.





