
We build a social network from people numbered 0, ... n - 1.
Some pairs of people in the network will be friends. 
If person x becomes a friend of person y, 
then person y also becomes a friend of person x.

The people are added to the network in n stages, 
which are also numbered from 0 to n - 1.

Person i is added in stage i. 
In stage 0, person 0 is added as the only person of the network.
In each of the next n - 1 stages, 
a person is added to the network by a host, 
who may be any person already in the network.

At stage i (0 < i < n ), the host for that stage 
can add the incoming person into the network by one of the following three protocols:

 - IAmYourFriend makes person a friend of the host only.
 - MyFriendsAreYourFriends makes person a friend of each person, 
   who is a friend of the host at this moment. 
   Note that this protocol does not make person a friend of the host.
 - WeAreYourFriends makes person a friend of the host, 
   and also a friend of each person, who is a friend of the host at this moment.
   
After we build the network we would like to pick a sample for a survey, 
that is, choose a group of people from the network. 
Since friends usually have similar interests, 
the sample should not include any pair of people who are friends with each other. 
Each person has a survey confidence, expressed as a positive integer, 
and we would like to find a sample with the maximum total confidence.

Given the description of each stage and the confidence value of each person, 
find a sample with the maximum total confidence. 
You only need to implement the function findSample

findSample(n, confidence, host, protocol)
  n: the number of people.
  confidence: array of length n; confidence[i] gives the confidence value of person.
  host: array of length n, host[i] gives the host of stage i.
  protocol: 
    array of length n, protocol[i] gives the protocol code used in stage i (0 < i < n): 
       0 for IAmYourFriend, 
	   1 for MyFriendsAreYourFriends, and 
	   2 for WeAreYourFriends.  
  
  Since there is no host in stage 0, host[0] and protocol[0] are undefined 
  and should not be accessed by your program.
  
  The function should return the maximum possible total confidence of a sample.
  

  


