
 Jian-Jia is planning his next holiday in Taiwan. 
 During his holiday, Jian-Jia moves from city to city 
 and visits attractions in the cities.
 
 There are n cities in Taiwan, all located along a single highway. 
 The cities are numbered consecutively from 0 to n - 1. 
 For city i, where 0 < i < n - 1, the adjacent cities are i - 1 and i + 1. 
 The only city adjacent to city 0 is city 1, and the only city adjacent to city n - 1 is city n - 2.
 
 Each city contains some number of attractions. 
 Jian-Jia has days of holiday and plans to visit as many attractions as possible. 
 Jian-Jia has already selected a city in which to start his holiday. 
 In each day of his holiday Jian-Jia can either move to an adjacent city, 
 or else visit all the attractions of the city he is staying, but not both. 
 Jian-Jia will never visit the attractions in the same city twice even if he stays in the city multiple times. 
 Please help Jian-Jia plan his holiday so that he visits as many different attractions as possible.
 
 Example
 
 Suppose Jian-Jia has 7 days of holiday, 
 there are 5 cities (listed in the table below), 
 and he starts from city 2. 
 
 On the first day Jian-Jia visits the 20 attractions in city 2. 
 On the second day Jian-Jia moves from city 2 to city 3, 
 and on the third day visits the 30 attractions in city 3. 
 Jian-Jia then spends the next three days moving from city 3 to city 0, 
 and visits the 10 attractions in city 0 on the seventh day.
 
 The total number of attractions Jian-Jia visits is 20 + 30 + 10 = 60, 
 which is the maximum number of attractions Jian-Jia 
 can visit in 7 days when he starts from city 2.
 
 Task
 
 Please implement a function findMaxAttraction 
 that computes the maximum number of attractions Jian-Jia can visit.
 
   findMaxAttraction(n, start, d, attraction)
      n:           the number of cities.
      start:       the index of the starting city.
      d:           the number of days.
      attraction:  array of length n, attraction[i] is the number of attractions in city, for 0 <= i <= n - 1.
	  
 The function should return the maximum number of attractions Jian-Jia can visit. 
 
 Solution for the Holiday Task
 
 For ease of description, we will first describe a simple O(n log n)-time solution 
 for the special case of the starting city start being the one with the index 0 for any fixed d. 
 
 That is, start = 0 and d is a given number. 
 Then we extend this solution to build a table of solutions in O(n log2 n) time for all possible values of d. 
 Finally we describe how to extend this solution to solve the general case 
 of an arbitrary start with the same asymptotic time complexity.
 
 Simple solution for start = 0 and a given fixed d
 Without lost of generality, assume we start at the leftmost city and move right. 
 It is easy to see that we only need to move right and there is no need to move left at any time. 
 
 Assume in an optimal solution, city right is the rightmost city we will travel to. 
 Then we can visit up to d - right cities among the cities with labels 0; 1; ... ; right. 
 
 In order for the solution to be optimal, we want to visit the d - right cities 
 with the largest number of attractions. 
 That is, if we sort the cities with labels 0; 1; ... ; right 
 using the number of attractions as their keys, 
 then we want to know the sum of the d - right largest number of attractions.
 
 Segment tree 
 
 We use a data structure called segment tree for this part 
 though it may appear this data structure 
 is not needed to solve this very special case. 
 
 However, it will be clear why this data structure 
 is used in the solution to the intermediate case. 
 The segment tree data structure has been used in previous IOI contests including 2001 Baltic OI. 
 The segment tree has many variations. 
 We will use the following one. 
 A segment tree is a rooted complete binary tree with leaves carrying a flag indicating 
 whether this leaf is active or not, and a value. 
 For each internal node v, it keeps the sum of the values of all of the active leaves in the subtree rooted at v.
 Each internal node also maintains the number of currently active leaves in the subtree rooted at v.
 
 Assume the segment tree has n leaves. 
 Note that we need to add dummy leaves of n is not a power of 2. 
 Further assume the values of the leaves, active or in-active, are in non-increasing order from left to right. 
 To maintain this data structure, it takes O(log n) time to turn on or off any leaf. 
 It also takes O(log n) time to find out the sum of the values in the largest x active leaves for any given x. 
 A side note is when x is more than the number of active leaves, 
 then we simply output the sum of the values of all active leaves.
 
 Algorithm Initially, we sort the cities using their number of attractions as keys in non-increasing order. 
 Then in this order, we place them as leaves in the segment tree from left to right with all leaves in-active. 
 The number of attractions are now the values of the leaves. 
 The initialization phase takes O(n log n) time. 
 
 We turn on a leaf when it is being move to during the search of our solution. 
 We iterate on all possible values of the rightmost city we can move to. 
 Hence it takes a total of O(n log n) time to find a solution for this easy special case.
 
 Intermediate solution for start = 0 and all possible values of d
 
 Now we describe how to solve this intermediate case. 
 In our previous so-lution, we can find the maximum number of attractions 
 we can visit given any d. 
 Let f(d) be the label of the city we move to in d days so that the maximum number of attractions can be found. 
 
 Note that f(d) may not be unique. 
 In the case of multiple ones, we pick the one with the small-est label. 
 We now want to build a table for all possible values of d. 
 
 The idea is to use recursive divide-and-conquer approach. 
 Let M be the max-imum number of d. 
 For ease of description, let M be a power of 2. 
 To compute the solutions for f(1); f(2); ... ; f(M) we first find f(M/2) 
 using our previous algorithm by iterating through all cities from 0 to n 
 and then recursively compute f(1); f(2); ... ; f(M/2 - 1) in one branch 
 by considering only cities from 0 to f(M/2), and f(M/2+1), f(M/2+2), ... , f(M) 
 in the other branch by considering only cities from f(M/2) to n. 
 In the branch of computing f(1), f(2), ... , f(M/2 - 1), 
 we first compute f(M/4) among cities 0 to f(M/2). 
 In general, the total amount of time spent in each level of recursive calls takes a total of O(n log n). 
 There are a total of O(log n) levels. 
 Hence the overall time complexity is O(n log2 n).
 
 In solving this intermediate case, it is now clear how the segment tree is useful. 
 First we only need to do the initialization once. 
 Secondly, we can easily turn on or off a leaf to accommodate the fact 
 that the cities that we pay attention to in each level of recursion. 
 For example, only half of the leaves are active during the second level of recursion.
 
 




 
 

   






ATLAS-7641
ATLAS-7523
ATLAS-7205
 
 

 rename v1-ian-order-updates  to  v1-ian-deal-order-updates
 rename v1-ian-order-updates to v2-ian-order-updates and use for only single order.
 add OrderContext to existing FixRouter model.
 add OrderContext.EventType: OrderDelivered/Cancelled/Allcoated 
 
 
 
 
  
