
 Taiwan has a big railway line connecting the western and eastern shores of the island. 
 The line consists of m blocks. 
 The consecutive blocks are numbered 0,..., m-1 starting from the western end. 
 Each block has a one-way west-bound track on the north, 
 a one-way east-bound track on the south, and optionally a train station between them.
 
 There are three types of blocks. 
 A type C block has a train station that you must enter from the northern track 
 and exit to the southern track, 
 a type D block has a train station that you must enter from the southern track 
 and exit to the northern track, 
 and a type empty block has no train station. 
 
 For example, in the following figure block 0 is type empty, 
 block 1 is type C, 
 and block 5 is type D. 
 Blocks connect to each other horizontally. 
 Tracks of adjacent blocks are joined by connectors, 
 shown as shaded rectangles in the following figure.
 
 The railsystem has n stations numbered from 0 to n - 1. 
 We assume that we can go from any station to any other station by following the track. 
 For example we can go from station 0 to station 2 by starting from block 2, 
 then passing through blocks 3 and 4 by the southern track, 
 and then passing through station 1, then passing through block 4 by the northern track, 
 and finally reaching station 2 at block 3
 
 Since there are multiple possible routes, 
 the distance from one station to another is defined as the minimum number of connectors the route passes through. 
 For example the shortest route from station 0 to 2 
 is through blocks 2-3-4-5-4-3 and passes through 5 connectors, so the distance is 5
 
 A computer system manages the railsystem. 
 Unfortunately after a power outage the computer no longer knows 
 where the stations are and what types of blocks they are in. 
 The only clue the computer has is the block number of station 0, 
 which is always in a type C block. 
 
 Fortunately the computer can query the distance from any station to any other station. 
 For example, the computer can query 'what is the distance from station 0 to station 2?' 
 and it will receive 5.
 
 Task
 
 You need to implement a function findLocation that determines 
 for each station the block number and block type.
 
 findLocation(n, first, location, stype)
   n: the number of stations.
   first: the block number of station 0.
   location: array of size n; 
      you should place the block number of station into location[i].
   stype: 
      array of size n; you should place the block type of station i into stype[i]: 
	  1 for type C and 2 for type D.
	  
 You can call a function getDistance to help you find the locations and types of stations.
 
 getDistance(i, j) returns the distance from station i to station j. 
 getDistance(i, i) will return 0. 
 getDistance(i, j) will return -1 if i or j is outside the range
 
Solution. 

 Way : Ad Hoc
 Query complexity: 3(N-1)
 Time complexity : O(N log N)
 
 ** This problem can be solved by the following steps :
 
 First, we know that station 0 is C type, and its location. 
 We can query all the other stations’ distances from station 0, 
 we call this : dis[0][i]
 
 Second, we sort all the dis[0][i], and obviously, 
 the station x with the shortest distance dis[0][x] 
 must be the first D type location after station 0. 
 
 Third, we process each station one by one 
 according to their shortest distance with station 0 
 (that is, the order obtained in second step). 
 
 For each station processed, we determine its type and location immediately as follows:
 
 3.1 First, we maintain the information (location,id) 
     of the leftmost C type and the rightmost D type as the algorithm proceeds. 
	 
 3.2 To process the current station k, we use two queries, 
     query(k, leftmost C type)  as dis[k][L], 
	 query(k, rightmost D type) as dis[k][R]. 
	
	 And we also have dis[0][k]. 
	 
	 By some observations, we know that either dis[k][L] or dis[k][R] is achieved with a ‘direct’ route 
	 (without moving forth and back).
	 
	 For example, we have only 4 cases to consider :

     a. dis[k][L] is a direct route
        ( ) )
        L k R
	
	 b. dis[k][L] is a direct route
        (   )    )
        L   R    k
		
	 c. dis[k][R] is a direct route
        (   (   )
        k   L   R

     d. dis[k][R] is a direct route
        (   (   )
        L   k   R

 By careful analysis (some if/else conditions), we can get the answer. 
 Sometimes, we may need extra information to resolve the four cases, 
 where we can check with dis[0][k].
 
 Take case (a) for example 		
	
 a. dis[k][L] is a direct route
    (    )     )
    L    k     R
	 
 the location of k might be L + dis[k][L], 
 Then use this location, we need to check if dis[k][R] is reasonable or not.
 
 a.1
     (   (   )    )
     L   p   k    R
	 
 There might be some p(type C) between L and k, 
 So the dis[k][R] is dis[p][R] + dis[p][k], 
 we need to check whether p exists or not. 
 
 If p doesn’t exist, then case (a) might be wrong, 
 then try cases (b),(c), and (d) until we find the answer.
 
 







   



 



  
