
Jian-Jia is building a wall by stacking bricks of the same size together. 
This wall consists of n columns of bricks, 
which are numbered 0 to n-1 from left to right. 
The columns may have different heights. 
The height of a column is the number of bricks in it.

Jian-Jia builds the wall as follows. 
Initially there are no bricks in any column. 
Then, Jian-Jia goes through k phases of adding or removing bricks. 
The building process completes when all k phases are finished. 
In each phase Jian-Jia is given a range of consecutive brick columns and a height h, 
and he does the following procedure:

In an adding phase, Jian-Jia adds bricks to those columns in the given range 
that have less than h bricks, 
so that they have exactly h bricks. 
He does nothing on the columns having h or more bricks.

In a removing phase, Jian-Jia removes bricks from those columns in the given range 
that have more than h bricks, 
so that they have exactly h bricks. 
He does nothing on the columns having h bricks or less.

Your task is to determine the finalshape of the wall.

Example

We assume that there are 10 brick columns and 6 wall building phases. 
All ranges in the following table are inclusive. 
Diagrams of the wall after each phase are shown below.

phase  type        range        height 

0      add    columns 1 to 8    4

 |
4| ----------------
3| |              |
2| |              |
1|_|_ _ _ _ _ _ _ |_ _ _ _ _
 0  1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9

Since all columns are initially empty, after phase 0 each of the columns 1 to 8 will have 4 bricks
Columns 0 and 9 remain empty.

1   remove    columns 4 to 9     1

In phase 1, the bricks are removed from columns 4 to 8 
until each of them has 1 brick, and column 9 remains empty.

 |
4| ------
3| |    |         
2| |    |__________   
1|_|_ _ _ _ _ _ _ |_ _ _ _ _
 0  1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9

Phase 2 makes no change since columns 3 to 6 do not have more than 5 bricks.

3 add columns 0 to 5 3

 |
4| ------
3|-|    |---         
2|         |_______   
1|_ _ _ _ _ _ _ _ |_ _ _ _ _
 0  1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9


Task
Given the description of the phases, 
please calculate the number of bricks in each column after all phases are finished. 
You need to implement the function buildWall.

buildWall(n, k, op, left, right, height, finalHeight)

  n: the number of columns of the wall.
  k: the number of phases.
  
  op: array of length k; 
      op[i] is the type of phase i: 1 for an adding phase and 2 for a removing phase, 
	  for 0<=i<=k-1.
	  
  left and right: 
      arrays of length k; the range of columns in phase i starts with column left[i] and ends with column right[i]	  
	  (including both endpoints left[i] and right[i]) for 0<=i<=k-1.
	  You will always have left[i] <= right[i].
	  
  height: array of length k; height[i] is the height parameter of phase i, for 0<=i<=k-1.
  
  finalHeight: 
      array of length n; you should return your results by placing 
	  the final number of bricks in column into finalHeight[i], for 0<=i<=k-1.
	  
Solition. 

We’ll simplify the notion of the problem as follow:

Initially we have an array of length n where the value at each index is 0, 
and we are to process k queries in order. 
We will denote the value at index x as A[x].
There are two kinds of operations:

Minimize(l,r,t): 
   For all indices x between [l, r], the value become min(A[x], t)
   
Maximize(l,r,t): 
   For all indices x between [l, r], the value become max(A[x], t)
   
The minimize operation corresponds to the original remove operation;
the maximize operation corresponds to the original add operation.

Trivial solution - O(nk)

A trivial solution to this problem is to use an array of length n to maintain 
the current height at each index, 
and for each query perform a linear update in O(n).
This solution runs in O(nk).

Segment Tree - O((n + k) lg n)

One crucial observation is that for a specific position, 
any cascade of operations applied on it could be simplified 
to one minimize operation and one maximize operation.

For example, applying 
(here we omit the paramter l, r as we consider operations solely on a specific index):

minimize(9), minimize(8), minimize(7) => minimize(7), maximize(−inf)
minimize(3), maximize(7), minimize(4) => minimize(4), maximize(4)

In general, this observation could be verified by simple induction.
With this observation we could now improve the update time. 
We instead use a segment tree to maintain the final operations applied on an interval.

class Node 
{
   Node *left, *right;  // children nodes
   int from, to;        // corresponding interval [from, to]
   int opmin, opmax;    // min/max operation applied on interval
};

An minimize operation would look something like:

void Node::minimize(int l, int r, int t) {
  if( from==l && to==r ) { // applied on full segment
    opmin = min(opmin, t);
    opmax = min(opmin, opmax);
  } else {
    // pass down previously applied operation
    left->minimize( left->from, left->to, opmin );
    left->maximize( left->from, left->to, opmax );
    right->minimize( right->from, right->to, opmin );
    right->maximize( right->from, right->to, opmax );
	
    // recursively apply current minimize operation
    if ( r<=left->to ) left->minimize( l, r, t );
    else if( l>=right->from ) right->minimize( l, r, t );
    else {
       left->minimize( l, left->to, t );
       right->minimize( right->from, r, t );
    }
  }
}

A single round of minimize operation runs in O(lg n), 
likewise for maximize operations. 
Note that in the snippet above, 
we use the well-known lazy-update technique to maintain the operations applied at one position. 
i.e. the message is passed down to children nodes only when necessary, 
that is, when new operations are imposed on only part of the segment, 
so previous operations should be passed down first.









   







