PROBLEM

The secret messages between Santa Claus and his little helpers 
are usually encoded in the 25-language. 
The 25-alphabet is the same as the Latin alphabet with one exception
- the letter 'Z' is absent, 
i.e. the 25-alphabet contains 25 Latin letters 
from 'A' through 'Y' in the same order as the Latin alphabet. 

Each word in the 25-language consists of exactly 25 different letters. 
A word can be written in a 5x5 table filling the rows first;
for example, the word ADJPTBEKQUCGLRVFINSWHMOXY will be written as
follows:
  A D J P T
  B E K Q U
  C G L R V
  F I N S W
  H M O X Y
  
A valid word in the 25-language has its letters in each row 
as well as in each column written in ascending order. 
Thus, the word ADJPTBEKQUCGLRVFINSWHMOXY is a valid word, 
in contrast to the word ADJPTBEGQUCKLRVFINSWHMOXY 
(the ascending order is violated in the second column, and in the third column, too).

Santa Claus has a lexicon. 
His lexicon is the list of all valid 25-language words in ascending order 
(lexicographically) along with their ordinal numbers starting from 1.

For example, in the lexicon ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXY 
is the word number 1 and    ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSUTVWXY is the word number 2. 

In word number 2, U and T are interchanged from their order in word number 1.
Unfortunately, this lexicon is huge. 
Write a program that determines the ordinal number of an arbitrary given word, 
and also the word corresponding to a given ordinal number. 
There are no more than 2^31 words in the lexicon.  

INPUT

The input file is named twofive.in and consists of two lines. 
The first line contains a string with one character: a 'W' or an 'N'. 
If the first line contains a 'W', then the second line contains a valid 25-language word, 
that is, a string with 25 characters.
If the first line contains an 'N', then the second line contains the ordinal number of an
existing 25-language word.

OUTPUT

The output file is named twofive.out and consists of one line. 
If the second line of the input file contains a 25-language word, 
then the line of the output file contains the ordinal number of that word. 
If the second line of the input file contains a number,
then the line of the output file contains the 25-language word with that ordinal number.

Solution

The solution is based on a function numconts, 
which, given an arbitrary set of letters having fixed positions, 
will compute the number of possible ways to legally place all the remaining letters. 
The function will try to position the letters in the edges of a shape of a Young tableau 
(the same shape that is used for the problem depot).

If all the letters have been placed, then there is exactly one way to continue: do nothing. 
So, for a full state, numconts initializes the table snum[states-1] to 1. 
Then, it will start to fill the table using the function calcstate.

Calcstate returns the number of possible ways to choose positions for the remaining letters, 
given the shape of the positioning of the earlier letters and the fixed set. 
It tries to place the next letter to all valid positions, 
and sums the values obtained by calling itself recursively for the new shapes. 
The intermediate results are stored in the table snum so that they don't have to be recalculated.

Solving the actual problem using the numconts function is fairly easy. 
Let's say we have to calculate the number of a word. 
We keep up a value corresponding to the number of the alphabetically first word 
we would be able to generate with our current the fixed set. 

We will fix all the letters one by one, starting from the most significant one. 
A letter is fixed by first setting it to A, 
and then incrementing it until the desired one is reached. 
Each time it is increased, numconts is used to calculate the number of words 
that were skipped in the operation, and the current value is updated accordingly.
When all the letters have been fixed, we have the correct solution.

Doing things the other way around works almost the same way. 
We again fix the letters one by one, 
this time incrementing them until the current value exceeds the desired value. 
When this happends, we take a step back, and move to the next letter. 
When we're finished, the two values have become equal, and we have the correct word.

W = ABCDE FGHIJ KLMNO PQRSU TVWXY

 ABCDE
 FGHIJ
 KLMNO
 PQRSU
 TVWXY
 
function count will accept a valid string S and will find number of ways to legaly place 

from the start we have: (i,j)=(1,1) k = 0

 

 








 