
 Byteman owns the most beautiful garden in Bytetown. 
 He planted n roses in his garden. 
 Summer has come and the flowers have grown big and beautiful. 
 Byteman has realized that he is not able to take care of all the roses on his own. 
 He has decided to employ two gardeners to help him. 
 He wants to select two rectangular areas, 
 so that each of the gardeners will take care of the roses inside one area. 
 The areas should be disjoint and each should contain exactly k roses.
 
 Byteman wants to make a fence surrounding the rectangular areas, but he is short of money, 
 so he wants to use as little fence as possible. 
 Your task is to help Byteman select the two rectangular areas.
 
 The garden forms a rectangle l meters long and w meters wide. 
 It is divided into l · w squares of size 1 meter × 1 meter each. 
 
 We fix a coordinate system with axes parallel to the sides of the garden. 
 All squares have integer coordinates (x,y) satisfying 1 ≤ x ≤ l, 1 ≤ y ≤ w. 
 Each square may contain any number of roses.
 The rectangular areas, which must be selected, 
 should have their sides parallel to the sides of the garden 
 and the squares in their corners should have integer coordinates. 
 
 For 1 ≤ l1 ≤ l2 ≤ l and 1 ≤ w1 ≤ w2 ≤ w, 
 a rectangular area with corners (l1,w1), (l1,w2), (l2,w1) and (l2,w2):
 
  • contains all the squares with coordinates (x,y) satisfying l1 ≤ x ≤ l2 and w1 ≤ y ≤ w2, and
  • has perimeter 2 ·(l2 −l1 +1)+2 ·(w2−w1 +1).
  
 The two rectangular areas must be disjoint, that is they cannot contain a common square. 
 Even if they have a common side, or part of it, they must be surrounded by separate fences.
 
 
 Task
 
 Write a program, that:
   • reads from the standard input the dimensions of the garden, 
     the number of roses in the garden, 
	 the number of roses that should be in each of the rectangular areas, and the positions of the roses,
	 
   • finds the corners of two such rectangular areas with minimum sum of perimeters 
     that satisfy the given conditions,
	 
   • writes to the standard output the minimum sum of perimeters of two non-overlapping rectangular areas,
     each containing exactly the given number of roses 
	 (or a single word NO, if no such pair of areas exists).
	 
 Input
 
 The first line of standard input contains two integers: l and w (1 ≤ l,w ≤ 250) 
 separated by a single space — the length and the width of the garden. 
 
 The second line contains two integers: n and k (2 ≤ n ≤ 5000, 1 ≤ k ≤ n/2) separated by a single space 
 — the number of roses in the garden and the number of roses 
 that should be in each of the rectangular areas. 
 
 The following n lines contain the coordinates of the roses, one rose per line. 
 The (i+2)-nd line contains two integers li, wi (1 ≤ li ≤ l, 1 ≤ wi ≤ w) separated by a single space
 
 — the coordinates of the square containing the i-th rose. 
 
 Two or more roses can occur in the same square. In 50% of test cases, the dimensions of the garden will satisfy l,w ≤ 40.	 
 
 Output
 
 The standard output should contain only one line with exactly one integer 
 — the minimum sum of perimeters of two non-overlapping rectangular areas, 
 each containing exactly k roses, or a single word NO, 
 if no such pair of areas exists.
 
 Solution
 
 Let us call a rectangular region containing exactly k roses a k-rectangle. 
 Let us also denote by r(x,y) the number of roses in the square (x,y). 
 The problem is to find two disjoint k-rectangles with minimal sum of perimeters.
 
 The simplest solution is to consider all possible rectangular regions of the garden, 
 and for each of them to count the number of roses inside. 
 This way we can enumerate all k-rectangles in O(w^3*l^3) time
 
 There may be up to O(w^2*l^2) k-rectangles in total. 
 The second step is to consider all the pairs of k-rectangles 
 and choose the one consisting of disjoint regions with minimum sum of perimeters. 
 Such a solution should receive about 50 % points, despite its terrible time complexity of O(w^4*l^4)
 
 Model solution
 Now we will present a number of gradual improvements, which will finally yield us the model solution. 
 Please note, that we can optimize checking if a given rectangular region is a k-rectangle. 
 Let us denote by R(x,y) the number of roses in a region, with one corner at (1,1) and the opposite one at (x,y). 
 We can pre-compute all the values of R(x,y) iteratively in O(w·l) time using the following formula:
 
   R(x,y) = 0 if x = 0 or y = 0
   R(x,y) = R(x−1,y) + R(x,y−1) − R(x−1,y−1) + rx,y otherwise

   Y
   |
 y |-------------
y-1|_________|  |
   |         |  |
   |         |  |
   |         |  |
   |------------------- X 
           x-1 x

 Having this, we can express R(x1,y1,x2,y2) 
 — the number of roses in a rectangular region with corners (x1,y1) and (x2,y2) as:
   
   R(x1,y1,x2,y2) = R(x2,y2) − R(x2,y1−1) − R(x1−1,y2) + R(x1−1,y1−1)

   Y
   |
 y2|-------------
   |_________|__|
 y1|         |  |
   |         |  |
   |         |  |
   |------------------- X 
           x1  x2

This way, R (x1,y1,x2,y2) can be evaluated in O(1) time. 
Using the presented method, we can enumerate all k-rectangles
in O(w^2 * l^2) time. 
Unfortunately, this does not solve the problem of considering all pairs of k-rectangles.

But fortunately, there is another method, which copes with this problem. 
Please observe, that if we have two disjoint rectangular regions, 
then there must exist either a horizontal or a vertical line 
such that one rectangle is above it (or respectively to the left) 
and the other one is below it (or respectively to the right). 

Hence, for each horizontal line we can find two k-rectangles with the smallest perimeters, 
laying on the opposite sides of the line. 
Similar values are to be found for all vertical lines. 
When we have done this, we can easily compute the final result in O(w+l) 
by considering all the possible dividing lines 
and choosing the result which gives us the optimal sum of perimeters.

Now we will show how to find optimal perimeters for the first case 
(rectangular regions above the given horizontal line). 
The three other cases can be solved analogously. 

 Let us denote by Ay 
 the minimal perimeter of k-rectangle laying above the horizontal line 
 with the given y-coordinate, whose bottommost coordinate is greater than or equal y. 
 
 Let us also denote by ay the minimal perimeter of the k-rectangle with bottommost 
 coordinate equal y. 
 
 Please note, that:

        Ay = min(ay,...,aw)
		
 A simple way to calculate ai’s is to initially set them to infinity, 
 and then update them while iterating through all k rectangles. 
 With this improvement our algorithm works in O(w^2*l^2) time.
 
 This is not all.
 Please note, that we do not need to consider all k-rectangles. 
 We can limit our considerations to those k-rectangles, 
 which do not contain any other k-rectangles in their interiors. 
 To enumerate all interesting k-rectangles 
 (and maybe some not interesting too), 
 we consider all pairs (y1,y2), 1 <= y1 <= y2 <= w. 
 
 For each such pair, we use a sliding window, 
 which is a rectangle having corners at (x1,y1) and (x2,y2). 
 At the beginning, x1 = x2 = 1. 
 Then we repeatedly move the sliding window according to the following rules, until x2 > l:

   • if there are exactly k roses in the sliding window 
     (i.e. R (x1,y1,x2,y2) = k), 
	 then we have found a new k-rectangle;
     after updating the four constructed sequences 
	 (ai and the three other analogous sequences), 
	 x1 is incremented by one,
	 
	 
     if R (x1,y1,x2,y2) < k then x2 is incremented by one, to expand the sliding window,
     if R (x1,y1,x2,y2) > k then x1 is incremented by one, to shrink the sliding window,

  The above algorithm works in O(w^2*l) time, 
  and enumerates (among others) all interesting k-rectangles. 
  Of course, we can reduce its running time to O(w·l·min(w,l)) 
  by adapting the direction, in which this method works.
  
  The presented solution, with all the above optimizations, constitutes the model solution
  
  Solution 2

  If we take two non-overlapping rectangles, 
  they can always be separated by a vertical or horizontal line.
  
  Thus, we can try all possible ways of splitting the original rectangle 
  using either horizontal or vertical line. 
  For each split, we have to find the single best rectangle in each part.
  
  In this way, we have reduced the problem 
  from jointly identifying two rectangles with minimum cost 
  to that of finding one minimum cost rectangle within a given rectangle.

  How can we systematically enumerate all rectangles? 
  
  Assume we are using fixed height rectangles. 
  Systematically choose each row of the garden to be the "base row". 
  For each choice of base row, check each band that uses this base row. 
  Symmetrically, fix a base column for vertical bands.
  
  This still requires us to calculate the number of roses in a given rectangle. 
  How can we do this efficiently without actually adding up all values within the rectangle?
  
  Calculate number of roses for special kind of rectangles, which start at top left corner of the original rectangle.
  
  Count(i,j) is the number of roses in the rectangle whose top left corner is (1,1) 
  and bottom right corner is (i,j). 
  We can compute Count(i,j) if we know the neighbouring values:
  
  Count(i,j) = Count(i-1,j) + Count(i,j-1) - Count(i-1,j-1) + Roses(i,j)
  where Roses(i,j) is number of roses at (i,j).
  
  Now, given a rectangle with top left corner (u,v) and bottom right corner (x,y), the count of this rectangle is:
  Count(x,y) - Count(u,y) - Count(x,v) + Count(u,v)
  
  Now, sitting on base row i we want to compute the best K-rose rectangle 
  whose bottom edge is on i and whose top edge is on row i-k.
  
  For this, we use the sliding window technique from the Empty Plot problem.
  
  Given l and r, we can find the number of roses in this rectangle, using the counts we have calculated. 
  This is really a one dimensional sliding window problem. 
  If the count in the rectangle defined by l and r is less than or greater than K 
  we expand/contract the window as before. 
  If the count is exactly K, we compute the perimeter and note it down.
  
  In this way, we can compute the best rectangle sitting on base row i as the minimum among all best rectangles 
  whose top row ranges from 1 to k-1. 
  For each top row, the sliding window takes time N. There are M rows above i, so this takes MN time.
  
  Similarly, we can find all rectangles whose top row is the base row i and bottom row varies from i+1,…,M.
  We do this for every base row, so this takes time M times MN = M2N overall.
  In a similar way, we fix base columns and find the best rectangles to the left and right. 
  This takes N times MN = N2M overall.
  
  
  
  
  


 
 
