Mean Sequence

Consider a nondecreasing sequence of integers s1,...,sn+1 (si <= si+1 for 1 <= i <= n). 
The sequence m1,...,mn defined by
mi = (si + si+1) / 2, for 1 <= i <= n, is called the mean sequence of sequence s1,...,sn+1. 

For example, the mean sequence of sequence 1, 2, 2, 4 is the sequence 1.5, 2, 3. 
Note that elements of the mean sequence can be fractions. 
However, this task deals with mean sequences whose elements are integers only.

Given a nondecreasing sequence of n integers m1,...,mn, 
compute the number of nondecreasing sequences of n + 1 integers s1,...,sn+1 
that have the given sequence m1,...,mn as mean sequence.

Task

Write a program that:
 reads from the standard input a nondecreasing sequence of integers,
 calculates the number of nondecreasing sequences, for which the given sequence is mean sequence,
 writes the answer to the standard output.

Input
 The first line of the standard input contains one integer n (2 <= n <= 5 000 000). 
 The remaining n lines contain the sequence m1,...,mn. 
 Line i + 1 contains a single integer mi (0 <= mi <= 1 000 000 000 ). 
 You can assume that in 50% of the test cases n <= 1 000 and 0 <= mi <= 20 000.
 

Solution: 
By definition, mean sequence is: 
2m1=s1+s2
2m2=s2+s3
2m3=s3+s4
....
2mi=si+si+1
....
2mn-1=sn-1+sn
2mn=sn+sn+1

Lets try to get rid of values
 2m1 = s1  + s2
-2m2 = -s2 - s3
 2m3 = s3  + s4.
 
 
-2m2k = -s2k - s2k+1
m2k+1 =  
 

At first, observe that the definition of mean sequence can be applied to any sequence, not only nondecreasing sequences.
If we drop the condition that sequence s1,...,sn+1 is nondecreasing, 
then fixing a single si fixes the entire sequence, given its mean sequence m1,...,mn. 

Let us define the reflection operation r on integer a with respect to center c as follows:
 r(a,c) = b if and only if (a+b)/2=c
 that is, r(a,c) = 2c−a. 

 If si is fixed, then 
    si+1 = r(si, mi) and 
	si−1 = r(si, mi−1), etc.
	
 Hence, there exist an infinite number of sequences s1,...,sn+1 
 that have the given sequence m1,...,mn as mean sequence — one for each choice of s1.
 
There is a finite number of nondecreasing sequences though. 
A simple upper bound on the number of possible nondecreasing sequences may be m2 − m1 + 1, 
which is the number of integers between m1 and m2 (inclusive). 
This is because s2 must satisfy m1 <= s2 <= m2. 

m1 = (s1 + s2) / 2 <= (s2 + s2) / 2
m2 = (s2 + s3) / 2 >= (s2 + s2) / 2 

s1 <= s2 <= s3 <= s4 <= ....

Indeed, if s2 < m1 then s1 > m2 and therefore s2 < s1 so the sequence is not nondecreasing. 
Similarly, if s2 > m2 then s3 < m2 giving a sequence which is not nondecreasing either. 
This way we can construct a solution, which tests all the possible values of s2 lying between m1 and m2, 
and for each such s2 it computes the rest of the sequence 
and then checks if it is nondecreasing. 
Such a solution works in O(n(m2 −m1 +1)) time and can be implemented with O(n) or better O(m2 −m1 +1) memory complexity
  m1 <= s2 <= m2

  m2 = (s2 + s3) / 2 <= 
  m3 = (s3 + m4) / 2 >= s3

  

Optimal solution
Before we present the model solution, a following definition will be useful. 
Let us call a value v feasible for si in the given sequence, 
when there exists an nondecreasing sequence s1,...,sn+1 with si = v and mean sequence m1,...,mn. 
Now we need an important observation.

Observation 1 
  If, for some i, values a and b with a <= b are feasible for si, then every c in the interval [a,b] is feasible for si.
  
The actual number of nondecreasing sequences s1,...,sn+1 can be obtained by generalizing the problem as follows.
Given a nondecreasing sequence m1,...,mn, determine the interval of feasible values for sn+1. 
The answer is then the size of that interval. 

In the model solution the interval of feasible values of sn+1 is computed inductively. 
We start with the case n = 0. In this case, the interval of feasible values for s1 consists of all integers: (−∞,+∞). 

Now let [a,b] be the interval for nondecreasing sequences s1,...,sn+1 having mean sequence m1,...,mn. 

Let us consider the mean sequence m1,...,mn extended by a new element mn+1 > mn. 
This reduces the possible values for sn+1 to the interval [a, min(b,mn+1)], 

             a <= sn+1 <= min(b,mn+1)

         r(a, mn+1) <=  sn+2 = r(sn+1, mn+1) <= r(min(b,mn+1), mn+1)
		  
and hence the interval for sn+2 is the reflection of this interval, that is, 
[r(min(b,mn+1),mn+1),r(a,mn+1)]. 

We consider interval [a,b] as empty if a > b, and otherwise it contains b−a+1 elements. 
This way we obtain O(n) time complexity and O(1) memory complexity solution, 
because there is no need to store the entire sequence in memory. 
Intervals of feasible values can be computed while reading the input data.







 
 
 
 