
Mountains

The Mountain Amusement Park has opened a brand-new simulated roller coaster. 
The simulated track consists of n rails attached end-to-end with the beginning of the first rail fixed at elevation 0. 

Byteman, the operator, can reconfigure the track at will 
by adjusting the elevation change over a number of consecutive rails. 
The elevation change over other rails is not affected. 
Each time rails are adjusted, the following track is raised or lowered as necessary to connect the track 
while maintaining the start at elevation 0. 

The figure on the next page illustrates two example track reconfigurations.

Each ride is initiated by launching the car with sufficient energy to reach height h. 
That is, the car will continue to travel as long as the elevation of the track does not exceed h, 
and as long as the end of the track is not reached. 

Given the record for all the day’s rides and track configuration changes, 
compute for each ride the number of rails traversed by the car before it stops.

Internally, the simulator represents the track as a sequence of n elevation changes, one for each rail. 
The i-th number di represents the elevation change (in centimetres) over the i-th rail. 

Suppose that after traversing i−1 rails the car has reached an elevation of h centimetres. 
After traversing i rails the car will have reached an elevation of h + di centimetres.

Initially the rails are horizontal; 
that is, di = 0 for all i. 

Rides and reconfigurations are interleaved throughout the day.

Each reconfiguration is specified by three numbers: a, b and D. 
The segment to be adjusted consists of rails a through b (inclusive). 

The elevation change over each rail in the segment is set to D. 
That is, di = D for all a <= i <= b.
Each ride is specified by one number h — the maximum height that the car can reach.

Task
Write a program that:
• reads from the standard input a sequence of interleaved reconfigurations and rides,
• for each ride computes the number of rails traversed by the car,
• writes the results to the standard output.


Input

The first line of input contains one positive integer n — the number of rails, 
1 <= n <= 1 000 000 000 . 
The following lines contain reconfigurations interleaved with rides, followed by an end marker. 

Each line contains one of:
  • Reconfiguration — a single letter ‘I’, and integers a, b and D, all separated by single spaces 
   (1 <= a <= b <= n, −1 000 000 000 <= D <= 1 000 000 000 ).
  • Ride — a single letter ‘Q’, and an integer h (0 <= h <= 1 000 000 000 ) separated by a single space;
  • A single letter ‘E’ — the end marker, indicating the end of the input data.
  
You may assume that at any moment the elevation of any point in the track is in the interval [ 0 ,1 000 000 000] centimetres.
The input contains no more than 100 000 lines.
In 50 % of test cases n satisfies 1 <= n <= 20 000 and there are no more than 1 000 lines of input.

Output

The i-th line of output should consist of one integer — the number of rails traversed by the car during the i-th ride.


At the beginning, 
let us denote by I the number of input lines starting with letter ‘I’ (i.e. reconfigurations). 
Similarly, let Q be the number of rides.

Simple solutions

One possible simple, although not optimal, solution is to represent the trail as a vector A, 
where A[i] denotes the elevation after the i-th rail. 
The complexity of processing a reconfiguration (we call this operation insertion) is O(n). 
Single query about a ride also takes O(n), so the total time complexity is O((I +Q)· n). 
Moreover, memory complexity is O(n) which is far too high to not exceed the memory limit in large test cases.

Another simple approach is to represent the track as a sorted list of disjoint intervals 
such that throughout each interval, the difference of elevation over every rail is the same. 
This way we have insertion and query complexity of O(I), so the entire solution is O((I +Q)·I). 
Memory complexity is O(I).

Model solution

A data structure used in the model solution is a binary tree. 
Each of its nodes describes an interval (i.e. a number of consecutive rails) 

J =[2^k*t, 2^k*(t+1)], for some integers k and t. 

The information contained in the node is

S(J) = Sum(di), i from J

H(J) = max( {0} U { sum(di), 2^k*t <= i <= j: j from J } )

The node is a leaf if all the values di are equal. 
In this case computing SJ and HJ is trivial. 
Otherwise, the node has two sons, with assigned intervals:

    J1 =[2^(k−1)(2t),   2^(k−1)(2t +1)]
and J2 =[2^(k−1)(2t +1),2^(k−1)(2t +2)]

In this case SJ and HJ are computed as SJ = SJ1 +SJ2
and HJ = max{HJ1,SJ1 +HJ2}.


In our example: 
We have 4 rails:  .----.----.----.----
                     1   2    3     4
di =                 0   0    0     0 

After we have reconstructed the difference:   d  [2, 2, 2, 2]
If we need to find the height of the 3rd rail. 
First rail starts at point 0 and we need to sum di

S(j) = d1 + d2 + d3 + ... + dj = Sum(di, 1 <= i <= j)

S(1) = 2. S(2) = 4, S(3) = 6, S(4) = 8
  
   2    2    2    2
.----.----.----.----.

Suppose that we change second value to - 1
   2   -1   2     2
.----.----.----.----.

S(1) = 2, S(2) = 1, S(3) = 3, S(4) = 5





 
 












