

Nearly all of the Kingdom of Byteland is covered by forests and rivers. 
Small rivers meet to form bigger rivers, which also meet and, in the end, 
all the rivers flow together into one big river. 
The big river meets the sea near Bytetown.

There are n lumberjacks’ villages in Byteland, each placed near a river. 
Currently, there is a big sawmill in Bytetown that processes all trees cut in the Kingdom. 

The trees float from the villages down the rivers to the sawmill in Bytetown. 

The king of Byteland decided to build k additional sawmills in villages 
to reduce the cost of transporting the trees downriver. 

After building the sawmills, the trees need not float to Bytetown,
but can be processed in the first sawmill they encounter downriver. 

Obviously, the trees cut near a village with a sawmill need not be transported by river. 
It should be noted that the rivers in Byteland do not fork.

Therefore, for each village, there is a unique way downriver from the village to Bytetown

The king’s accountants calculated how many trees are cut by each village per year. 
You must decide where to build the sawmills to minimize the total cost of transporting the trees per year. 
River transportation costs one cent per kilometre, per tree.

Task

Write a program that:
  - reads from the standard input the number of villages, 
    the number of additional sawmills to be built, 
	the number of trees cut near each village, and descriptions of the rivers,
	
  - calculates the minimal cost of river transportation after building additional sawmills,
  - writes the result to the standard output

Input

The first line of input contains two integers: 
     n — the number of villages other than Bytetown (2 ≤ n ≤ 100),
 and k — the number of additional sawmills to be built (1 ≤ k ≤ 50 and k ≤ n). 
 The villages are numbered 1,2,...,n, while Bytetown has number 0.
 
Each of the following n lines contains three integers, separated by single spaces. 
Line i+1 contains: 

   wi — the number of trees cut near village i per year (0 ≤ wi ≤ 10000),
   vi — the first village (or Bytetown) downriver from village i (0 ≤ vi ≤ n),
   di — the distance (in kilometres) by river from village i to vi (1 ≤ di ≤ 10000).

    edge
 i -------> vi
wi

In 50 % of test cases n will not exceed 20.

Output

The first and only line of the output should contain one integer: 
the minimal cost of river transportation (in cents).

Example

For the input data:

4 2
1 0 1
1 1 10
10 2 5
1 2 3

the correct result is:              3
4                                 /(10)
                                5/ 
                                /
Bytetown    1           10     V
    0   <------- 1  <-------- 2 
	             (1)         (1) ^
                                  \
                                   \3
								    \
                                     4 (1)

Solution. 

root - is root of the tree. It is node 0.

dfs(root, k) - returns min cost of river transportation for subtree root, 
               where max number of additional sawmill.
			   
We do not need to put a sawmill at root. 

    root
   	
   /   \     \	
  c1   c2     c3 	


dfs(node, true, k)  - min cost to move all trees inside subtree in node. 
dfs(node, false, k) - here some trees will be moved to node and then go farther. 


Solution. 

Notation

It is not hard to observe that since for each village there is a unique way down the river 
from the village to Bytetown, we can treat the rivers and villages as a tree with the root in Bytetown. 
Nodes of the tree correspond to the villages 
(for convenience we will refer to Bytetown as a village too), 
and node v is the parent of node u when v is the first village downriver from u.

Let r denote the root of the tree, i.e. r corresponds to Bytetown. 
By depth(u) we will denote the number of edges on a unique path from u to r. 
Clearly, the values of depth(u) can be computed for all villages u in linear time. 
The number of children of node u will be denoted by deg(u), 
and the number of trees cut near village u will be denoted by trees(u).

Dynamic Programming

We can apply dynamic programming to solve the task. 
Let A(v,t,l) denote the minimal cost of transportation of the trees cut in the subtree rooted in v, 
assuming that t additional sawmills can be built in the subtree, 
and the trees not processed in v can be processed in the village of depth l (on the way from v to Bytetown). 

We compute values of A(v,t,l) for each village v, and such numbers t,l, that 0 <= t <= k and 0 <= l < depth(v). 
Clearly, when the tree rooted in v has at most t nodes, 
then A(v,t,l) = 0, as we can simply place a sawmill in every village. 
We can use the following formula:

A(v,t,l) = 0,   when the tree rooted in v has at most t nodes,
           min(A1(v,t,l), A2(v,t,l)) , otherwise
		   
where A1(v,t,l) is the cost of transportation when there is no sawmill in v, 
and A2(v,t) is the cost of transportation when there is one. 

These costs depend on the distribution of sawmills between subtrees rooted in children of v. 
Let d = deg(v) and let v1,v2,...,vd be the children of v. Then:

  A1(v,t,l) = trees(v)*(depth(v)-l) + min(t1+..+td=t) sum(i=1..d A(vi,ti,l))

  A2(v,t) = min(t1+...+td=t-1) sum(i=1..d A(vi,ti,depth(v)))

  

f(x, scub, nearest, left)

we start with: f(0, 0, 0, k)

Suppose we put a mill in node x, 

x - is current node, we need to calculate min cost to send all trees
    in subtree rooted in x. 
	
	
	x 
	
  /	|..  \       \    ....  \ 
 0  1    scub -1 scub      length(children)
 
 
 

		   





























